<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">

    <channel>
        <title>Open to Debate – Debates</title>
        <link>https://opentodebate.org</link>
        <description>Debates with related research and news</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 03:03:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
        <item>
            <title>Hollywood has Fueled Anti-Americanism Abroad</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/hollywood-has-fueled-anti-americanism-abroad</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10157</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> December 13, 2006</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Culture</p>
<p>As America’s premier cultural export, Hollywood is lauded as a beacon of democracy and free expression around the world. But as its films increasingly portray themes of violence, overt sexuality, and condemnation of U.S. governance, Hollywood has become fodder for America’s enemies. Is Hollywood to blame for anti-Americanism abroad?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/5dQKhzjS-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/5dQKhzjS-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>James Hirsen</strong><br>James is a pundit for <a href="https://www.newsmax.com/">NewsMax.com</a> and author of the popular weekly column "The Left Coast Report," where he takes a humorous poke at the politics of Hollywood. His latest book is "Hollywood Nation: Left Coast Lies, Old Media Spin, and the New Media Revolution" (2005). Hirsen teaches law at California's Trinity Law School and Biola University.</p>
<p><strong>Roger Kimball</strong><br>Roger is managing editor, co-editor, and co-publisher of the New Criterion magazine, a monthly review of the arts and intellectual life, and an art critic for the London Spectator. Kimball contributes to numerous journals in the US and England. He is the author of many books, including his most recent, "The Rape of the Masters: How Political Correctness Sabotages Art" (2004).</p>
<p><strong>Signe Wilkinson</strong><br>Signe is the author of One Nation, Under Surveillance, and the winner of the Pulitzer Prize for editorial cartooning in 1992. Her editorial cartoons are syndicated by the Washington Post Writers Group.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Robin Bronk</strong><br>Robin Bronk is the execuitive Director of The Creative Coalition. The Creative Coalition is a nonprofit, nonpartisan, social, and political advocacy organization for the arts and entertainment industries. She is dedicated to educating and mobilizing the arts community on issues of public importance, particularly the First Amendment, arts advocacy, and public education.</p>
<p><strong>Robert Greenwald</strong><br>Robert's first feature documentary was "Unprecedented: The 2000 Political Election" (2002). Most recently, he directed and produced "Wal-Mart: The High Cost of Low Prices" (2005). His new media company, Brave New Films, is working on producing films that will influence debates on the most important issues of the day.</p>
<p><strong>Richard Walter</strong><br>Richard chairs the graduate program in screenwriting. His students enjoy great success at the studios and networks.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>"Smart Drugs" Are Here -Should College Students Be Allowed to Use Them?</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>We use coffee to stay awake, good food and nutrition to stay healthy and alert. But if there was a drug that made you smarter, helped you learn, and made you more focused, would you take it?</p>
<p>That's a question that Nicole Vincent, associate professor of philosophy, law and neuroscience at Georgia State University, asked to open her TED talk in Sydney last year.</p>
<p>That question also opened a Monday night debate at George Washington University in which two sides argued both for and against whether "College Students Should Be Allowed to Take Smart Drugs."</p></div>
<div><strong>Are Smart Drugs a Smart Choice? Experts Debate at SMPA</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>If there was a pill that could make everyone smarter and more focused, how many people would take it?</p>
<p>This question was the subject of debate among experts at the Jack Morton Auditorium Monday night. Moderated by ABC News correspondent John Donvan, the panel weighed the medical and moral risks, as well as the benefits, of college students using drugs like Adderall, without a prescription, to help them study.</p></div>
<div><strong>Are Smart Drugs Good for College Students?</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Should college students take smart drugs? That was the question posed to a panel of professors at an Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. debate at George Washington University on Monday night.</p></div>
<div><strong>Intelligence Squared / Open to Debate FIRE Debate: College Students Should Be Allowed to Take Smart Drugs</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. and the Foundation for Individual Rights in Education (FIRE) are embarking on a joint venture (that I am proud to have brokered), to present a series of high-profile debates on college campuses. Our first debate will be tomorrow at George Washington University.</p></div>
<div><strong>Smart Drugs for College Kids</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Pop a pill, ace a test. If you could take a pill that would instantly make you work harder, improve your brain function, and make you smarter, would you?</p>
<p>A panel of experts argued this question in a debate this week presented by Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. at George Washington University in Washington, D.C., entitled, College Students Should be Allowed to Take Smart Drugs.</p></div>
<div><strong>New Haven Debate Will Focus on Whether Free Speech Is Threatened on Campuses</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>The atmosphere on campuses nationwide has become charged with accusations, on one side, that micro-aggressions are hurtful to women and people of color and countercharges that universities are censoring speakers.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the issue will land in the spotlight at the Yale Repertory Theatre as four debaters argue for or against the statement, Free speech is threatened on campus.</p>
<p>I don't think there's any question that free speech is threatened on campus. I think the question is whether free speech should be threatened on campus, said Wendy Kaminer, who is one of the debaters in the Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. debate, sponsored by the Adam Smith Society, an organization composed of business school students and alumni.</p></div>
<div><strong>Tell Us: Is Your Speech Policed in Your Dorm?</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>On Tuesday, an audience gathered at Yale to hear a debate on the proposition, 'Free speech is threatened on campus.'The question pertained to institutions of higher education generally, not just the host university. The outcome: a clear majority agree that free speech is threatened. But that wasn't yet true when the event began.</p></div>
<div><strong>Students Unswayed by Free Speech Debate</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Before a nearly full auditorium at the Yale Repertory Theater Tuesday night, the NPR show 'Intelligence Squared U.S. / Open to Debate'hosted a debate on the motion that free speech is threatened on college campuses. But despite the robust turnout, most students' opinions on the topic remained largely unchanged, with students stating that many of the arguments advanced at the debate were ideas they had already heard last fall.</p></div>
<div><strong>Debate at Yale Rep in New Haven Examines Free Speech on Campus</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>The atmosphere on college campuses has changed, a Columbia University professor argued before an audience full of Yale students and New Haven residents Tuesday. And that change has created spaces in which free speech is not extinguished, but threatened.</p>
<p>A majority of the audience agreed.</p>
<p>After a debate hosted by Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S., a nonprofit that provides free online access to debates held across the country on issues facing society, 66 percent of the audience left convinced that free speech is threatened on college campuses. The event was held at the Yale Repertory Theatre.</p></div>
<div><strong>Critics of Leftist Assault on Campus Win over Yale Audience in Free-Speech Debate</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Portrayed as 'ignorant at best and immoral at worst,' non-leftist students self-censor.</p>
<p>In recent weeks, speakers such as conservative Ben Shapiro and anti-feminist Milo Yiannopoulos have faced angry crowds of progressive students who tried to shut down their campus speeches with interruptions and physical confrontations.</p>
<p>Yet it took an evening of civil debate between scholars and writers to convince a divided Yale University audience that 'free speech is threatened on campus.'</p>
<p>The public radio show and podcast Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. hosted the Tuesday evening Oxford-style debate at Yale, moderated by ABC News correspondent John Donvan.</p></div>
<div><strong>The Glaring Evidence That Free Speech Is Threatened on Campus</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>A debate at Yale highlighted the disconnect between those who would downplay the problem, and the growing mass of evidence that they're wrong.</p>
<p>At a recentIntelligence Squared / Open to Debate (https://opentodebate.org/debate/free-speech-threatened-campus/), an audience filled an auditorium at Yale University to weigh the timely proposition, 'Free speech is threatened on campus.' The debate concerned higher education generally, not just the host institution. And at the event's conclusion, having heard arguments on both sides of the question, 66 percent of the crowd agreed: free speech is threatened. That represented a 17-point shift from a poll taken as the event began. The evidence is that persuasive.</p></div>
<div><strong>Open to Debate: Free Speech Is Threatened on Campus</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Open to Debate presented an excellent debate on Tuesday at Yale 'Resolved: Free speech is threatened on campus.'</p>
<p>Yale was a particularly apt venue for this debate. Yale has a proud tradition of freedom of speech, and its official statement on free speech, the 'Woodward Report' of 1974, is one of the strongest defenses of free speech in the academy. But the infamous controversy of this past Halloween, and the way that Yale handled the controversy, have led many to doubt Yale's current commitment to free speech. This year, Yale only narrowly avoided ranking among the 10 worst colleges in the United States for free speech, according to the Foundation for Individual Rights in Education (FIRE). So this debate was particularly timely, and it clearly struck a nerve at Yale.</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Hollywood has Fueled Anti-Americanism Abroad</em></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> December 13, 2006</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Culture</p>
<p>As America’s premier cultural export, Hollywood is lauded as a beacon of democracy and free expression around the world. But as its films increasingly portray themes of violence, overt sexuality, and condemnation of U.S. governance, Hollywood has become fodder for America’s enemies. Is Hollywood to blame for anti-Americanism abroad?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/5dQKhzjS-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/5dQKhzjS-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>James Hirsen</strong><br>James is a pundit for <a href="https://www.newsmax.com/">NewsMax.com</a> and author of the popular weekly column "The Left Coast Report," where he takes a humorous poke at the politics of Hollywood. His latest book is "Hollywood Nation: Left Coast Lies, Old Media Spin, and the New Media Revolution" (2005). Hirsen teaches law at California's Trinity Law School and Biola University.</p>
<p><strong>Roger Kimball</strong><br>Roger is managing editor, co-editor, and co-publisher of the New Criterion magazine, a monthly review of the arts and intellectual life, and an art critic for the London Spectator. Kimball contributes to numerous journals in the US and England. He is the author of many books, including his most recent, "The Rape of the Masters: How Political Correctness Sabotages Art" (2004).</p>
<p><strong>Signe Wilkinson</strong><br>Signe is the author of One Nation, Under Surveillance, and the winner of the Pulitzer Prize for editorial cartooning in 1992. Her editorial cartoons are syndicated by the Washington Post Writers Group.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Robin Bronk</strong><br>Robin Bronk is the execuitive Director of The Creative Coalition. The Creative Coalition is a nonprofit, nonpartisan, social, and political advocacy organization for the arts and entertainment industries. She is dedicated to educating and mobilizing the arts community on issues of public importance, particularly the First Amendment, arts advocacy, and public education.</p>
<p><strong>Robert Greenwald</strong><br>Robert's first feature documentary was "Unprecedented: The 2000 Political Election" (2002). Most recently, he directed and produced "Wal-Mart: The High Cost of Low Prices" (2005). His new media company, Brave New Films, is working on producing films that will influence debates on the most important issues of the day.</p>
<p><strong>Richard Walter</strong><br>Richard chairs the graduate program in screenwriting. His students enjoy great success at the studios and networks.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>"Smart Drugs" Are Here -Should College Students Be Allowed to Use Them?</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>We use coffee to stay awake, good food and nutrition to stay healthy and alert. But if there was a drug that made you smarter, helped you learn, and made you more focused, would you take it?</p>
<p>That's a question that Nicole Vincent, associate professor of philosophy, law and neuroscience at Georgia State University, asked to open her TED talk in Sydney last year.</p>
<p>That question also opened a Monday night debate at George Washington University in which two sides argued both for and against whether "College Students Should Be Allowed to Take Smart Drugs."</p></div>
<div><strong>Are Smart Drugs a Smart Choice? Experts Debate at SMPA</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>If there was a pill that could make everyone smarter and more focused, how many people would take it?</p>
<p>This question was the subject of debate among experts at the Jack Morton Auditorium Monday night. Moderated by ABC News correspondent John Donvan, the panel weighed the medical and moral risks, as well as the benefits, of college students using drugs like Adderall, without a prescription, to help them study.</p></div>
<div><strong>Are Smart Drugs Good for College Students?</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Should college students take smart drugs? That was the question posed to a panel of professors at an Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. debate at George Washington University on Monday night.</p></div>
<div><strong>Intelligence Squared / Open to Debate FIRE Debate: College Students Should Be Allowed to Take Smart Drugs</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. and the Foundation for Individual Rights in Education (FIRE) are embarking on a joint venture (that I am proud to have brokered), to present a series of high-profile debates on college campuses. Our first debate will be tomorrow at George Washington University.</p></div>
<div><strong>Smart Drugs for College Kids</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Pop a pill, ace a test. If you could take a pill that would instantly make you work harder, improve your brain function, and make you smarter, would you?</p>
<p>A panel of experts argued this question in a debate this week presented by Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. at George Washington University in Washington, D.C., entitled, College Students Should be Allowed to Take Smart Drugs.</p></div>
<div><strong>New Haven Debate Will Focus on Whether Free Speech Is Threatened on Campuses</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>The atmosphere on campuses nationwide has become charged with accusations, on one side, that micro-aggressions are hurtful to women and people of color and countercharges that universities are censoring speakers.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the issue will land in the spotlight at the Yale Repertory Theatre as four debaters argue for or against the statement, Free speech is threatened on campus.</p>
<p>I don't think there's any question that free speech is threatened on campus. I think the question is whether free speech should be threatened on campus, said Wendy Kaminer, who is one of the debaters in the Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. debate, sponsored by the Adam Smith Society, an organization composed of business school students and alumni.</p></div>
<div><strong>Tell Us: Is Your Speech Policed in Your Dorm?</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>On Tuesday, an audience gathered at Yale to hear a debate on the proposition, 'Free speech is threatened on campus.'The question pertained to institutions of higher education generally, not just the host university. The outcome: a clear majority agree that free speech is threatened. But that wasn't yet true when the event began.</p></div>
<div><strong>Students Unswayed by Free Speech Debate</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Before a nearly full auditorium at the Yale Repertory Theater Tuesday night, the NPR show 'Intelligence Squared U.S. / Open to Debate'hosted a debate on the motion that free speech is threatened on college campuses. But despite the robust turnout, most students' opinions on the topic remained largely unchanged, with students stating that many of the arguments advanced at the debate were ideas they had already heard last fall.</p></div>
<div><strong>Debate at Yale Rep in New Haven Examines Free Speech on Campus</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>The atmosphere on college campuses has changed, a Columbia University professor argued before an audience full of Yale students and New Haven residents Tuesday. And that change has created spaces in which free speech is not extinguished, but threatened.</p>
<p>A majority of the audience agreed.</p>
<p>After a debate hosted by Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S., a nonprofit that provides free online access to debates held across the country on issues facing society, 66 percent of the audience left convinced that free speech is threatened on college campuses. The event was held at the Yale Repertory Theatre.</p></div>
<div><strong>Critics of Leftist Assault on Campus Win over Yale Audience in Free-Speech Debate</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Portrayed as 'ignorant at best and immoral at worst,' non-leftist students self-censor.</p>
<p>In recent weeks, speakers such as conservative Ben Shapiro and anti-feminist Milo Yiannopoulos have faced angry crowds of progressive students who tried to shut down their campus speeches with interruptions and physical confrontations.</p>
<p>Yet it took an evening of civil debate between scholars and writers to convince a divided Yale University audience that 'free speech is threatened on campus.'</p>
<p>The public radio show and podcast Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. hosted the Tuesday evening Oxford-style debate at Yale, moderated by ABC News correspondent John Donvan.</p></div>
<div><strong>The Glaring Evidence That Free Speech Is Threatened on Campus</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>A debate at Yale highlighted the disconnect between those who would downplay the problem, and the growing mass of evidence that they're wrong.</p>
<p>At a recentIntelligence Squared / Open to Debate (https://opentodebate.org/debate/free-speech-threatened-campus/), an audience filled an auditorium at Yale University to weigh the timely proposition, 'Free speech is threatened on campus.' The debate concerned higher education generally, not just the host institution. And at the event's conclusion, having heard arguments on both sides of the question, 66 percent of the crowd agreed: free speech is threatened. That represented a 17-point shift from a poll taken as the event began. The evidence is that persuasive.</p></div>
<div><strong>Open to Debate: Free Speech Is Threatened on Campus</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Open to Debate presented an excellent debate on Tuesday at Yale 'Resolved: Free speech is threatened on campus.'</p>
<p>Yale was a particularly apt venue for this debate. Yale has a proud tradition of freedom of speech, and its official statement on free speech, the 'Woodward Report' of 1974, is one of the strongest defenses of free speech in the academy. But the infamous controversy of this past Halloween, and the way that Yale handled the controversy, have led many to doubt Yale's current commitment to free speech. This year, Yale only narrowly avoided ranking among the 10 worst colleges in the United States for free speech, according to the Foundation for Individual Rights in Education (FIRE). So this debate was particularly timely, and it clearly struck a nerve at Yale.</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Hollywood has Fueled Anti-Americanism Abroad</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>A Democratically-Elected Hamas is Still a Terrorist Organization</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/democratically-elected-hamas-still-terrorist-organization</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:9940</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> November 29, 2006</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> World</p>
<p>In 2006, amidst growing resentment toward the Palestine Liberation Organization, Hamas won political power in a democratic election. The group, named a terrorist organization by both the United States and European Union, retains its charter calling for violence against Israel, yet provides critical social services to its constituents. Is a democratically elected Hamas still a terrorist organization, or should nations around the world recognize Hamas as a legitimate governing body?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/AgpkyZSL-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/AgpkyZSL-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Daniel Ayalon</strong><br>Since 2002, Daniel has worked extensively with the US administration and Congress to advance economic, political, and diplomatic relations. He has served the last three consecutive Israeli administrations, most recently as Chief Foreign Policy Adviser to Prime Minister Ariel Sharon. In the 1990s, he was posted in New York and Panama.
Daniel currently serves as the Deputy Foreign Minister of Israel.</p>
<p><strong>Steven A. Cook</strong><br>Steven is an expert on Arab politics and US Middle East policy, Cook directed the Council's Independent Task Force on reform in the Arab World. He has written widely on Islamist politics and democratic development in the Middle East.</p>
<p><strong>John O'Sullivan</strong><br>John is a political journalist who has edited publications from The National Review to the London Times. He is currently writing a book on Reagan, Thatcher, and the Pope. O'Sullivan began his career as a London correspondent for Irish Radio and Television.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Stanley L. Cohen</strong><br>Stanley is probably best known for his defense of Mousa Abu Marzook, the head of the political wing of Hamas, whose extradition from the United States was sought by Israel in 1995. Over the years, he has represented many other Muslim and Palestinian activists and imams throughout the United States and overseas.</p>
<p><strong>Mohammad-Mahmoud Ould Mohamedou</strong><br>Mohamed Mahmoud Ould Mohamedou is a scholar, author, and diplomat. He is currently the deputy director, a professor of international history and politics, and director of executive education at the Geneva Graduate Institute and has held academic posts at Harvard and the Ralph Bunche Institute on the United Nations (now Ralph Bunche Institute for International Studies at the City University of New York’s Graduate Center), among others. He is the author of severali books and previously served as Minister of Foreign Affairs of Mauritania.</p>
<p><strong>Mark Perry</strong><br>Through the Conflicts Forum, Perry has been engaged in a series of exchanges with Hamas over the past two years. He has worked with Arafat's Fatah wing and Hamas to cool their political competition. He is the author of "A Fire in Zion: The Israeli-Palestinian Search for Peace" (1994).</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Obama's Iran Deal is Good for America: A Debate</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:21:28</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>On Tuesday evening, I attended a debate in New York City sponsored by Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. focusing on whether or not Obama's Iran deal is good for the country. (The podcast is available at the website.)</p>
<p>On the pro side of the debate (for more complete bios on the debaters, visit the IQ2 / Open to Debate website) was Philip Gordon, a senior fellow at the Council on Foreign Relations, former special assistant to the president, and White House coordinator for the Middle East, North Africa, and the Gulf Region. He was joined by Thomas Pickering, currently vice chairman of an international consulting firm but more notable for his time served as a diplomat in various ambassadorships including to the U.N.</p></div>
<div><strong>How to Win the Iran Argument</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:21:28</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>In the heart of blue America ' New York City ' Mark Dubowitz and Mike Doran debated Philip Gordon and Thomas Pickering on whether the Iran deal is good for the United States. The way these things work is that the side that moves opinion the most from pre- to post-debate polling wins. In this case, Dubowitz and Doran won, moving opinion against the deal from 19 to 43 percent. The deal defenders gained just 13 points (from 37 to 50 percent).</p>
<p>The debate is hugely instructive and entertaining and can be viewed in its entirety, but I will note some high points and try to draw some lessons for future debates in and outside Congress.</p></div>
<div><strong>Geopolitical Expert Ian Bremmer on the Choices America Faces</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:21:28</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Q: You seemed to argue at an Intelligence Squared U.S. / Open to Debate, that the US cannot be the world police anymore. How does this notion fit into your idea of an Indispensable America?</p>
<p>Bremmer: I did argue that (though they assign you the position... and any good debater should be able to analytically handle that). But I think Indispensable America is becoming much more challenging. US allies are less capable/willing to support. US adversaries are more willing to challenge. And the willingness of the American people to pay the tab in blood and treasure is decreasing. I'd be much more comfortable with Indispensable America if I believed we could actually follow through on it.</p></div>
<div><strong>Do We Have an ISIS Strategy?</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>That the debate surrounding ISIS seems confused was recently echoed in an actual debate on the topic. The folks at Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. recently held a formal Oxford Union-style debate at the Aspen Security Forum. The proposition being debated was Containment is not enough: ISIS must be defeated. The outcome wasn't surprising, but the arguments were. All four debaters agreed that ISIS had to be fought militarily, ideologically, and in what stands for public opinion these days: social media. The only real question was: What is America's role?</p></div>
<div><strong>Between Iraq and a Hawk Base</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>That tension between steadfast principles and hard realities, both at home and abroad, was on display when some of America's leading foreign-policy thinkers gathered for a retreat hosted by the Aspen Institute, a nonpartisan education and policy organization, in August. The conference's main event was an hour-long debate about ISIS. Each debate team featured two national security officials from the Bush and Obama administrations. One team, Philip Zelikow, a former counselor to Secretary of State Condoleezza Rice, and Michale Flournoy, Obama's former defense undersecretary of defense for policy, argued that ISIS should be defeated, including through military means. The other team, Dov Zakheim, Bush's former Defense Department comptroller and foreign ­policy adviser, and Anne-Marie Slaughter, Obama's director of policy planning for the State Department, argued that it should be contained until it collapsed under the weight of its own failed ideology, as occurred with the Soviet Union. Among the 200 spectators were retired general David Petraeus, the former Secretary of State Madeleine Albright, and Jeb Bush's outside adviser, Richard Fontaine.</p>
<p>The debate was spirited and replete with unintended ironies. There was Flournoy, the former Obama official, arguing the traditional neocon position that the only way to give the lie to ISIS's ideology was to take territory away from ISIS And there was Zakheim, the former Bush official, sounding decidedly noninterventionist: The issue is, can you and are you willing to send in hundreds of thousands of troops? Do you think this country wants to do that? Do you think we even want to spend money to do that?</p>
<p>Zakheim's realpolitik warning hit the audience like a bucket of cold water. Even the nation's most intellectually rigorous foreign thinkers seemed struck by the challenge of convincing the American public that war against ISIS would not entail a horrific reprise of the Iraq war. Surveyed before the debate began, 52 percent of attendees believed that ISIS should be destroyed, with 27 percent saying it should be contained and another 21 percent being undecided. After the debate, the audience underwent a reversal: 59 percent were now convinced that the proper course of action was to contain ISIS rather than to pour blood and treasure into an attempt to destroy it.</p></div>
<div><strong>Enemies? Frenemies? Debate on China-US Ties Concludes That War Isn't Imminent</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>A former prime minister of Australia, a political science professor, and two senior members from United States-based think-tanks took turns at the lectern at a packed auditorium in Kaufman Music Center on Oct. 14 to debate a topic of the times: are China and the United States long-term enemies?</p></div>
<div><strong>Sino-US Ties: Prospects for Cooperation not Confrontation</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>In a debate held by "Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S.", renowned international relations experts such as John J. Mearsheimer from the University of Chicago and former Australian prime minister Kevin Rudd debated whether China and the US would become long-term enemies. The opinion poll of audiences that followed shows that 56 percent of those on site and 64 percent of those on-line said "no".</p></div>
<div><strong>Are China and the U.S.A. Long-Term Enemies?</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>After taping this weekend's Radio Derb, with its segments about U.S. China tensions and geostrategy, I was browsing through my blog roll when I came across this at Steve Hsu's site.</p>
<p>It's one of the Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. debates a real debate, not one of these on the motion: China and the U.S. Are Long-Term Enemies.</p></div>
<div><strong>Debate: Are the U.S. and China Long-Term Enemies?</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>In a spirited Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. debate on Wednesday night, Asia Society Policy Institute President Kevin Rudd and Kissinger Institute Director Robert Daly faced off with University of Chicago Professor John Mearsheimer and Heritage Foundation Senior Fellow Peter Brookes over this provocative motion: China and the U.S. are long-term enemies.</p></div>
<div><strong>Should 100,000 Syrian Refugees Come to America?</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>A major debate between leading U.S. experts on refugee and migration issues, organized by the Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. organization, produced drastically split results on the motion of whether the U.S. should let in 100,000 Syrian Refugees.</p></div>
<div><strong>Is It Reasonable to Resettle Refugees in America?</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>The Syrian refugee crisis coinciding with America's Presidential Campaigns has brought the emotional debate over refugees into the political arenas of nearly every state and over the internet. Candidates and conservative journalists have placed fear of terrorism and radicalization in front of voters while liberals in this country and abroad use compassion and sympathy in an attempt to play the heartstrings of ordinarily big-hearted Americans. While Women of the World obviously believes in our capacity to serve refugees and ensure their benefit to society and has few barriers to the amazing stories of survival of our new refugee neighbors, we want to win both hearts and minds, to show that it is reasonable to resettle refugees in America.</p>
<p>One of the first forays into understanding if it is reasonable to resettle refugees in America was Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. on the subject of Should the US let in 100,000 Syrian Refugees?</p></div>
<div><strong>A Humanitarian Stimulus</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>It's time to dispose of the politics of fear and embrace a pro-refugee, pro-economy policy.</p>
<p>[...]</p>
<p>The new Middle East refugees appear to fit this pattern. In a recent Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. on refugees, David Miliband, president of the International Rescue Committee, noted that eight out of 10 Syrian refugees to the United States are employed within six months of admission. And the Office of Refugee Resettlement within the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services reported in 2013 that Iraqi refugees rapidly increased their rate of economic self-sufficiency from their initial arrival in the United States.</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>A Democratically-Elected Hamas is Still a Terrorist Organization</em></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> November 29, 2006</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> World</p>
<p>In 2006, amidst growing resentment toward the Palestine Liberation Organization, Hamas won political power in a democratic election. The group, named a terrorist organization by both the United States and European Union, retains its charter calling for violence against Israel, yet provides critical social services to its constituents. Is a democratically elected Hamas still a terrorist organization, or should nations around the world recognize Hamas as a legitimate governing body?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/AgpkyZSL-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/AgpkyZSL-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Daniel Ayalon</strong><br>Since 2002, Daniel has worked extensively with the US administration and Congress to advance economic, political, and diplomatic relations. He has served the last three consecutive Israeli administrations, most recently as Chief Foreign Policy Adviser to Prime Minister Ariel Sharon. In the 1990s, he was posted in New York and Panama.
Daniel currently serves as the Deputy Foreign Minister of Israel.</p>
<p><strong>Steven A. Cook</strong><br>Steven is an expert on Arab politics and US Middle East policy, Cook directed the Council's Independent Task Force on reform in the Arab World. He has written widely on Islamist politics and democratic development in the Middle East.</p>
<p><strong>John O'Sullivan</strong><br>John is a political journalist who has edited publications from The National Review to the London Times. He is currently writing a book on Reagan, Thatcher, and the Pope. O'Sullivan began his career as a London correspondent for Irish Radio and Television.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Stanley L. Cohen</strong><br>Stanley is probably best known for his defense of Mousa Abu Marzook, the head of the political wing of Hamas, whose extradition from the United States was sought by Israel in 1995. Over the years, he has represented many other Muslim and Palestinian activists and imams throughout the United States and overseas.</p>
<p><strong>Mohammad-Mahmoud Ould Mohamedou</strong><br>Mohamed Mahmoud Ould Mohamedou is a scholar, author, and diplomat. He is currently the deputy director, a professor of international history and politics, and director of executive education at the Geneva Graduate Institute and has held academic posts at Harvard and the Ralph Bunche Institute on the United Nations (now Ralph Bunche Institute for International Studies at the City University of New York’s Graduate Center), among others. He is the author of severali books and previously served as Minister of Foreign Affairs of Mauritania.</p>
<p><strong>Mark Perry</strong><br>Through the Conflicts Forum, Perry has been engaged in a series of exchanges with Hamas over the past two years. He has worked with Arafat's Fatah wing and Hamas to cool their political competition. He is the author of "A Fire in Zion: The Israeli-Palestinian Search for Peace" (1994).</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Obama's Iran Deal is Good for America: A Debate</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:21:28</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>On Tuesday evening, I attended a debate in New York City sponsored by Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. focusing on whether or not Obama's Iran deal is good for the country. (The podcast is available at the website.)</p>
<p>On the pro side of the debate (for more complete bios on the debaters, visit the IQ2 / Open to Debate website) was Philip Gordon, a senior fellow at the Council on Foreign Relations, former special assistant to the president, and White House coordinator for the Middle East, North Africa, and the Gulf Region. He was joined by Thomas Pickering, currently vice chairman of an international consulting firm but more notable for his time served as a diplomat in various ambassadorships including to the U.N.</p></div>
<div><strong>How to Win the Iran Argument</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:21:28</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>In the heart of blue America ' New York City ' Mark Dubowitz and Mike Doran debated Philip Gordon and Thomas Pickering on whether the Iran deal is good for the United States. The way these things work is that the side that moves opinion the most from pre- to post-debate polling wins. In this case, Dubowitz and Doran won, moving opinion against the deal from 19 to 43 percent. The deal defenders gained just 13 points (from 37 to 50 percent).</p>
<p>The debate is hugely instructive and entertaining and can be viewed in its entirety, but I will note some high points and try to draw some lessons for future debates in and outside Congress.</p></div>
<div><strong>Geopolitical Expert Ian Bremmer on the Choices America Faces</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:21:28</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Q: You seemed to argue at an Intelligence Squared U.S. / Open to Debate, that the US cannot be the world police anymore. How does this notion fit into your idea of an Indispensable America?</p>
<p>Bremmer: I did argue that (though they assign you the position... and any good debater should be able to analytically handle that). But I think Indispensable America is becoming much more challenging. US allies are less capable/willing to support. US adversaries are more willing to challenge. And the willingness of the American people to pay the tab in blood and treasure is decreasing. I'd be much more comfortable with Indispensable America if I believed we could actually follow through on it.</p></div>
<div><strong>Do We Have an ISIS Strategy?</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>That the debate surrounding ISIS seems confused was recently echoed in an actual debate on the topic. The folks at Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. recently held a formal Oxford Union-style debate at the Aspen Security Forum. The proposition being debated was Containment is not enough: ISIS must be defeated. The outcome wasn't surprising, but the arguments were. All four debaters agreed that ISIS had to be fought militarily, ideologically, and in what stands for public opinion these days: social media. The only real question was: What is America's role?</p></div>
<div><strong>Between Iraq and a Hawk Base</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>That tension between steadfast principles and hard realities, both at home and abroad, was on display when some of America's leading foreign-policy thinkers gathered for a retreat hosted by the Aspen Institute, a nonpartisan education and policy organization, in August. The conference's main event was an hour-long debate about ISIS. Each debate team featured two national security officials from the Bush and Obama administrations. One team, Philip Zelikow, a former counselor to Secretary of State Condoleezza Rice, and Michale Flournoy, Obama's former defense undersecretary of defense for policy, argued that ISIS should be defeated, including through military means. The other team, Dov Zakheim, Bush's former Defense Department comptroller and foreign ­policy adviser, and Anne-Marie Slaughter, Obama's director of policy planning for the State Department, argued that it should be contained until it collapsed under the weight of its own failed ideology, as occurred with the Soviet Union. Among the 200 spectators were retired general David Petraeus, the former Secretary of State Madeleine Albright, and Jeb Bush's outside adviser, Richard Fontaine.</p>
<p>The debate was spirited and replete with unintended ironies. There was Flournoy, the former Obama official, arguing the traditional neocon position that the only way to give the lie to ISIS's ideology was to take territory away from ISIS And there was Zakheim, the former Bush official, sounding decidedly noninterventionist: The issue is, can you and are you willing to send in hundreds of thousands of troops? Do you think this country wants to do that? Do you think we even want to spend money to do that?</p>
<p>Zakheim's realpolitik warning hit the audience like a bucket of cold water. Even the nation's most intellectually rigorous foreign thinkers seemed struck by the challenge of convincing the American public that war against ISIS would not entail a horrific reprise of the Iraq war. Surveyed before the debate began, 52 percent of attendees believed that ISIS should be destroyed, with 27 percent saying it should be contained and another 21 percent being undecided. After the debate, the audience underwent a reversal: 59 percent were now convinced that the proper course of action was to contain ISIS rather than to pour blood and treasure into an attempt to destroy it.</p></div>
<div><strong>Enemies? Frenemies? Debate on China-US Ties Concludes That War Isn't Imminent</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>A former prime minister of Australia, a political science professor, and two senior members from United States-based think-tanks took turns at the lectern at a packed auditorium in Kaufman Music Center on Oct. 14 to debate a topic of the times: are China and the United States long-term enemies?</p></div>
<div><strong>Sino-US Ties: Prospects for Cooperation not Confrontation</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>In a debate held by "Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S.", renowned international relations experts such as John J. Mearsheimer from the University of Chicago and former Australian prime minister Kevin Rudd debated whether China and the US would become long-term enemies. The opinion poll of audiences that followed shows that 56 percent of those on site and 64 percent of those on-line said "no".</p></div>
<div><strong>Are China and the U.S.A. Long-Term Enemies?</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>After taping this weekend's Radio Derb, with its segments about U.S. China tensions and geostrategy, I was browsing through my blog roll when I came across this at Steve Hsu's site.</p>
<p>It's one of the Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. debates a real debate, not one of these on the motion: China and the U.S. Are Long-Term Enemies.</p></div>
<div><strong>Debate: Are the U.S. and China Long-Term Enemies?</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>In a spirited Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. debate on Wednesday night, Asia Society Policy Institute President Kevin Rudd and Kissinger Institute Director Robert Daly faced off with University of Chicago Professor John Mearsheimer and Heritage Foundation Senior Fellow Peter Brookes over this provocative motion: China and the U.S. are long-term enemies.</p></div>
<div><strong>Should 100,000 Syrian Refugees Come to America?</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>A major debate between leading U.S. experts on refugee and migration issues, organized by the Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. organization, produced drastically split results on the motion of whether the U.S. should let in 100,000 Syrian Refugees.</p></div>
<div><strong>Is It Reasonable to Resettle Refugees in America?</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>The Syrian refugee crisis coinciding with America's Presidential Campaigns has brought the emotional debate over refugees into the political arenas of nearly every state and over the internet. Candidates and conservative journalists have placed fear of terrorism and radicalization in front of voters while liberals in this country and abroad use compassion and sympathy in an attempt to play the heartstrings of ordinarily big-hearted Americans. While Women of the World obviously believes in our capacity to serve refugees and ensure their benefit to society and has few barriers to the amazing stories of survival of our new refugee neighbors, we want to win both hearts and minds, to show that it is reasonable to resettle refugees in America.</p>
<p>One of the first forays into understanding if it is reasonable to resettle refugees in America was Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. on the subject of Should the US let in 100,000 Syrian Refugees?</p></div>
<div><strong>A Humanitarian Stimulus</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>It's time to dispose of the politics of fear and embrace a pro-refugee, pro-economy policy.</p>
<p>[...]</p>
<p>The new Middle East refugees appear to fit this pattern. In a recent Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. on refugees, David Miliband, president of the International Rescue Committee, noted that eight out of 10 Syrian refugees to the United States are employed within six months of admission. And the Office of Refugee Resettlement within the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services reported in 2013 that Iraqi refugees rapidly increased their rate of economic self-sufficiency from their initial arrival in the United States.</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>A Democratically-Elected Hamas is Still a Terrorist Organization</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Freedom of Expression Must Include the License to Offend</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/freedom-expression-must-include-license-offend</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10111</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> October 17, 2006</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Culture</p>
<p>Heralding the First Amendment, proponents of free speech champion the right to expression unencumbered by government intervention. But is freedom of expression absolute and limitless?  Should we be free to use words with the intention to harm?  Should some words remain unspoken, or does this mind-set lead us to the path of censorship?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/1P3G4LwN-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/1P3G4LwN-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Philip Gourevitch</strong><br>Philip is the author of "A Cold Case" (2001) and "We Wish to Inform You That Tomorrow We Will be Killed With Our Families: Stories From Rwanda" (1998), winners of the National Book Critics Circle Award, the LA Times Book Prize, and in England, the Guardian First Book Award.</p>
<p><strong>Christopher Hitchens</strong><br>For nearly a dozen years, Christopher Hitchens contributed an essay on books each month to The Atlantic. He was the author of more than ten books, including "A Long Short War: The Postponed Liberation of Iraq" (2003), "Why Orwell Matters" (2002), "God Is Not Great" (2007), and "Hitch-22" (2009). He was a contributing editor to Vanity Fair and wrote prolifically for American and English periodicals, including The Nation, The London Review of Books, Granta, Harper's, The Los Angeles Times Book Review, New Left Review, Slate, The New York Review of Books, Newsweek International, The Times Literary Supplement, and The Washington Post. He was also a regular television and radio commentator.
Hitchens began his career in England in the 1970s as a writer for the New Statesman and the Evening Standard<em>.</em> From 1977 to 1979, he worked for London's Daily Express as a foreign correspondent and then returned to the New Statesman as foreign editor, where he worked from 1979 to 1981. Hitchens has also served as the Washington editor for Harper's and as the U.S. correspondent for The Spectator and The Times Literary Supplement. From 1986 to 1992, he was the book critic at New York Newsday. He also taught as a visiting professor at the University of California, Berkeley; the University of Pittsburgh; and the New School of Social Research.
Born in 1949 in Portsmouth, England, Hitchens received a degree in philosophy, politics, and economics from Balliol College, Oxford, in 1970.</p>
<p><strong>Signe Wilkinson</strong><br>Signe is the author of One Nation, Under Surveillance, and the winner of the Pulitzer Prize for editorial cartooning in 1992. Her editorial cartoons are syndicated by the Washington Post Writers Group.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>David Cesarani</strong><br>David is a British scholar specializing in Jewish history who has written and edited over a dozen books. He has advised the British government on the commemoration of the Holocaust. In 2006, he was recognized in the Queen's New Year's Honors list for services to Holocaust education.</p>
<p><strong>Daisy Khan</strong><br>Dasiy Khan founded ASMA, which is a non-profit religious and educational organization dedicated to building bridges between the American public and American Muslims. As wife of Imam Feisal of Masjid al-Farah in New York City, Khan mentors young Muslim women who face challenges of cultural assimilation in America and counsels Muslims on marital and spiritual issues.</p>
<p><strong>Mari Matsuda</strong><br>Mari specializes in the fields of torts, constitutional law, legal history, feminist theory, critical race theory, and civil rights law. She was the first tenured female Asian American law professor in the US at the UCLA School of Law. Matsuda is the author of numerous books with Charles R. Lawrence III.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>"Smart Drugs" Are Here -Should College Students Be Allowed to Use Them?</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>We use coffee to stay awake, good food and nutrition to stay healthy and alert. But if there was a drug that made you smarter, helped you learn, and made you more focused, would you take it?</p>
<p>That's a question that Nicole Vincent, associate professor of philosophy, law and neuroscience at Georgia State University, asked to open her TED talk in Sydney last year.</p>
<p>That question also opened a Monday night debate at George Washington University in which two sides argued both for and against whether "College Students Should Be Allowed to Take Smart Drugs."</p></div>
<div><strong>Are Smart Drugs a Smart Choice? Experts Debate at SMPA</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>If there was a pill that could make everyone smarter and more focused, how many people would take it?</p>
<p>This question was the subject of debate among experts at the Jack Morton Auditorium Monday night. Moderated by ABC News correspondent John Donvan, the panel weighed the medical and moral risks, as well as the benefits, of college students using drugs like Adderall, without a prescription, to help them study.</p></div>
<div><strong>Are Smart Drugs Good for College Students?</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Should college students take smart drugs? That was the question posed to a panel of professors at an Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. debate at George Washington University on Monday night.</p></div>
<div><strong>Intelligence Squared / Open to Debate FIRE Debate: College Students Should Be Allowed to Take Smart Drugs</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. and the Foundation for Individual Rights in Education (FIRE) are embarking on a joint venture (that I am proud to have brokered), to present a series of high-profile debates on college campuses. Our first debate will be tomorrow at George Washington University.</p></div>
<div><strong>Smart Drugs for College Kids</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Pop a pill, ace a test. If you could take a pill that would instantly make you work harder, improve your brain function, and make you smarter, would you?</p>
<p>A panel of experts argued this question in a debate this week presented by Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. at George Washington University in Washington, D.C., entitled, College Students Should be Allowed to Take Smart Drugs.</p></div>
<div><strong>New Haven Debate Will Focus on Whether Free Speech Is Threatened on Campuses</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>The atmosphere on campuses nationwide has become charged with accusations, on one side, that micro-aggressions are hurtful to women and people of color and countercharges that universities are censoring speakers.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the issue will land in the spotlight at the Yale Repertory Theatre as four debaters argue for or against the statement, Free speech is threatened on campus.</p>
<p>I don't think there's any question that free speech is threatened on campus. I think the question is whether free speech should be threatened on campus, said Wendy Kaminer, who is one of the debaters in the Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. debate, sponsored by the Adam Smith Society, an organization composed of business school students and alumni.</p></div>
<div><strong>Tell Us: Is Your Speech Policed in Your Dorm?</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>On Tuesday, an audience gathered at Yale to hear a debate on the proposition, 'Free speech is threatened on campus.'The question pertained to institutions of higher education generally, not just the host university. The outcome: a clear majority agree that free speech is threatened. But that wasn't yet true when the event began.</p></div>
<div><strong>Students Unswayed by Free Speech Debate</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Before a nearly full auditorium at the Yale Repertory Theater Tuesday night, the NPR show 'Intelligence Squared U.S. / Open to Debate'hosted a debate on the motion that free speech is threatened on college campuses. But despite the robust turnout, most students' opinions on the topic remained largely unchanged, with students stating that many of the arguments advanced at the debate were ideas they had already heard last fall.</p></div>
<div><strong>Debate at Yale Rep in New Haven Examines Free Speech on Campus</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>The atmosphere on college campuses has changed, a Columbia University professor argued before an audience full of Yale students and New Haven residents Tuesday. And that change has created spaces in which free speech is not extinguished, but threatened.</p>
<p>A majority of the audience agreed.</p>
<p>After a debate hosted by Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S., a nonprofit that provides free online access to debates held across the country on issues facing society, 66 percent of the audience left convinced that free speech is threatened on college campuses. The event was held at the Yale Repertory Theatre.</p></div>
<div><strong>Critics of Leftist Assault on Campus Win over Yale Audience in Free-Speech Debate</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Portrayed as 'ignorant at best and immoral at worst,' non-leftist students self-censor.</p>
<p>In recent weeks, speakers such as conservative Ben Shapiro and anti-feminist Milo Yiannopoulos have faced angry crowds of progressive students who tried to shut down their campus speeches with interruptions and physical confrontations.</p>
<p>Yet it took an evening of civil debate between scholars and writers to convince a divided Yale University audience that 'free speech is threatened on campus.'</p>
<p>The public radio show and podcast Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. hosted the Tuesday evening Oxford-style debate at Yale, moderated by ABC News correspondent John Donvan.</p></div>
<div><strong>The Glaring Evidence That Free Speech Is Threatened on Campus</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>A debate at Yale highlighted the disconnect between those who would downplay the problem, and the growing mass of evidence that they're wrong.</p>
<p>At a recentIntelligence Squared / Open to Debate (https://opentodebate.org/debate/free-speech-threatened-campus/), an audience filled an auditorium at Yale University to weigh the timely proposition, 'Free speech is threatened on campus.' The debate concerned higher education generally, not just the host institution. And at the event's conclusion, having heard arguments on both sides of the question, 66 percent of the crowd agreed: free speech is threatened. That represented a 17-point shift from a poll taken as the event began. The evidence is that persuasive.</p></div>
<div><strong>Open to Debate: Free Speech Is Threatened on Campus</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Open to Debate presented an excellent debate on Tuesday at Yale 'Resolved: Free speech is threatened on campus.'</p>
<p>Yale was a particularly apt venue for this debate. Yale has a proud tradition of freedom of speech, and its official statement on free speech, the 'Woodward Report' of 1974, is one of the strongest defenses of free speech in the academy. But the infamous controversy of this past Halloween, and the way that Yale handled the controversy, have led many to doubt Yale's current commitment to free speech. This year, Yale only narrowly avoided ranking among the 10 worst colleges in the United States for free speech, according to the Foundation for Individual Rights in Education (FIRE). So this debate was particularly timely, and it clearly struck a nerve at Yale.</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Freedom of Expression Must Include the License to Offend</em></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> October 17, 2006</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Culture</p>
<p>Heralding the First Amendment, proponents of free speech champion the right to expression unencumbered by government intervention. But is freedom of expression absolute and limitless?  Should we be free to use words with the intention to harm?  Should some words remain unspoken, or does this mind-set lead us to the path of censorship?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/1P3G4LwN-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/1P3G4LwN-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Philip Gourevitch</strong><br>Philip is the author of "A Cold Case" (2001) and "We Wish to Inform You That Tomorrow We Will be Killed With Our Families: Stories From Rwanda" (1998), winners of the National Book Critics Circle Award, the LA Times Book Prize, and in England, the Guardian First Book Award.</p>
<p><strong>Christopher Hitchens</strong><br>For nearly a dozen years, Christopher Hitchens contributed an essay on books each month to The Atlantic. He was the author of more than ten books, including "A Long Short War: The Postponed Liberation of Iraq" (2003), "Why Orwell Matters" (2002), "God Is Not Great" (2007), and "Hitch-22" (2009). He was a contributing editor to Vanity Fair and wrote prolifically for American and English periodicals, including The Nation, The London Review of Books, Granta, Harper's, The Los Angeles Times Book Review, New Left Review, Slate, The New York Review of Books, Newsweek International, The Times Literary Supplement, and The Washington Post. He was also a regular television and radio commentator.
Hitchens began his career in England in the 1970s as a writer for the New Statesman and the Evening Standard<em>.</em> From 1977 to 1979, he worked for London's Daily Express as a foreign correspondent and then returned to the New Statesman as foreign editor, where he worked from 1979 to 1981. Hitchens has also served as the Washington editor for Harper's and as the U.S. correspondent for The Spectator and The Times Literary Supplement. From 1986 to 1992, he was the book critic at New York Newsday. He also taught as a visiting professor at the University of California, Berkeley; the University of Pittsburgh; and the New School of Social Research.
Born in 1949 in Portsmouth, England, Hitchens received a degree in philosophy, politics, and economics from Balliol College, Oxford, in 1970.</p>
<p><strong>Signe Wilkinson</strong><br>Signe is the author of One Nation, Under Surveillance, and the winner of the Pulitzer Prize for editorial cartooning in 1992. Her editorial cartoons are syndicated by the Washington Post Writers Group.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>David Cesarani</strong><br>David is a British scholar specializing in Jewish history who has written and edited over a dozen books. He has advised the British government on the commemoration of the Holocaust. In 2006, he was recognized in the Queen's New Year's Honors list for services to Holocaust education.</p>
<p><strong>Daisy Khan</strong><br>Dasiy Khan founded ASMA, which is a non-profit religious and educational organization dedicated to building bridges between the American public and American Muslims. As wife of Imam Feisal of Masjid al-Farah in New York City, Khan mentors young Muslim women who face challenges of cultural assimilation in America and counsels Muslims on marital and spiritual issues.</p>
<p><strong>Mari Matsuda</strong><br>Mari specializes in the fields of torts, constitutional law, legal history, feminist theory, critical race theory, and civil rights law. She was the first tenured female Asian American law professor in the US at the UCLA School of Law. Matsuda is the author of numerous books with Charles R. Lawrence III.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>"Smart Drugs" Are Here -Should College Students Be Allowed to Use Them?</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>We use coffee to stay awake, good food and nutrition to stay healthy and alert. But if there was a drug that made you smarter, helped you learn, and made you more focused, would you take it?</p>
<p>That's a question that Nicole Vincent, associate professor of philosophy, law and neuroscience at Georgia State University, asked to open her TED talk in Sydney last year.</p>
<p>That question also opened a Monday night debate at George Washington University in which two sides argued both for and against whether "College Students Should Be Allowed to Take Smart Drugs."</p></div>
<div><strong>Are Smart Drugs a Smart Choice? Experts Debate at SMPA</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>If there was a pill that could make everyone smarter and more focused, how many people would take it?</p>
<p>This question was the subject of debate among experts at the Jack Morton Auditorium Monday night. Moderated by ABC News correspondent John Donvan, the panel weighed the medical and moral risks, as well as the benefits, of college students using drugs like Adderall, without a prescription, to help them study.</p></div>
<div><strong>Are Smart Drugs Good for College Students?</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Should college students take smart drugs? That was the question posed to a panel of professors at an Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. debate at George Washington University on Monday night.</p></div>
<div><strong>Intelligence Squared / Open to Debate FIRE Debate: College Students Should Be Allowed to Take Smart Drugs</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. and the Foundation for Individual Rights in Education (FIRE) are embarking on a joint venture (that I am proud to have brokered), to present a series of high-profile debates on college campuses. Our first debate will be tomorrow at George Washington University.</p></div>
<div><strong>Smart Drugs for College Kids</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Pop a pill, ace a test. If you could take a pill that would instantly make you work harder, improve your brain function, and make you smarter, would you?</p>
<p>A panel of experts argued this question in a debate this week presented by Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. at George Washington University in Washington, D.C., entitled, College Students Should be Allowed to Take Smart Drugs.</p></div>
<div><strong>New Haven Debate Will Focus on Whether Free Speech Is Threatened on Campuses</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>The atmosphere on campuses nationwide has become charged with accusations, on one side, that micro-aggressions are hurtful to women and people of color and countercharges that universities are censoring speakers.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the issue will land in the spotlight at the Yale Repertory Theatre as four debaters argue for or against the statement, Free speech is threatened on campus.</p>
<p>I don't think there's any question that free speech is threatened on campus. I think the question is whether free speech should be threatened on campus, said Wendy Kaminer, who is one of the debaters in the Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. debate, sponsored by the Adam Smith Society, an organization composed of business school students and alumni.</p></div>
<div><strong>Tell Us: Is Your Speech Policed in Your Dorm?</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>On Tuesday, an audience gathered at Yale to hear a debate on the proposition, 'Free speech is threatened on campus.'The question pertained to institutions of higher education generally, not just the host university. The outcome: a clear majority agree that free speech is threatened. But that wasn't yet true when the event began.</p></div>
<div><strong>Students Unswayed by Free Speech Debate</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Before a nearly full auditorium at the Yale Repertory Theater Tuesday night, the NPR show 'Intelligence Squared U.S. / Open to Debate'hosted a debate on the motion that free speech is threatened on college campuses. But despite the robust turnout, most students' opinions on the topic remained largely unchanged, with students stating that many of the arguments advanced at the debate were ideas they had already heard last fall.</p></div>
<div><strong>Debate at Yale Rep in New Haven Examines Free Speech on Campus</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>The atmosphere on college campuses has changed, a Columbia University professor argued before an audience full of Yale students and New Haven residents Tuesday. And that change has created spaces in which free speech is not extinguished, but threatened.</p>
<p>A majority of the audience agreed.</p>
<p>After a debate hosted by Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S., a nonprofit that provides free online access to debates held across the country on issues facing society, 66 percent of the audience left convinced that free speech is threatened on college campuses. The event was held at the Yale Repertory Theatre.</p></div>
<div><strong>Critics of Leftist Assault on Campus Win over Yale Audience in Free-Speech Debate</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Portrayed as 'ignorant at best and immoral at worst,' non-leftist students self-censor.</p>
<p>In recent weeks, speakers such as conservative Ben Shapiro and anti-feminist Milo Yiannopoulos have faced angry crowds of progressive students who tried to shut down their campus speeches with interruptions and physical confrontations.</p>
<p>Yet it took an evening of civil debate between scholars and writers to convince a divided Yale University audience that 'free speech is threatened on campus.'</p>
<p>The public radio show and podcast Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. hosted the Tuesday evening Oxford-style debate at Yale, moderated by ABC News correspondent John Donvan.</p></div>
<div><strong>The Glaring Evidence That Free Speech Is Threatened on Campus</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>A debate at Yale highlighted the disconnect between those who would downplay the problem, and the growing mass of evidence that they're wrong.</p>
<p>At a recentIntelligence Squared / Open to Debate (https://opentodebate.org/debate/free-speech-threatened-campus/), an audience filled an auditorium at Yale University to weigh the timely proposition, 'Free speech is threatened on campus.' The debate concerned higher education generally, not just the host institution. And at the event's conclusion, having heard arguments on both sides of the question, 66 percent of the crowd agreed: free speech is threatened. That represented a 17-point shift from a poll taken as the event began. The evidence is that persuasive.</p></div>
<div><strong>Open to Debate: Free Speech Is Threatened on Campus</strong> <small>2016-05-13 14:45:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Open to Debate presented an excellent debate on Tuesday at Yale 'Resolved: Free speech is threatened on campus.'</p>
<p>Yale was a particularly apt venue for this debate. Yale has a proud tradition of freedom of speech, and its official statement on free speech, the 'Woodward Report' of 1974, is one of the strongest defenses of free speech in the academy. But the infamous controversy of this past Halloween, and the way that Yale handled the controversy, have led many to doubt Yale's current commitment to free speech. This year, Yale only narrowly avoided ranking among the 10 worst colleges in the United States for free speech, according to the Foundation for Individual Rights in Education (FIRE). So this debate was particularly timely, and it clearly struck a nerve at Yale.</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Freedom of Expression Must Include the License to Offend</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>We Must Tolerate a Nuclear Iran</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/we-must-tolerate-a-nuclear-iran</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10294</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> September 27, 2006</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> World</p>
<p>There is no doubt that a nuclear Iran would be a danger to the United States and its allies. But would the costs of going to war outweigh the costs of tolerating a nuclear Iran?  And is diplomacy without the threat of military force ineffective?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/d5AJ4Ga8-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/d5AJ4Ga8-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>George Perkovich</strong><br>George is an expert in US foreign policy, non-proliferation, security, global governance, non-governmental actors, India, Iran, and Pakistan.</p>
<p><strong>Karim Sadjadpour</strong><br>Karim Sadjadpour is a senior associate at the Carnegie Endowment. He joined Carnegie after four years as the chief Iran analyst at the International Crisis Group based in Washington and Tehran, where he conducted dozens of interviews with senior Iranian officials and hundreds with Iranian intellectuals, clerics, dissidents, paramilitaries, businessmen, students, activists, and youth, among others.
He is a regular contributor to BBC TV and radio, CNN, National Public Radio, PBS NewsHour, and Al-Jazeera, and has appeared on the "Today Show", "Charlie Rose", "Fox News Sunday", and the "Colbert Report", among others. He contributes regularly to publications such as The Economist, The Washington Post, The New York Times, The International Herald Tribune, and Foreign Policy.
Frequently called upon to brief U.S., EU, and Asian officials about Middle Eastern affairs, he regularly testifies before Congress, has lectured at Harvard, Princeton, and Stanford Universities, and has been the recipient of numerous academic awards, including a Fulbright scholarship.
In 2007, Sadjadpour was named a Young Global Leader by the World Economic Forum in Davos. He is a board member of the Banu Foundation, an organization dedicated to assisting grassroots organizations that are empowering women worldwide.
He has lived in Latin America, Europe, and the Middle East.</p>
<p><strong>Sanam Vakil</strong><br>Sanam is a former research associate for the Council on Foreign Relations' Iran Project and served as a consultant to the World Bank Group's Middle East and North Africa Division.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Patrick Clawson</strong><br>Patrick's previous positions include five years as a senior research professor at the National Defense University's Institute for National Strategic Studies and four years each as a senior economist at the Foreign Policy Research Institute, the World Bank, and the IMF. He is the author of numerous books on the Middle East and Iran.</p>
<p><strong>Reuel Marc Gerecht</strong><br>Reuel Marc Gerecht is a former case officer for the CIA, where he served as a Middle Eastern targets officer with the CIA's directorate of operations. He is a senior fellow at the Foundation for Defense of Democracies, a non-partisan organization centered on national security, where he focuses on Iran, sanctions, terrorism, and the Middle East. He is the author of "Know Thy Enemy: A Spy’s Journey into Revolutionary Iran" and "The Islamic Paradox: Shiite Clerics, Sunni Fundamentalists, and the Coming of Arab Democracy," among others.</p>
<p><strong>Bill Kristol</strong><br>Bill Kristol has been a leading participant in American political debates and a widely respected analyst of American political developments for decades. Having served in senior positions in the Reagan and George H.W. Bush administrations, Kristol understands government from the inside; as a professor at the University of Pennsylvania and Harvard University, he has studied American politics and society from the outside. After serving in the Reagan and George H.W. Bush administrations, Kristol founded and edited The Weekly Standard from 1995 until its 2018 closure. Now, he is the editor-at-large of The Bulwark and founding director of Defending Democracy Together, an organization dedicated to defending America’s liberal democratic norms, principles, and institutions. Today, Kristol speaks on issues ranging from American foreign policy to the future of the Republican Party and the meaning of American conservatism. Kristol frequently appears on all the major television talk shows, and is the host of “Conversations with Bill Kristol.” Kristol received his undergraduate degree and his Ph.D. from Harvard University. Kristol is also the co-author of the bestseller “The War Over Iraq: America’s Mission and Saddam’s Tyranny”.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Open to Debate Presents: It’s Time to Expand Nuclear Power with Bill Nye</strong> <small>2023-02-08 18:52:41</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>On Thursday, January 23, Bill Nye takes the Open to Debate stage to kick off the veteran debate series’ spring season. Nye, a longtime fan who publicly changed his mind about GMOs after attending the 2014 Open to Debate on the subject, will offer a nuclear power explainer to introduce the nonprofit’s live debate on the motion “It’s Time to Expand Nuclear Power.”</p>
<p>Proponents claim that nuclear energy is the most effective way to combat climate change while still meeting the world’s growing demand for energy. But critics argue that expanding nuclear energy is dangerous, costly, and ill-advised. Should nuclear energy fuel our future? Arguing yes will be Daniel Poneman, Deputy Secretary of Energy under President Obama, and the co-founder of Energy for Humanity, Kirsty Gogan. Arguing against them will be former chairman of the US Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Gregory B. Jaczko, and the president of the Institute for Energy and Environmental Research, Arjun Makhijani.</p>
<p>The “It’s Time to Expand Nuclear Power” debate will mark Open to Debate debut at their new NYC home, the Florence Gould Hall, then air soon after as part of the syndicated public radio show, podcast, and video series “Open to Debate”</p>
<p>KEYNOTE SPEAKER</p>
<p>* Bill Nye: Scientist and CEO of the Planetary Society
Bill Nye, scientist, engineer, comedian, author, and inventor, is a man with a mission: to help foster a scientifically literate society and to help people everywhere understand and appreciate the science that makes our world work. After Nye attended a 2014 Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. debate on GMOs, he spent time with panelist Dr. Robert Fraley and publicly changed his mind on the topic. He is CEO of the Planetary Society, a space-interest group, and hosts the “Science Rules!” podcast. Nye is best known for hosting the children’s science show “Bill Nye the Science Guy,” “Bill Nye Saves the World,” and is the author of multiple bestselling books.</p>
<p>For the Motion</p>
<p>* Kirsty Gogan: Co-founder and Executive Director of Energy for Humanity
Kirsty Gogan is the co-founder and executive director of Energy for Humanity (EFH), an NGO focused on decarbonization and energy access. EFH led a delegation of climate scientists to defend nuclear energy at the Paris Climate Conference. A founding director of CleanTech Catalyst, Gogan has advised the UK government on nuclear power and evaluated the national response to Fukushima.</p>
<p>* Daniel Poneman: President and CEO of Centrus Energy
Daniel Poneman is a former government official and nuclear energy executive. Under President Obama, he was the Deputy Secretary of Energy and also served as a COO of the Department of Energy. He is now the president and CEO of Centrus Energy, a global energy company that supplies low enriched uranium for commercial nuclear power plants. He is a senior fellow at the Belfer Center for Science and International Affairs and author of the recent book “Double Jeopardy: Combating Nuclear Terror and Climate Change.”</p>
<p>Arguing Against the Motion</p>
<p>* Gregory B. Jaczko: Former Chairman of the US Nuclear Regulatory Commission
Gregory B. Jaczko is the former chairman of the US Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC), where he handled the American government’s response to the Fukushima meltdown. After leaving the NRC, he wrote “Confessions of A Nuclear Regulator” and founded the wind energy company Wind Future LLC.</p>
<p>* Arjun Makhijani: President of the Institute for Energy and Environmental Research
Arjun Makhijani is the president of the Institute for Energy and Environmental Research and the author of “Carbon-Free and Nuclear Free: A Roadmap for US Energy Policy.” He has spent decades studying nuclear disarmament and energy efficiency. Makhijani has a Ph.D. from University of California at Berkeley, where he specialized in nuclear fusion.</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>We Must Tolerate a Nuclear Iran</em></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> September 27, 2006</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> World</p>
<p>There is no doubt that a nuclear Iran would be a danger to the United States and its allies. But would the costs of going to war outweigh the costs of tolerating a nuclear Iran?  And is diplomacy without the threat of military force ineffective?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/d5AJ4Ga8-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/d5AJ4Ga8-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>George Perkovich</strong><br>George is an expert in US foreign policy, non-proliferation, security, global governance, non-governmental actors, India, Iran, and Pakistan.</p>
<p><strong>Karim Sadjadpour</strong><br>Karim Sadjadpour is a senior associate at the Carnegie Endowment. He joined Carnegie after four years as the chief Iran analyst at the International Crisis Group based in Washington and Tehran, where he conducted dozens of interviews with senior Iranian officials and hundreds with Iranian intellectuals, clerics, dissidents, paramilitaries, businessmen, students, activists, and youth, among others.
He is a regular contributor to BBC TV and radio, CNN, National Public Radio, PBS NewsHour, and Al-Jazeera, and has appeared on the "Today Show", "Charlie Rose", "Fox News Sunday", and the "Colbert Report", among others. He contributes regularly to publications such as The Economist, The Washington Post, The New York Times, The International Herald Tribune, and Foreign Policy.
Frequently called upon to brief U.S., EU, and Asian officials about Middle Eastern affairs, he regularly testifies before Congress, has lectured at Harvard, Princeton, and Stanford Universities, and has been the recipient of numerous academic awards, including a Fulbright scholarship.
In 2007, Sadjadpour was named a Young Global Leader by the World Economic Forum in Davos. He is a board member of the Banu Foundation, an organization dedicated to assisting grassroots organizations that are empowering women worldwide.
He has lived in Latin America, Europe, and the Middle East.</p>
<p><strong>Sanam Vakil</strong><br>Sanam is a former research associate for the Council on Foreign Relations' Iran Project and served as a consultant to the World Bank Group's Middle East and North Africa Division.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Patrick Clawson</strong><br>Patrick's previous positions include five years as a senior research professor at the National Defense University's Institute for National Strategic Studies and four years each as a senior economist at the Foreign Policy Research Institute, the World Bank, and the IMF. He is the author of numerous books on the Middle East and Iran.</p>
<p><strong>Reuel Marc Gerecht</strong><br>Reuel Marc Gerecht is a former case officer for the CIA, where he served as a Middle Eastern targets officer with the CIA's directorate of operations. He is a senior fellow at the Foundation for Defense of Democracies, a non-partisan organization centered on national security, where he focuses on Iran, sanctions, terrorism, and the Middle East. He is the author of "Know Thy Enemy: A Spy’s Journey into Revolutionary Iran" and "The Islamic Paradox: Shiite Clerics, Sunni Fundamentalists, and the Coming of Arab Democracy," among others.</p>
<p><strong>Bill Kristol</strong><br>Bill Kristol has been a leading participant in American political debates and a widely respected analyst of American political developments for decades. Having served in senior positions in the Reagan and George H.W. Bush administrations, Kristol understands government from the inside; as a professor at the University of Pennsylvania and Harvard University, he has studied American politics and society from the outside. After serving in the Reagan and George H.W. Bush administrations, Kristol founded and edited The Weekly Standard from 1995 until its 2018 closure. Now, he is the editor-at-large of The Bulwark and founding director of Defending Democracy Together, an organization dedicated to defending America’s liberal democratic norms, principles, and institutions. Today, Kristol speaks on issues ranging from American foreign policy to the future of the Republican Party and the meaning of American conservatism. Kristol frequently appears on all the major television talk shows, and is the host of “Conversations with Bill Kristol.” Kristol received his undergraduate degree and his Ph.D. from Harvard University. Kristol is also the co-author of the bestseller “The War Over Iraq: America’s Mission and Saddam’s Tyranny”.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Open to Debate Presents: It’s Time to Expand Nuclear Power with Bill Nye</strong> <small>2023-02-08 18:52:41</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>On Thursday, January 23, Bill Nye takes the Open to Debate stage to kick off the veteran debate series’ spring season. Nye, a longtime fan who publicly changed his mind about GMOs after attending the 2014 Open to Debate on the subject, will offer a nuclear power explainer to introduce the nonprofit’s live debate on the motion “It’s Time to Expand Nuclear Power.”</p>
<p>Proponents claim that nuclear energy is the most effective way to combat climate change while still meeting the world’s growing demand for energy. But critics argue that expanding nuclear energy is dangerous, costly, and ill-advised. Should nuclear energy fuel our future? Arguing yes will be Daniel Poneman, Deputy Secretary of Energy under President Obama, and the co-founder of Energy for Humanity, Kirsty Gogan. Arguing against them will be former chairman of the US Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Gregory B. Jaczko, and the president of the Institute for Energy and Environmental Research, Arjun Makhijani.</p>
<p>The “It’s Time to Expand Nuclear Power” debate will mark Open to Debate debut at their new NYC home, the Florence Gould Hall, then air soon after as part of the syndicated public radio show, podcast, and video series “Open to Debate”</p>
<p>KEYNOTE SPEAKER</p>
<p>* Bill Nye: Scientist and CEO of the Planetary Society
Bill Nye, scientist, engineer, comedian, author, and inventor, is a man with a mission: to help foster a scientifically literate society and to help people everywhere understand and appreciate the science that makes our world work. After Nye attended a 2014 Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. debate on GMOs, he spent time with panelist Dr. Robert Fraley and publicly changed his mind on the topic. He is CEO of the Planetary Society, a space-interest group, and hosts the “Science Rules!” podcast. Nye is best known for hosting the children’s science show “Bill Nye the Science Guy,” “Bill Nye Saves the World,” and is the author of multiple bestselling books.</p>
<p>For the Motion</p>
<p>* Kirsty Gogan: Co-founder and Executive Director of Energy for Humanity
Kirsty Gogan is the co-founder and executive director of Energy for Humanity (EFH), an NGO focused on decarbonization and energy access. EFH led a delegation of climate scientists to defend nuclear energy at the Paris Climate Conference. A founding director of CleanTech Catalyst, Gogan has advised the UK government on nuclear power and evaluated the national response to Fukushima.</p>
<p>* Daniel Poneman: President and CEO of Centrus Energy
Daniel Poneman is a former government official and nuclear energy executive. Under President Obama, he was the Deputy Secretary of Energy and also served as a COO of the Department of Energy. He is now the president and CEO of Centrus Energy, a global energy company that supplies low enriched uranium for commercial nuclear power plants. He is a senior fellow at the Belfer Center for Science and International Affairs and author of the recent book “Double Jeopardy: Combating Nuclear Terror and Climate Change.”</p>
<p>Arguing Against the Motion</p>
<p>* Gregory B. Jaczko: Former Chairman of the US Nuclear Regulatory Commission
Gregory B. Jaczko is the former chairman of the US Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC), where he handled the American government’s response to the Fukushima meltdown. After leaving the NRC, he wrote “Confessions of A Nuclear Regulator” and founded the wind energy company Wind Future LLC.</p>
<p>* Arjun Makhijani: President of the Institute for Energy and Environmental Research
Arjun Makhijani is the president of the Institute for Energy and Environmental Research and the author of “Carbon-Free and Nuclear Free: A Roadmap for US Energy Policy.” He has spent decades studying nuclear disarmament and energy efficiency. Makhijani has a Ph.D. from University of California at Berkeley, where he specialized in nuclear fusion.</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>We Must Tolerate a Nuclear Iran</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
    
</rss>
