<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">

    <channel>
        <title>Open to Debate – Debates</title>
        <link>https://opentodebate.org</link>
        <description>Debates with related research and news</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 03:03:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
        <item>
            <title>Silicon Valley Has Lost Its Soul</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/silicon-valley-has-lost-its-soul</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10149</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> November 11, 2018</p>
<p>Silicon Valley once promised to solve many of the world’s problems with a technological revolution. But now, the tech hub is the center of much scrutiny, and for many, that scrutiny is warranted. From privacy violations to flawed business models to a lack of diversity and representation, Silicon Valley has seemingly betrayed its idealism. And though technological progress has notably enriched a few, Silicon Valley has failed to deliver its promise to all. Has the prioritization of profits and conformity of thought corrupted its original “do good” agenda? Proponents argue no: Silicon Valley’s critics are simply overreacting. After all, it is still the center of innovation, and the tech giants have revolutionized the way we think, shop, communicate, and experience our lives for the better. Do big tech’s detractors simply expect too much from lucrative corporations? Or has Silicon Valley lost its soul?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/99qtl4tD-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/99qtl4tD-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Noam Cohen</strong><br>Noam Cohen is a journalist and the author of "The Know-It-Alls: The Rise of Silicon Valley as a Political Powerhouse and Social Wrecking Ball." From 2007 to 2013, he wrote the New York Times' "Link By Link" column, which covered the influence of digital technologies on global culture and the economy, including some of the Times’ earliest coverage of Wikipedia, Bitcoin, and Twitter. Since then, Cohen’s op-eds in the Times have exposed the ties between Silicon Valley’s disruptive values and Donald Trump’s candidacy and election.</p>
<p><strong>Dipayan Ghosh</strong><br>Dipayan Ghosh is the Pozen Fellow at the Harvard Kennedy School's Shorenstein Center, where he works on digital privacy, artificial intelligence, and civil rights. He previously worked on global privacy and public policy issues at Facebook, where he led strategic efforts to address privacy and security. Prior to that, Ghosh was a technology and economic policy adviser in the Obama White House. He served across the Office of Science and Technology Policy and the National Economic Council, where he worked on issues concerning big data’s impact on consumer privacy and the digital economy. He received a Ph.D. in electrical engineering and computer science at Cornell University.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Leslie Berlin</strong><br>Leslie Berlin is a historian for the Silicon Valley Archives at Stanford University and the author, most recently, of "Troublemakers: Silicon Valley’s Coming of Age." She has been a fellow at the Center for Advanced Studies in the Behavioral Sciences and served on the advisory committee of the Lemelson Center for the Study of Invention and Innovation at the Smithsonian’s National Museum of American History. Leslie has been a "Prototype" columnist for the New York Times and has commented on Silicon Valley for the Wall Street Journal, NPR, PBS, the BBC, The Atlantic, and Wired, among other outlets.</p>
<p><strong>Joshua McKenty</strong><br>Joshua McKenty is vice president of the systems advisory group at Pivotal, where he works with Fortune 100 customers who seek to transition to a cloud-native architecture. An entrepreneur and technologist, he is the co-founder of OpenStack and Piston (acquired by Cisco) and was the founding chief architect of NASA Nebula, the federal government’s first cloud computing platform. He was the team lead for the development of Netscape 8 as well as AOL’s IE AIM toolbar and Joint CTO at Mercurial Communications. More recently, McKenty led the IT efforts and successful first release of OpenQuake, an open-source software application allowing users to compute seismic hazards, seismic risks, and the socio-economic impact of earthquakes.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Silicon Valley Has Lost Its Soul</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Algorithms & Tech Addiction</u></p>
<p><u>Regulation</u></p>
<p><u>Silicon Valley Labor Movement</u></p>
<p><u>American Jobs & Silicon Valley</u></p>
<p><u>Global Perspectives</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> November 11, 2018</p>
<p>Silicon Valley once promised to solve many of the world’s problems with a technological revolution. But now, the tech hub is the center of much scrutiny, and for many, that scrutiny is warranted. From privacy violations to flawed business models to a lack of diversity and representation, Silicon Valley has seemingly betrayed its idealism. And though technological progress has notably enriched a few, Silicon Valley has failed to deliver its promise to all. Has the prioritization of profits and conformity of thought corrupted its original “do good” agenda? Proponents argue no: Silicon Valley’s critics are simply overreacting. After all, it is still the center of innovation, and the tech giants have revolutionized the way we think, shop, communicate, and experience our lives for the better. Do big tech’s detractors simply expect too much from lucrative corporations? Or has Silicon Valley lost its soul?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/99qtl4tD-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/99qtl4tD-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Noam Cohen</strong><br>Noam Cohen is a journalist and the author of "The Know-It-Alls: The Rise of Silicon Valley as a Political Powerhouse and Social Wrecking Ball." From 2007 to 2013, he wrote the New York Times' "Link By Link" column, which covered the influence of digital technologies on global culture and the economy, including some of the Times’ earliest coverage of Wikipedia, Bitcoin, and Twitter. Since then, Cohen’s op-eds in the Times have exposed the ties between Silicon Valley’s disruptive values and Donald Trump’s candidacy and election.</p>
<p><strong>Dipayan Ghosh</strong><br>Dipayan Ghosh is the Pozen Fellow at the Harvard Kennedy School's Shorenstein Center, where he works on digital privacy, artificial intelligence, and civil rights. He previously worked on global privacy and public policy issues at Facebook, where he led strategic efforts to address privacy and security. Prior to that, Ghosh was a technology and economic policy adviser in the Obama White House. He served across the Office of Science and Technology Policy and the National Economic Council, where he worked on issues concerning big data’s impact on consumer privacy and the digital economy. He received a Ph.D. in electrical engineering and computer science at Cornell University.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Leslie Berlin</strong><br>Leslie Berlin is a historian for the Silicon Valley Archives at Stanford University and the author, most recently, of "Troublemakers: Silicon Valley’s Coming of Age." She has been a fellow at the Center for Advanced Studies in the Behavioral Sciences and served on the advisory committee of the Lemelson Center for the Study of Invention and Innovation at the Smithsonian’s National Museum of American History. Leslie has been a "Prototype" columnist for the New York Times and has commented on Silicon Valley for the Wall Street Journal, NPR, PBS, the BBC, The Atlantic, and Wired, among other outlets.</p>
<p><strong>Joshua McKenty</strong><br>Joshua McKenty is vice president of the systems advisory group at Pivotal, where he works with Fortune 100 customers who seek to transition to a cloud-native architecture. An entrepreneur and technologist, he is the co-founder of OpenStack and Piston (acquired by Cisco) and was the founding chief architect of NASA Nebula, the federal government’s first cloud computing platform. He was the team lead for the development of Netscape 8 as well as AOL’s IE AIM toolbar and Joint CTO at Mercurial Communications. More recently, McKenty led the IT efforts and successful first release of OpenQuake, an open-source software application allowing users to compute seismic hazards, seismic risks, and the socio-economic impact of earthquakes.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Silicon Valley Has Lost Its Soul</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Algorithms & Tech Addiction</u></p>
<p><u>Regulation</u></p>
<p><u>Silicon Valley Labor Movement</u></p>
<p><u>American Jobs & Silicon Valley</u></p>
<p><u>Global Perspectives</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Trump Is Bad for Comedy</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/trump-bad-comedy</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10361</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> November 01, 2018</p>
<p>From the opening skit on “Saturday Night Live” to “The Late Show with Stephen Colbert” to the pages of The Onion, President Trump has become the face of comedy. Some comedians and writers argue that in the Trump era, satire has become more challenging and jokes have become cheap.  Trump, according to his critics, has normalized the absurd and the nature of political satire in a post-truth world. But others disagree; they argue that the president serves up comedy-gold every day, making their jobs – and the laughs they seek to elicit – easier than ever before. And, they argue, comedy is much more “woke” than it used to be, with late-night hosts and comedians playing a pivotal role in the fight for social justice. Is the president killing comedy? Or is he making the funny business ever more relevant?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/uxPTKusN-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/uxPTKusN-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>P.J. O'Rourke</strong><br>P. J. O’Rourke is a leading political satirist and editor-in-chief of the web magazine American Consequences. He has written nineteen books on subjects as diverse as politics, cars, etiquette, and economics, including his most recent book “None of My Business,” as well as “Parliament of Whores,” and “Give War a Chance,” which both reached number one on the New York Times best-seller list. He is a contributing editor at the Weekly Standard, a research fellow at the Cato Institute, and a regular panelist on NPR’s “Wait Wait … Don’t Tell Me.”</p>
<p><strong>Sara Schaefer</strong><br><p class="xmsonormal">Sara Schaefer is a critically acclaimed stand-up comedian, writer, and producer who has won two Emmy awards and a Webby award for her work on “Late Night with Jimmy Fallon.” She has written for Ed Helms’s Comedy Central special, “The Fake News with Ted Nelms,” and co-hosted, with comedian Nikki Glaser, the MTV show “Nikki & Sara Live.” Schaefer has been named one of New York Magazine’s “10 Comedians to Watch” and one of HuffPost’s “53 Favorite Female Comedians.”</p></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Kurt Andersen</strong><br>Kurt Andersen is the best-selling author of three critically acclaimed novels. His non-fiction books include, most recently, "Fantasyland: How America Went Haywire: A 500-Year History." He is the co-author, with Alec Baldwin, of "You Can’t Spell America Without Me," a fictional Trump memoir. Andersen is also the host and co-creator of "Studio 360," the Peabody Award-winning public radio show. Previously, he co-founded Spy magazine, a monthly satirical publication that frequently featured Donald Trump.</p>
<p><strong>Billy Kimball</strong><br>Billy Kimball is an Emmy award-winning writer and co-executive producer for the hit HBO series “Veep” starring Julia Louis-Dreyfus. He has also written nine episodes of "The Simpsons" and wrote the Academy Awards in 2016 and 2017.  In 1992, he executive produced more than 40 hours of live coverage of that year's presidential election for Comedy Central under the rubric "Indecision '92."</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Tom Ginsburg Debates Whether Trump Should Be Indicted on Intelligence Squared / Open to Debate Podcast</strong> <small>2023-02-07 23:01:46</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Should Trump Be Indicted?</p>
<p>After a series of prime-time hearings from the January 6th Committee and hundreds of charges against individuals who participated in the events of that day, the Department of Justice faces a complex political and legal question: Should it charge Donald Trump with federal crimes? Those calling on Attorney General Merrick Garland to act argue that no person is above the law and that the Committee's investigations have unearthed more than enough evidence to bring a variety of charges against the former president. But still, others warn that indicting a former president who has signaled interest in returning to the campaign trail in 2024 and who enjoys considerable support in the Republican party will even further fraction the nation's political divisions. Would indicting President Trump set a dangerous precedent and deepen political hostility in the run-up to a major presidential election? Or would failing to indict him prove even worse?</p>
<p>Read more at Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. (http://opentodebate.org)</p></div>
<div><strong>Open to Debate Podcast: Should Trump Be Indicted?</strong> <small>2023-02-07 23:06:48</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>There are many issues in our lives where neutral opinions are replaced with hard-line views. Should the toilet paper roll be over or under when placed on the holder? Should ketchup be used as a condiment for breakfast, or is it strictly for french fries and burgers? Is there a place for a mullet in polite society?</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Trump Is Bad for Comedy</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Conservative Comedy</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>A Comedy Boom? Or Bust?</u></p>
<p><u>Late-Night Comedy & Politics</u></p>
<p><u>Comedy Against Trump</u></p>
<p><u>Comedy's Impact</u></p>
<p><u>Clapter</u></p>
<p><u>Saturday Night Live in the Trump Era</u></p>
<p><u>Comedians Respond To Trump</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> November 01, 2018</p>
<p>From the opening skit on “Saturday Night Live” to “The Late Show with Stephen Colbert” to the pages of The Onion, President Trump has become the face of comedy. Some comedians and writers argue that in the Trump era, satire has become more challenging and jokes have become cheap.  Trump, according to his critics, has normalized the absurd and the nature of political satire in a post-truth world. But others disagree; they argue that the president serves up comedy-gold every day, making their jobs – and the laughs they seek to elicit – easier than ever before. And, they argue, comedy is much more “woke” than it used to be, with late-night hosts and comedians playing a pivotal role in the fight for social justice. Is the president killing comedy? Or is he making the funny business ever more relevant?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/uxPTKusN-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/uxPTKusN-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>P.J. O'Rourke</strong><br>P. J. O’Rourke is a leading political satirist and editor-in-chief of the web magazine American Consequences. He has written nineteen books on subjects as diverse as politics, cars, etiquette, and economics, including his most recent book “None of My Business,” as well as “Parliament of Whores,” and “Give War a Chance,” which both reached number one on the New York Times best-seller list. He is a contributing editor at the Weekly Standard, a research fellow at the Cato Institute, and a regular panelist on NPR’s “Wait Wait … Don’t Tell Me.”</p>
<p><strong>Sara Schaefer</strong><br><p class="xmsonormal">Sara Schaefer is a critically acclaimed stand-up comedian, writer, and producer who has won two Emmy awards and a Webby award for her work on “Late Night with Jimmy Fallon.” She has written for Ed Helms’s Comedy Central special, “The Fake News with Ted Nelms,” and co-hosted, with comedian Nikki Glaser, the MTV show “Nikki & Sara Live.” Schaefer has been named one of New York Magazine’s “10 Comedians to Watch” and one of HuffPost’s “53 Favorite Female Comedians.”</p></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Kurt Andersen</strong><br>Kurt Andersen is the best-selling author of three critically acclaimed novels. His non-fiction books include, most recently, "Fantasyland: How America Went Haywire: A 500-Year History." He is the co-author, with Alec Baldwin, of "You Can’t Spell America Without Me," a fictional Trump memoir. Andersen is also the host and co-creator of "Studio 360," the Peabody Award-winning public radio show. Previously, he co-founded Spy magazine, a monthly satirical publication that frequently featured Donald Trump.</p>
<p><strong>Billy Kimball</strong><br>Billy Kimball is an Emmy award-winning writer and co-executive producer for the hit HBO series “Veep” starring Julia Louis-Dreyfus. He has also written nine episodes of "The Simpsons" and wrote the Academy Awards in 2016 and 2017.  In 1992, he executive produced more than 40 hours of live coverage of that year's presidential election for Comedy Central under the rubric "Indecision '92."</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Tom Ginsburg Debates Whether Trump Should Be Indicted on Intelligence Squared / Open to Debate Podcast</strong> <small>2023-02-07 23:01:46</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Should Trump Be Indicted?</p>
<p>After a series of prime-time hearings from the January 6th Committee and hundreds of charges against individuals who participated in the events of that day, the Department of Justice faces a complex political and legal question: Should it charge Donald Trump with federal crimes? Those calling on Attorney General Merrick Garland to act argue that no person is above the law and that the Committee's investigations have unearthed more than enough evidence to bring a variety of charges against the former president. But still, others warn that indicting a former president who has signaled interest in returning to the campaign trail in 2024 and who enjoys considerable support in the Republican party will even further fraction the nation's political divisions. Would indicting President Trump set a dangerous precedent and deepen political hostility in the run-up to a major presidential election? Or would failing to indict him prove even worse?</p>
<p>Read more at Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. (http://opentodebate.org)</p></div>
<div><strong>Open to Debate Podcast: Should Trump Be Indicted?</strong> <small>2023-02-07 23:06:48</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>There are many issues in our lives where neutral opinions are replaced with hard-line views. Should the toilet paper roll be over or under when placed on the holder? Should ketchup be used as a condiment for breakfast, or is it strictly for french fries and burgers? Is there a place for a mullet in polite society?</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Trump Is Bad for Comedy</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Conservative Comedy</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>A Comedy Boom? Or Bust?</u></p>
<p><u>Late-Night Comedy & Politics</u></p>
<p><u>Comedy Against Trump</u></p>
<p><u>Comedy's Impact</u></p>
<p><u>Clapter</u></p>
<p><u>Saturday Night Live in the Trump Era</u></p>
<p><u>Comedians Respond To Trump</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Progressive Populism Will Save the Democratic Party</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/progressive-populism-will-save-democratic-party</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10390</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> October 11, 2018</p>
<p>As Democratic leaders and strategists gear up for the 2018 and 2020 elections, the party stands at a crossroads. For progressive populists, the path forward is clear: Democrats must get back in touch with the party’s working-class roots by championing a specific set of policies, including Medicare for all, free public college tuition, a guaranteed federal jobs program, and housing as a human right. They say this strategy is key to winning back disillusioned working-class voters and to regaining power in Washington and beyond. But others view this as a dangerous path. They argue that a handful of high-profile progressive wins have been overhyped by the media and, rather than make promises that may be impossible to execute in this political climate, Democrats should champion centrist, economically viable policies that will win elections and solidify the base. How can the Democratic Party, out of power and outnumbered in Washington D.C. and state capitals across the nation, bring itself out of the political wilderness?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/gUDnhLhI-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/gUDnhLhI-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Karine Jean-Pierre</strong><br><p class="xmsonormal">Karine Jean-Pierre is the national spokesperson and senior adviser for <a href="https://front.moveon.org/">MoveOn.org</a>, a progressive public policy advocacy group and political action committee that raises millions of dollars for progressive candidates. Jean-Pierre’s professional experience has ranged from presidential campaigns to grassroots activism, local politics, and working in the White House. She previously served as the deputy campaign manager for Martin O’Malley for President and the campaign manager for the ACLU's Reproductive Freedom Initiative. She is a frequent political commentator and lecturer at Columbia University.</p></p>
<p><strong>Jeff Weaver</strong><br><p class="xmsonormal">Jeff Weaver is a senior political adviser to Senator Bernie Sanders and was the campaign manager for Sanders’s 2016 presidential campaign. After the 2016 election, he served as the president of Our Revolution, a progressive political action organization established to continue Sanders’s movement, until June of 2017. A long-trusted adviser to Sanders, Weaver is the author of the new book, "How Bernie Won: Inside the Revolution That’s Taking Back Our Country - And Where We Go From Here."</p>
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://ballotpedia.org/Jeff_Weaver">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Jonathan Cowan</strong><br><p class="xmsonormal">Jonathan Cowan is the co-founder and president of Third Way, a leading public policy think tank and prominent voice in center-left debates in America. Cowan has over 25 years of experience at senior levels of politics and government, including in Congress and as chief of staff of the Department of Housing and Urban Development during the Clinton administration. Cowan has served as a visiting fellow at Harvard’s Institute of Politics and is frequently cited as a policy and political expert in national outlets.</p>
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.thirdway.org/about/leadership/jonathan-cowan">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Steven Rattner</strong><br>Steven Rattner is the chairman and chief executive officer of Willett Advisors LLC, the investment arm for former New York Mayor Michael R. Bloomberg’s personal and philanthropic assets. In addition, he serves as an economic analyst for MSNBC and is a contributing writer to the New York Times op-ed page. Rattner previously served as counselor to the Secretary of the Treasury and led the Obama administration’s successful effort to restructure the automobile industry, which he chronicled in his book, “Overhaul: An Insider’s Account of the Obama Administration’s Emergency Rescue of the Auto Industry.”</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Progressive Populism Will Save the Democratic Party</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Progressive Populist Candidates</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Public Opinion, Data & Polls</u></p>
<p><u>Medicare for All & Single-Payer</u></p>
<p><u>Free Public College Tuition</u></p>
<p><u>Guaranteed Federal Jobs Program</u></p>
<p><u>Abolish ICE</u></p>
<p><u>Housing as a Human Right</u></p>
<p><u>Recent Legislation</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> October 11, 2018</p>
<p>As Democratic leaders and strategists gear up for the 2018 and 2020 elections, the party stands at a crossroads. For progressive populists, the path forward is clear: Democrats must get back in touch with the party’s working-class roots by championing a specific set of policies, including Medicare for all, free public college tuition, a guaranteed federal jobs program, and housing as a human right. They say this strategy is key to winning back disillusioned working-class voters and to regaining power in Washington and beyond. But others view this as a dangerous path. They argue that a handful of high-profile progressive wins have been overhyped by the media and, rather than make promises that may be impossible to execute in this political climate, Democrats should champion centrist, economically viable policies that will win elections and solidify the base. How can the Democratic Party, out of power and outnumbered in Washington D.C. and state capitals across the nation, bring itself out of the political wilderness?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/gUDnhLhI-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/gUDnhLhI-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Karine Jean-Pierre</strong><br><p class="xmsonormal">Karine Jean-Pierre is the national spokesperson and senior adviser for <a href="https://front.moveon.org/">MoveOn.org</a>, a progressive public policy advocacy group and political action committee that raises millions of dollars for progressive candidates. Jean-Pierre’s professional experience has ranged from presidential campaigns to grassroots activism, local politics, and working in the White House. She previously served as the deputy campaign manager for Martin O’Malley for President and the campaign manager for the ACLU's Reproductive Freedom Initiative. She is a frequent political commentator and lecturer at Columbia University.</p></p>
<p><strong>Jeff Weaver</strong><br><p class="xmsonormal">Jeff Weaver is a senior political adviser to Senator Bernie Sanders and was the campaign manager for Sanders’s 2016 presidential campaign. After the 2016 election, he served as the president of Our Revolution, a progressive political action organization established to continue Sanders’s movement, until June of 2017. A long-trusted adviser to Sanders, Weaver is the author of the new book, "How Bernie Won: Inside the Revolution That’s Taking Back Our Country - And Where We Go From Here."</p>
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://ballotpedia.org/Jeff_Weaver">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Jonathan Cowan</strong><br><p class="xmsonormal">Jonathan Cowan is the co-founder and president of Third Way, a leading public policy think tank and prominent voice in center-left debates in America. Cowan has over 25 years of experience at senior levels of politics and government, including in Congress and as chief of staff of the Department of Housing and Urban Development during the Clinton administration. Cowan has served as a visiting fellow at Harvard’s Institute of Politics and is frequently cited as a policy and political expert in national outlets.</p>
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.thirdway.org/about/leadership/jonathan-cowan">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Steven Rattner</strong><br>Steven Rattner is the chairman and chief executive officer of Willett Advisors LLC, the investment arm for former New York Mayor Michael R. Bloomberg’s personal and philanthropic assets. In addition, he serves as an economic analyst for MSNBC and is a contributing writer to the New York Times op-ed page. Rattner previously served as counselor to the Secretary of the Treasury and led the Obama administration’s successful effort to restructure the automobile industry, which he chronicled in his book, “Overhaul: An Insider’s Account of the Obama Administration’s Emergency Rescue of the Auto Industry.”</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Progressive Populism Will Save the Democratic Party</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Progressive Populist Candidates</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Public Opinion, Data & Polls</u></p>
<p><u>Medicare for All & Single-Payer</u></p>
<p><u>Free Public College Tuition</u></p>
<p><u>Guaranteed Federal Jobs Program</u></p>
<p><u>Abolish ICE</u></p>
<p><u>Housing as a Human Right</u></p>
<p><u>Recent Legislation</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Retail Alliances – Not Washington – Will Save the U.S. Health Care System</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/retail-alliances-not-washington-will-save-us-health-care-system</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10137</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> September 26, 2018</p>
<p>Last year, Intelligence Squared U.S. and the Mayo Clinic brought to the stage a bold inquiry about whether health care in the United States is terminally broken. And this year, we’re picking up where that discussion left off, against the backdrop of corporate behemoths announcing mergers that, they say, are sure to shake up health care – from the Amazon, Berkshire Hathaway, and JPMorgan Chase venture, to the CVS-Aetna deal, to the Humana-Walgreens partnership, and more. But while these superpower alliances are making a splash in the headlines, will they actually be able to disrupt, and save, U.S. health care? Proponents argue that the bargaining power and data competencies of these retailers will squeeze middlemen out of an inefficient supply chain and bring more transparency to health care pricing. But others argue that the promise of these novel efforts is overstated or misguided, particularly because U.S. health care is so complex and deeply rooted. Will consumer-focused models and employer-led initiatives lead to better and less expensive outcomes?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/ISc6dxul-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/ISc6dxul-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rajaie Batniji</strong><br>Dr. Rajaie Batniji is a physician, political economist, and the co-founder and chief health officer of Collective Health, an organization that leads the employer-driven health care economy and aims to create a more efficient health care experience. In his position, he oversees partnerships with health care networks and providers, analytics teams, and Collective Health’s employee health management programs. Dr. Batniji is also a clinical assistant professor of medicine at the Stanford University School of Medicine.</p>
<p><strong>W. Gregg Slager</strong><br>W. Gregg Slager is a senior partner at the leading firm Ernst & Young and a founder of the company's global health sector. He currently serves as the EY global health transaction advisory services leader, where he works with organizations from multiple sectors to manage health care costs, improve efficiency, and facilitate better health outcomes. Slager frequently speaks and writes about health care mergers and acquisitions and is a private investor in wellness- and technology-focused ventures.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Lisa Bielamowicz</strong><br>Dr. Lisa Bielamowicz is the co-founder and president of Gist Healthcare. Her work combines national-level insight with a deep understanding of local market dynamics and system strength. Prior to founding Gist, Dr. Bielamowicz was the chief medical officer and senior vice president of the Advisory Board Company, where she led the firm’s strategy and clinical research for over a decade. As a physician, Dr. Bielamowicz brings a clinical lens to her work and has a deep understanding of the dynamics of physician practice.</p>
<p><strong>Rosemarie Day</strong><br>Rosemarie Day is the founder and CEO of Day Health Strategies. She has over 25 years of experience in the public, private, and non-profit sectors, including 16 years of leadership experience in state government. Day served as the founding deputy director and chief operating officer of the Health Connector in Massachusetts, where she played a significant role in launching the first state-run health insurance exchange in the United States. She also served as the chief operating officer for the Massachusetts Medicaid program, which covered more than one million members.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Retail Alliances - Not Washington - Will Save the U.S. Health Care System</em></p>
<p><u>Background: General</u></p>
<p><u>Background: Amazon, Berkshire Hathaway and JPMorgan Chase</u></p>
<p><u>Changing Patient-Doctor Relationships</u></p>
<p><u>Big Data and Health Care</u></p>
<p><u>Drug Pricing</u></p>
<p><u>Background: Amazon and PillPack</u></p>
<p><u>Background: CVS-Aetna</u></p>
<p><u>Background: Walmart-Humana</u></p>
<p><u>Background: Walgreens-Humana</u></p>
<p><u>Background: Apple</u></p>
<p><u>Background: Uber</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> September 26, 2018</p>
<p>Last year, Intelligence Squared U.S. and the Mayo Clinic brought to the stage a bold inquiry about whether health care in the United States is terminally broken. And this year, we’re picking up where that discussion left off, against the backdrop of corporate behemoths announcing mergers that, they say, are sure to shake up health care – from the Amazon, Berkshire Hathaway, and JPMorgan Chase venture, to the CVS-Aetna deal, to the Humana-Walgreens partnership, and more. But while these superpower alliances are making a splash in the headlines, will they actually be able to disrupt, and save, U.S. health care? Proponents argue that the bargaining power and data competencies of these retailers will squeeze middlemen out of an inefficient supply chain and bring more transparency to health care pricing. But others argue that the promise of these novel efforts is overstated or misguided, particularly because U.S. health care is so complex and deeply rooted. Will consumer-focused models and employer-led initiatives lead to better and less expensive outcomes?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/ISc6dxul-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/ISc6dxul-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rajaie Batniji</strong><br>Dr. Rajaie Batniji is a physician, political economist, and the co-founder and chief health officer of Collective Health, an organization that leads the employer-driven health care economy and aims to create a more efficient health care experience. In his position, he oversees partnerships with health care networks and providers, analytics teams, and Collective Health’s employee health management programs. Dr. Batniji is also a clinical assistant professor of medicine at the Stanford University School of Medicine.</p>
<p><strong>W. Gregg Slager</strong><br>W. Gregg Slager is a senior partner at the leading firm Ernst & Young and a founder of the company's global health sector. He currently serves as the EY global health transaction advisory services leader, where he works with organizations from multiple sectors to manage health care costs, improve efficiency, and facilitate better health outcomes. Slager frequently speaks and writes about health care mergers and acquisitions and is a private investor in wellness- and technology-focused ventures.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Lisa Bielamowicz</strong><br>Dr. Lisa Bielamowicz is the co-founder and president of Gist Healthcare. Her work combines national-level insight with a deep understanding of local market dynamics and system strength. Prior to founding Gist, Dr. Bielamowicz was the chief medical officer and senior vice president of the Advisory Board Company, where she led the firm’s strategy and clinical research for over a decade. As a physician, Dr. Bielamowicz brings a clinical lens to her work and has a deep understanding of the dynamics of physician practice.</p>
<p><strong>Rosemarie Day</strong><br>Rosemarie Day is the founder and CEO of Day Health Strategies. She has over 25 years of experience in the public, private, and non-profit sectors, including 16 years of leadership experience in state government. Day served as the founding deputy director and chief operating officer of the Health Connector in Massachusetts, where she played a significant role in launching the first state-run health insurance exchange in the United States. She also served as the chief operating officer for the Massachusetts Medicaid program, which covered more than one million members.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Retail Alliances - Not Washington - Will Save the U.S. Health Care System</em></p>
<p><u>Background: General</u></p>
<p><u>Background: Amazon, Berkshire Hathaway and JPMorgan Chase</u></p>
<p><u>Changing Patient-Doctor Relationships</u></p>
<p><u>Big Data and Health Care</u></p>
<p><u>Drug Pricing</u></p>
<p><u>Background: Amazon and PillPack</u></p>
<p><u>Background: CVS-Aetna</u></p>
<p><u>Background: Walmart-Humana</u></p>
<p><u>Background: Walgreens-Humana</u></p>
<p><u>Background: Apple</u></p>
<p><u>Background: Uber</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Unresolved: U.S. National Security</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/unresolved-us-national-security</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10302</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> September 20, 2018</p>
<p>For the United States, tensions are rising with both allies and adversaries. Rogue states are racing to master new technologies and create weapons of mass destruction. And faith in international institutions is seemingly deteriorating. What does this all mean for U.S. national security?
Staged in our "unresolved" format, five esteemed foreign policy thought leaders will argue for or against a number of motions revolving around some of America’s most pressing national security issues, including: Is NATO no longer fit for purpose? Is the Russia threat overblown? And is it time to take a hard line on Iran?</p>
<p><strong>Unresolved Questions:</strong></p>
<p>• Motion #1: It’s Time To Take a Hard Line on Iran</p>
<p>• Motion #2: NATO Is No Longer Fit for Purpose</p>
<p>• Motion #3: The Russia Threat Is Overblown</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/nHwrVGM5-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/nHwrVGM5-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Derek Chollet</strong><br>Derek Chollet is a veteran of the Obama administration, where he served six years in senior positions at the White House, State Department, and Pentagon. Most recently, he was the assistant secretary of defense for international security affairs. In that role, Chollet managed U.S. defense policy toward NATO, Europe, and the Middle East. Currently the executive vice president and senior adviser for security and defense policy at the German Marshall Fund of the United States, he is the author of "The Long Game: How Obama Defied Washington and Redefined America’s Role in the World."</p>
<p><strong>Stephen F. Cohen</strong><br>Stephen F. Cohen is among the most distinguished scholars of Russia in the United States and is internationally recognized for his academic works on Russian and Soviet political history since 1917. He is professor emeritus of Russian studies, history, and politics at New York University and Princeton University and a contributing editor at The Nation. Also an expert on Russian-American relations, Cohen is the author of several acclaimed books, most recently “Soviet Fates and Lost Alternatives: From Stalinism to the New Cold War.” His forthcoming book is “War With Russia? A Dissenting Narrative — From Putin and Ukraine to Trump and Russiagate.”</p>
<p><strong>Reuel Marc Gerecht</strong><br>Reuel Marc Gerecht is a former case officer for the CIA, where he served as a Middle Eastern targets officer with the CIA's directorate of operations. He is a senior fellow at the Foundation for Defense of Democracies, a non-partisan organization centered on national security, where he focuses on Iran, sanctions, terrorism, and the Middle East. He is the author of "Know Thy Enemy: A Spy’s Journey into Revolutionary Iran" and "The Islamic Paradox: Shiite Clerics, Sunni Fundamentalists, and the Coming of Arab Democracy," among others.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John J. Mearsheimer</strong><br><b></b><span data-contrast="none">John Mearsheimer is a political scientist and the R. Wendell Harrison Distinguished Service Professor in the Political Science Department at the University of Chicago. Before joining the University of Chicago, he was an officer in the U.S. Air Force, a research fellow at the Brookings Institution, and a post-doctoral fellow at Harvard University’s Center for International Affairs. He was also the Whitney H. Shepardson Fellow at the Council on Foreign Relations during the 1998-1999 academic year. Mearsheimer is the author of seven books, including </span><span data-contrast="auto">“Conventional Deterrence”, “The Tragedy of Great Power Politics”, the </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">New York Times</span></i><span data-contrast="auto"> best-seller “The Israel Lobby and U.S. Foreign Policy” (with Stephen M. Walt), and his most recent book “How States Think: The Rationality of Foreign Policy” (with Sebastian Rosato). He has also written many articles that have appeared in academic journals like </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">International Security</span></i><span data-contrast="auto">, and for newspapers and magazines including </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">Foreign Affairs</span></i><span data-contrast="auto">, </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">London Review of Books</span></i><span data-contrast="auto"> </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">The</span></i><span data-contrast="auto"> </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">New York Times,</span></i><span data-contrast="auto"> and the </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">Financial Times</span></i><span data-contrast="auto">, among other publications. He is the recipient of the James Madison Award from the American Political Science Association, received honorary doctorates from universities in China, Greece, and Romania, and was elected to the American Academy of Arts and Sciences.</span></p>
<p><strong>Kori Schake</strong><br>Kori Schake is a senior fellow and the director of foreign and defense policy studies at the American Enterprise Institute (AEI). Dr. Schake is the former deputy director-general of the International Institute for Strategic Studies in London. She has worked at the U.S. State Department, the U.S. Department of Defense, and the National Security Council at the White House. Author of five books, most recently "America vs. the West: Can the Liberal World Order Be Preserved?" Dr. Schake is widely published in policy journals and the popular press. She has a doctorate in government and politics from the University of Maryland.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Unresolved: U.S. National Security</em></p>
<p><u>Motion #1: It’s Time To Take a Hard Line on Iran</u></p>
<p><u>Motion #2: NATO Is No Longer Fit for Purpose</u></p>
<p><u>Motion #3: The Russia Threat Is Overblown</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> September 20, 2018</p>
<p>For the United States, tensions are rising with both allies and adversaries. Rogue states are racing to master new technologies and create weapons of mass destruction. And faith in international institutions is seemingly deteriorating. What does this all mean for U.S. national security?
Staged in our "unresolved" format, five esteemed foreign policy thought leaders will argue for or against a number of motions revolving around some of America’s most pressing national security issues, including: Is NATO no longer fit for purpose? Is the Russia threat overblown? And is it time to take a hard line on Iran?</p>
<p><strong>Unresolved Questions:</strong></p>
<p>• Motion #1: It’s Time To Take a Hard Line on Iran</p>
<p>• Motion #2: NATO Is No Longer Fit for Purpose</p>
<p>• Motion #3: The Russia Threat Is Overblown</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/nHwrVGM5-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/nHwrVGM5-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Derek Chollet</strong><br>Derek Chollet is a veteran of the Obama administration, where he served six years in senior positions at the White House, State Department, and Pentagon. Most recently, he was the assistant secretary of defense for international security affairs. In that role, Chollet managed U.S. defense policy toward NATO, Europe, and the Middle East. Currently the executive vice president and senior adviser for security and defense policy at the German Marshall Fund of the United States, he is the author of "The Long Game: How Obama Defied Washington and Redefined America’s Role in the World."</p>
<p><strong>Stephen F. Cohen</strong><br>Stephen F. Cohen is among the most distinguished scholars of Russia in the United States and is internationally recognized for his academic works on Russian and Soviet political history since 1917. He is professor emeritus of Russian studies, history, and politics at New York University and Princeton University and a contributing editor at The Nation. Also an expert on Russian-American relations, Cohen is the author of several acclaimed books, most recently “Soviet Fates and Lost Alternatives: From Stalinism to the New Cold War.” His forthcoming book is “War With Russia? A Dissenting Narrative — From Putin and Ukraine to Trump and Russiagate.”</p>
<p><strong>Reuel Marc Gerecht</strong><br>Reuel Marc Gerecht is a former case officer for the CIA, where he served as a Middle Eastern targets officer with the CIA's directorate of operations. He is a senior fellow at the Foundation for Defense of Democracies, a non-partisan organization centered on national security, where he focuses on Iran, sanctions, terrorism, and the Middle East. He is the author of "Know Thy Enemy: A Spy’s Journey into Revolutionary Iran" and "The Islamic Paradox: Shiite Clerics, Sunni Fundamentalists, and the Coming of Arab Democracy," among others.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John J. Mearsheimer</strong><br><b></b><span data-contrast="none">John Mearsheimer is a political scientist and the R. Wendell Harrison Distinguished Service Professor in the Political Science Department at the University of Chicago. Before joining the University of Chicago, he was an officer in the U.S. Air Force, a research fellow at the Brookings Institution, and a post-doctoral fellow at Harvard University’s Center for International Affairs. He was also the Whitney H. Shepardson Fellow at the Council on Foreign Relations during the 1998-1999 academic year. Mearsheimer is the author of seven books, including </span><span data-contrast="auto">“Conventional Deterrence”, “The Tragedy of Great Power Politics”, the </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">New York Times</span></i><span data-contrast="auto"> best-seller “The Israel Lobby and U.S. Foreign Policy” (with Stephen M. Walt), and his most recent book “How States Think: The Rationality of Foreign Policy” (with Sebastian Rosato). He has also written many articles that have appeared in academic journals like </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">International Security</span></i><span data-contrast="auto">, and for newspapers and magazines including </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">Foreign Affairs</span></i><span data-contrast="auto">, </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">London Review of Books</span></i><span data-contrast="auto"> </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">The</span></i><span data-contrast="auto"> </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">New York Times,</span></i><span data-contrast="auto"> and the </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">Financial Times</span></i><span data-contrast="auto">, among other publications. He is the recipient of the James Madison Award from the American Political Science Association, received honorary doctorates from universities in China, Greece, and Romania, and was elected to the American Academy of Arts and Sciences.</span></p>
<p><strong>Kori Schake</strong><br>Kori Schake is a senior fellow and the director of foreign and defense policy studies at the American Enterprise Institute (AEI). Dr. Schake is the former deputy director-general of the International Institute for Strategic Studies in London. She has worked at the U.S. State Department, the U.S. Department of Defense, and the National Security Council at the White House. Author of five books, most recently "America vs. the West: Can the Liberal World Order Be Preserved?" Dr. Schake is widely published in policy journals and the popular press. She has a doctorate in government and politics from the University of Maryland.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Unresolved: U.S. National Security</em></p>
<p><u>Motion #1: It’s Time To Take a Hard Line on Iran</u></p>
<p><u>Motion #2: NATO Is No Longer Fit for Purpose</u></p>
<p><u>Motion #3: The Russia Threat Is Overblown</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Globalization Has Undermined America&#x27;s Working Class</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/globalization-has-undermined-americas-working-class</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10131</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> June 28, 2018</p>
<p>Globalization ushered in an era of free trade, fluid borders, and unparalleled corporate profits. For its proponents, the global integration of states and their economies was a political and economic win that created a wealth of opportunities for workers and consumers around the world. But in the United States, jobs are disappearing. From construction zones to clerical offices to coal mines, the American working class is losing ground. Is globalization to blame? Did the push toward global integration leave our most vulnerable populations behind, making them the losers of this grand experiment? Or is globalization being used as a scapegoat for a wider range of failed public policies and unprecedented advances in technology?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/MYlwT4Kf-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/MYlwT4Kf-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Thea Lee</strong><br>Thea Lee is president of the Economic Policy Institute, a leading economic policy think tank. Before joining EPI, she was deputy chief of staff at the AFL-CIO, a voluntary federation of 56 national and international labor unions that represents 12.5 million working men and women. She has spent her career advocating on behalf of working families in national policy debates on issues such as wage inequality, workers’ rights, and fair trade. Lee is co-author of “The Field Guide to the Global Economy,” which analyzes the rapidly changing international economy.</p>
<p><strong>Jared Bernstein</strong><br>Jared Bernstein is a senior fellow at the Center on Budget and Policy Priorities. During the Obama administration, he served as Vice President Joe Biden’s chief economist and economic adviser, executive director of the White House Task Force on the Middle Class, and a member of President Obama's economic team. He is the author and co-author of numerous books including his latest book, "The Reconnection Agenda: Reuniting Growth and Prosperity."</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Jason Furman</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">Jason Furman is the Aetna Professor of the Practice of Economic Policy jointly at Harvard Kennedy School and the Department of Economics at Harvard University. He is also a nonresident senior fellow at the Peterson Institute for International Economics. Previously he served as a top economic adviser to President Obama, including serving as the 28th Chairman of the Council of Economic Advisers, acting as President Obama’s chief economist and a cabinet member. During this time, Furman played a major role in most of the major economic policies of the Obama Administration. Furman also served under President Clinton. Furman engages in public policy through research, writing, and teaching, focusing on U.S. and international macroeconomics, fiscal policy, labor markets, and competition policy. He is a member of numerous organizations, including the Council on Foreign Relations, the Group of Thirty, and the Economic Strategy Group. He also serves as a Trustee of the Russell Sage Foundation and the advisory boards for the Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, the Bund Summit, the Hamilton Project, and the Washington Center for Equitable Growth. In addition to articles in scholarly journals and periodicals, Furman is a regular contributor to the </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">W</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">all Street Journal</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0"> and </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">Project Syndicate</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0"> and the editor of two books on economic policy.</span></span></p>
<p><strong>James Manyika</strong><br>James Manyika is a senior partner at McKinsey & Company and the chairman and director of the McKinsey Global Institute, the firm’s business and economics research arm. He is co-author of "No Ordinary Disruption," which analyzes the transformation of the global economy, and has led McKinsey’s research initiatives on the digital economy, the future of work, and globalization. Manyika served on the U.S. Commerce Department’s Digital Economy Board of Advisers and was vice chair of the Global Development Council at the White House.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Globalization Has Undermined America's Working Class</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>President Trump's Tariffs</u></p>
<p><u>Offshoring & Outsourcing</u></p>
<p><u>Backlash to Globalization</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> June 28, 2018</p>
<p>Globalization ushered in an era of free trade, fluid borders, and unparalleled corporate profits. For its proponents, the global integration of states and their economies was a political and economic win that created a wealth of opportunities for workers and consumers around the world. But in the United States, jobs are disappearing. From construction zones to clerical offices to coal mines, the American working class is losing ground. Is globalization to blame? Did the push toward global integration leave our most vulnerable populations behind, making them the losers of this grand experiment? Or is globalization being used as a scapegoat for a wider range of failed public policies and unprecedented advances in technology?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/MYlwT4Kf-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/MYlwT4Kf-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Thea Lee</strong><br>Thea Lee is president of the Economic Policy Institute, a leading economic policy think tank. Before joining EPI, she was deputy chief of staff at the AFL-CIO, a voluntary federation of 56 national and international labor unions that represents 12.5 million working men and women. She has spent her career advocating on behalf of working families in national policy debates on issues such as wage inequality, workers’ rights, and fair trade. Lee is co-author of “The Field Guide to the Global Economy,” which analyzes the rapidly changing international economy.</p>
<p><strong>Jared Bernstein</strong><br>Jared Bernstein is a senior fellow at the Center on Budget and Policy Priorities. During the Obama administration, he served as Vice President Joe Biden’s chief economist and economic adviser, executive director of the White House Task Force on the Middle Class, and a member of President Obama's economic team. He is the author and co-author of numerous books including his latest book, "The Reconnection Agenda: Reuniting Growth and Prosperity."</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Jason Furman</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">Jason Furman is the Aetna Professor of the Practice of Economic Policy jointly at Harvard Kennedy School and the Department of Economics at Harvard University. He is also a nonresident senior fellow at the Peterson Institute for International Economics. Previously he served as a top economic adviser to President Obama, including serving as the 28th Chairman of the Council of Economic Advisers, acting as President Obama’s chief economist and a cabinet member. During this time, Furman played a major role in most of the major economic policies of the Obama Administration. Furman also served under President Clinton. Furman engages in public policy through research, writing, and teaching, focusing on U.S. and international macroeconomics, fiscal policy, labor markets, and competition policy. He is a member of numerous organizations, including the Council on Foreign Relations, the Group of Thirty, and the Economic Strategy Group. He also serves as a Trustee of the Russell Sage Foundation and the advisory boards for the Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, the Bund Summit, the Hamilton Project, and the Washington Center for Equitable Growth. In addition to articles in scholarly journals and periodicals, Furman is a regular contributor to the </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">W</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">all Street Journal</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0"> and </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">Project Syndicate</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0"> and the editor of two books on economic policy.</span></span></p>
<p><strong>James Manyika</strong><br>James Manyika is a senior partner at McKinsey & Company and the chairman and director of the McKinsey Global Institute, the firm’s business and economics research arm. He is co-author of "No Ordinary Disruption," which analyzes the transformation of the global economy, and has led McKinsey’s research initiatives on the digital economy, the future of work, and globalization. Manyika served on the U.S. Commerce Department’s Digital Economy Board of Advisers and was vice chair of the Global Development Council at the White House.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Globalization Has Undermined America's Working Class</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>President Trump's Tariffs</u></p>
<p><u>Offshoring & Outsourcing</u></p>
<p><u>Backlash to Globalization</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Is Social Media Good For Democracy?</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/social-media-good-democracy</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10159</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> June 26, 2018</p>
<p>By connecting people across the world for free, platforms like Twitter and Facebook set the stage for a promising digital revolution, providing tools that helped foster global friendships, break down long-standing barriers that kept people and ideas from being heard, and served as the ultimate democratizing force for information. Now, lawmakers in the U.S. and beyond are reeling with questions of how to prevent the spread of digital political propaganda and protect citizens’ personal privacy online. Critics argue that rather than uniting and informing, social media deepens social and political divisions and erodes trust in the democratic process. Will the power of social media yet be harnessed and used as an unprecedented force for good in the world? Or do systemic platform flaws pose an irreversible threat to the world’s democratic institutions?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/CajecmPc-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/CajecmPc-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Jeff Jarvis</strong><br>Jeff Jarvis is a national leader in the development of online news, blogging, and the investigation of new business models for news. He is director of the Tow-Knight Center for Entrepreneurial Journalism at the City University of New York and serves as an executive committee member for the News Integrity Initiative. Funded in part by Facebook and Mozilla, the initiative supports news literacy and journalistic efforts around the world. Jarvis is also the author of several books, including “Geeks Bearing Gifts” and “What Would Google Do?” He blogs about media and news at <a href="http://Buzzmachine.com">Buzzmachine.com</a> and cohosts the podcast <a href="https://twit.tv/shows/this-week-in-google">This Week in Google</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Emily Parker</strong><br>Emily Parker is the author of “Now I Know Who My Comrades Are: Voices From the Internet Underground,” which tells the stories of internet activists in China, Cuba, and Russia. Parker was chief strategy officer at Parlio, a Silicon Valley start-up that aimed to bring civility to social media. Previously she was a member of the policy planning staff at the U.S. Department of State, where she advised on internet freedom. Parker is a former staff writer and editor at the Wall Street Journal and a former editor at the New York Times. She is currently the co-founder of Longhash, a global blockchain start-up.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Franklin Foer</strong><br>Franklin Foer is a staff writer at The Atlantic and the former editor of The New Republic. He is the author of “World Without Mind: The Existential Threat of Big Tech,” which explores the influence of Amazon, Facebook, Apple, and Google on modern life, and was named one of the best books of the year by the New York Times.</p>
<p><strong>Roger McNamee</strong><br>Roger McNamee has spent 35 years investing in the technology industry. He is a co-founder of three firms: "Integral Capital Partners", "Silver Lake Partners", and "Elevation Partners." An early investor in Facebook, he served as a mentor to Mark Zuckerberg from 2006 to 2009. He is the author of “The New Normal,” a regular commentator on CNBC and MSNBC, and a touring musician. He holds four patents related to broadcasting live video to cell phones.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Is Elon Musk killing Twitter? How bankruptcy might not be the end</strong> <small>2023-02-02 18:59:19</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>A debate between an investor and a journalist looks into what is happening at the social media company</p>
<p>Last October, Elon Musk completed his move to acquire Twitter (https://interestingengineering.com/culture/elon-musk-completes-twitter-takeover) after a short legal brawl, but the joy of the move was short-lived. Having fired the top brass the same day, Musk moved on to firing more than half of Twitter’s staff, and bad news kept poring out of the San Francisco headquarters quite regularly.</p>
<p>As we enter the New Year, the situation hasn’t changed much, and Twitter continues to be in the news for all the wrong reasons, like not paying rent for its office spaces and employees being forced out of buildings by landlords, The New York Times reported (https://www.nytimes.com/2022/12/13/technology/elon-musk-twitter-shakeup.html?smid=tw-nytimes&smtyp=cur). The question that crosses one’s mind is if Musk is out to kill Twitter once and for all.</p>
<p>Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S.Intelligence Squared (http://opentodebate.org), a platform known for organizing debates, took up this question and set up a debate between Kara Swisher, the editor-at-large at New York Magazine, and Anthony Scaramucci, managing partner at Skybridge capital and former communications director at the White House.</p>
<p>Neither Swisher nor Scaramucci have a personal or professional relationship with Musk, even though they have met and interacted with the now Twitter CEO on multiple occasions.</p>
<p>Here's a look at various aspects of the effects Elon Musk's takeover has had on Twitter.</p>
<p>Active Users
Musk’s actions have allegedly led to a drop in usage among active users, who usually contribute a lot of content to the platform, and is forcing users to give competitors, like Mastodon, a try, Swisher said while stating that Musk's leadership was leading to Twitter's downfall.</p>
<p>Comparing it to a proverbial town square, Scaramucci argued that Twitter, since Musk’s takeover had more active users and was at the center of many important events, whether it was the FIFA World Cup or the FTX debacle.</p>
<p>Journalists could cover nuances of a story thanks to Twitter while people get updates about people they follow from the platform. Twitter Spaces turned out to be an effective medium and preferable over ClubHouse. When Musk himself joined Twitter Space, more than 100,000 people were in attendance listening and asking questions, Scaramucci said while defending that Musk wasn't killing Twitter.</p>
<p>Return of banned accounts
Swisher pointed out Musk-led Twitter has allowed 60,000 accounts previously suspended back on the platform to “improve the conversation”. Worse still, the decision to allow these users back seems to have been made single-handedly by Musk, instead of a council that was supposed to be set up.</p>
<p>Scaramucci argued that by bringing people back, Musk was giving them a platform to voice their opinions rather than shut them off. This way, he was bringing them back into the social contract. He added that when individuals speak, think and speak freely, it creates economic innovation.</p>
<p>Loss of revenue
Swisher strongly argued that Musk was indeed killing Twitter after his arrival blew off $5 billion in advertising revenues for the social media company, which was significant for income in the pre-Musk days. His plans of launching the paid subscription model of revenue generation hurt corporate clients more as users faked companies after paying $8 a month and got verified checks to their fake usernames.</p>
<p>Scaramucci added that large corporations were risk averse and did not want to advertise on Twitter due to what Musk was doing.</p>
<p>Twitter’s valuation drops
Swisher also pointed out a report that the Bank of America and Morgan Stanley who lent Musk money to finance his Twitter deal have now halved the Twitter debt on their books, which means the company’s equity has been wiped out in just two months after Musk has arrived at the helm of the affairs.</p>
<p>Scaramucci ceded that Twitter’s valuations were down but argued that the company was far from dead and could see a revival in the coming months and years. Instead with a more active user base, the company was more vital than ever.</p>
<p>Could Twitter go bankrupt?
Swisher pointed out that Musk first spoke about Twitter's potential bankruptcy (https://interestingengineering.com/culture/twitter-possible-bankruptcy-top-executives-leave). While it is likely that Musk, the world’s richest person, will not let it happen, he had many wealthy friends who could put money into the company if it came to that.</p>
<p>However, she warned that if the loan ended up on Wall Street, it could be bought by someone else, who would want Musk out before he could fix what he had broken at Twitter. She argued that although Twitter got a lot of attention from politicians and the media, it wasn’t a great business when compared to other social media outlets, and with Musk at the helm had turned into a lousy business.</p>
<p>Comparison with Tesla, SpaceX
Scaramucci’s faith in Elon Musk to revive Twitter comes from his other companies, Tesla and SpaceX, staring at bankruptcy in 2008. Back then, it was Musk’s leadership that steered them away to levels that made him one of the richest people in the world (https://interestingengineering.com/culture/elon-musk-just-got-36-billion-richer-in-a-single-day).</p>
<p>He said that Musk may have started on the wrong foot with Twitter trying to give away verified badges for a fee but, having realized his mistake, reversed his decision. In the long run, Scaramucci expects Musk to get things right at Twitter.</p>
<p>Swisher, however, argued that too much faith was being put into Musk’s ability because of his history. Musk was good at making cars and rockets, but that does not mean he will be good at media too.</p>
<p>Twitter being a media company puts him in a very different situation, and his ideas to ‘unlock its potential’ are retreads of what many orders have suggested in the past. In fact, Musk has been unable to execute them properly and has made the site more erratic as of now.</p>
<p>Swisher also referred to Steve Jobs as a true visionary who stayed in his lane and did great things. Musk, on the other hand, does not seem to have a clue about what he is up to.</p>
<p>Musk’s vision for Twitter
Scaramucci, an investor, had access to a Powerpoint presentation for Musk’s vision for Twitter, which said that he wants to broaden the social media base and make it more inclusive. Going forward, Musk wants Twitter to become a ‘super app’ much like WeChat, which is used in China by users for social media, making payments, and personal communication.</p>
<p>Swisher, however, said that ‘super apps’ have not worked in the U.S. before, and even the likes of Apple and Amazon have tried to do it and failed so far. It might be working in China, but the U.S. was a different market, and people would trust Amazon or Apple with their payments but not Twitter.</p>
<p>Moreover, people used different apps for different purposes, like Snapchat for communication and TikTok for entertainment. Like Facebook usage has dropped, Twitter under Musk is heading the same way.</p>
<p>Twitter: Unassailable or Obsolete?
Due to its ability to connect people to events happening globally, Scaramucci said, Twitter had found a niche for itself in the past 15 years of its existence and become an indispensable part of our daily lives. Even if Musk failed in his mission to turn the company around, he would leave, and someone else could steady the ship.</p>
<p>With Musk planning to ring in many changes in how Twitter looks and behaves, users could be worried if the sudden changes would keep the platform usable. Swisher thinks that if the user experience dips and people find it hard to use Twitter, then it is likely that competitors will make something easier to use, shifting the user base away.</p>
<p>Swisher was pessimistic that the company could survive the Elon storm and compared his management style to building a rocket while it was in flight. Worse still, his decisions were taking the rocket on a downward trajectory, and Musk was single-handedly making the decisions. Swisher would not be surprised if Twitter soon became part of the graveyard of internet companies such as AOL, AIM, Yahoo, and MySpace, which were great at one time but have become obsolete over the years.</p>
<p>Impact on Musk
The time Musk spends at Twitter also affects his other ventures, such as Tesla, Swisher argued. The EV-making company had seen a steep decline in its valuation (https://interestingengineering.com/culture/musk-lose-200-billion), with Twitter serving as a larger distraction for Musk, the CEO, than when he was just a prolific user of the platform.</p>
<p>The competition in the EV market has grown, and Tesla is ceding its market share, which took years to build, very rapidly. The mass firing of staff at Twitter is also resulting in class action lawsuits and which are likely to be the biggest ones in Musk’s life.</p>
<p>Scaramucci quoting Warren Buffett that a high-quality business can endure a bad management team or terrible decisions to set the tone of his defense is a strong indicator of what’s happening at Twitter.</p>
<p>The debate was published across various podcast platforms today.</p></div>
<div><strong>Swisher v. Scaramucci: Is Elon Musk Killing Twitter?</strong> <small>2023-08-23 08:48:59</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>This week’s Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. debate asks the question: Is Elon Musk (https://www.valuewalk.com/should-you-worry-about-elon-musk-selling-his-tesla-shares/) Killing Twitter? Journalist Kara Swisher argues Yes. Investor Anthony Scaramucci argues No. Wired’s Steven Levy and Insider’s Monica Melton chime in as well with questions.</p>
<p>Check out the full article which has the transcript.</p></div>
<div><strong>Pod-Alization: Libsyn Finds Its “Lore”; Is Musk Killing Twitter; Podcast Interviews</strong> <small>2023-02-07 19:20:15</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Is Musk killing Twitter
This week’s Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S.debate podcast asks: Is Elon Musk Killing Twitter? Journalist Kara Swisher argues Yes. Investor Anthony Scaramucci argues No. Wired’s Steven Levy and Insider’s Monica Melton chime in as well with questions.</p>
<p>The 50-minute debate is now available on all podcast platforms (search “Intelligence Squared U.S.”) and on YouTube.</p>
<p>Of course, you could ask another question. Is Musk at Twitter causing Tesla to implode? Musk’s auto business has missed production targets, seen its stock price plummet, and its cars in self-driving mode have been involved in several accidents.</p></div>
<div><strong>Unsatisfying answers about possibly benign balloons leave congressional critics frustrated</strong> <small>2023-02-16 16:48:58</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Calendar</p>
<p>FRIDAY | FEBRUARY 17</p>
<p>TBA Munich, Germany Munich Security Conference 2023 begins, running through Sunday, Feb. 19 https://securityconference.org (https://securityconference.org/en/news/full/muenchner-sicherheitskonferenz-one-month-to-go/)</p>
<p>2 p.m. Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. virtual live debate recording: Should The U.S. Ban TikTok? with Kori Schake, senior fellow and director of foreign and defense policy studies, American Enterprise Institute, arguing Yes and Milton Mueller, professor, Georgia Institute of Technology School of Public Policy, founder and director, Internet Governance Project, arguing No.Moderated by John Donvan https://www.workcast.com/register (https://www.workcast.com/register?cpak=5204951257857492&mc_cid=c86fb254c9&mc_eid=fb0110d67b)</p></div>
<div><strong>TikTok: to ban or not to ban?</strong> <small>2023-03-03 19:05:33</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>On February 17, Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. hosted a debate. The question was: should the U.S. ban TikTok? Our reporter was there to question both speakers. Here’s what he found out.</p>
<p>The U.S. should ban Tiktok.</p>
<p>Arguing for the motion at a public debate hosted by the company Intelligence Squared was Kori Schake, Director of Foreign and Defense Policy at the American Enterprise Institute, and former official on the National Security Council.</p>
<p>On the other side of the virtual aisle sat Milton L Mueller, a Professor of Cybersecurity Policy at the Georgia Institute of Technology, and creator of theGlobal Internet Governance Academic (http://giga-net.org/)Network (GigaNet) (http://giga-net.org/), an international association of scholars.</p>
<p>The choice of these two figures reflects the two parallel (and rarely converging) trends in the discourse on Tiktok, to which both speakers adhered throughout the course of the session (https://opentodebate.org/debate/should-the-u-s-ban-tiktok/#/): the technical details of how these software platforms operate, and the political rhetoric of the current everything-is-national-security paradigm.</p>
<p>The debate</p>
<p>Setting the parameters of the debate in her opening remarks, Schake laid out the stakes, boiling the issue down to two main concerns: first, that American user data is making its way to China; and second, that Tiktok could be used as a propaganda tool by the Chinese government. And it is this second point that should be of primary concern, not least given Tiktok’s extraordinary reach — 1.53 billion globally, and just shy of 80 million monthly active users in the U.S.</p>
<p>Mueller argued that China is not exporting its propaganda via Tiktok, noting that while ByteDance (https://thechinaproject.com/company-profiles/bytedance/) (Tiktok’s owner) does do this on its domestic platform Douyin, it doesn’t make sense to do so on Tiktok and if it did, it would be to no avail, as users do not want to see such content, so the algorithm would suppress it, leading to negligible impact.</p>
<p>This argument an appeal to Tiktok’s business interests echoes the testimony (https://www.judiciary.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/Sacks%20Testimony.pdf) of Yale Senior Fellow Samm Sacks in May 2019 to the Senate Judiciary Committee. Despite agreeing that ultimately the Chinese government can compel companies to turn over their data, she cited examples from Didi (https://thechinaproject.com/company-profiles/didi-chuxing/), Alibaba (https://thechinaproject.com/company-profiles/alibaba/), and Tencent (https://thechinaproject.com/company-profiles/tencent/) to argue that many Chinese firms routinely push back against data requests from the government. In this vein, while Douyin might be obligated to promote Communist Party media on its platform just like any other domestic competitor, Tiktok operates in a different social media landscape where such tactics are unlikely to succeed.</p>
<p>Schake combatted this by surveying recent developments. She recounted how FBI Director Chris Wray and his U.K. counterpart, MI5’s Ken McCallum, have both argued that Tiktok presents a threat to the national security of their respective nations, which led in part to the Federal ban on Tiktok for government-owned devices. Indeed, in the days since the debate took place, Politico has reported (https://www.politico.eu/article/european-commission-to-staff-dont-use-tiktok/) that the European Commission has also announced a similar ban, with the European Council and EU Parliament said to be following suit.</p>
<p>But John Donvan, who chaired the debate, noted that Kori Schake was effectively providing an argument to authority: in her own words, “I am not an expert on espionage or tech.” As such, she was channeling credible experts. However, as Mueller was quick to point out, for all his access to intelligence, Wray himself is not a technology specialist either. And as far as we can tell, neither is McCallum. What’s more, in all these cases, “concern” over Tiktok’s purported exposure to be manipulated to influence American discourse abounds, but the evidence is thinner, or at least knowledge of it in the public domain seems harder to come by.</p>
<p>Beyond the source code</p>
<p>I tried to pin Mueller down on this in the questions I put to the panelists: given that Tiktok’s recommendation algorithm is so complex often likened to a black box and given that China’s internet regulation guidelines are explicit about platforms promoting core socialist values, how can we know that Tiktok isn’t adhering to those guidelines in some way?</p>
<p>The answer I received was this: While we will likely learn little from analyzing the source code or the functioning of the algorithm from the back end, we can learn more by looking at its outputs. Go on Tiktok, scroll, search, and see what content gets pushed your way. The only way CCP propaganda would rise to the top, Mueller quipped, was if America’s youth had latent communist sympathies. And for now, they are making billions of dollars with the algorithm operating as it is why should they change it?</p>
<p>This is a compelling argument. However, it seemed somewhat naive as a caricature of how PRC propaganda might look, and how media influence operations work. While subtlety and nuance are not characterizations redolent of China’s Foreign Ministry announcements, influence campaigns rarely appear so clunky: you’re unlikely to see hammers and sickles in promoted content sympathetic to Beijing’s preferred candidates or critical of others.</p>
<p>Of course, while such content is well documented on Facebook, Twitter, and other American platforms, it is apparently understudied on TikTok. However, when I asked Schake whether this should be tackled in legislation regulating algorithms across all platforms, she said: I don’t know enough about the functioning of AI algorithms to be able to answer.</p>
<p>This highlights the lack of convergence that characterizes much of the broader debate on Tiktok in the U.S.: a lack of nuanced understanding of the nature of the risks that various technologies pose, because of a general lack of literacy on how these new technologies function.</p>
<p>A Sisyphean task</p>
<p>Experts broadly agree that we should be wary of TikTok: they have proven themselves untrustworthy on numerous occasions, most recently by having Beijing-based employees access (https://www.forbes.com/sites/emilybaker-white/2022/12/22/tiktok-tracks-forbes-journalists-bytedance/) American user data to track journalists despite claiming that this was not possible.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, two substantial problems with a ban remain: Financially, many American small business owners use TikTok as their main revenue source, and would be adversely affected by a ban and legally, there are constitutional challenges on free speech grounds.</p>
<p>For now, we await the recommendations of the two-year-long review by the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States (CFIUS), as well as further actions by the recently anointed Select Committee (https://www.congress.gov/committee/house-select-committee-on-the-strategic-competition-between-the-united-states-and-the-chinese-communist-party/hlzs00) on the Strategic Competition Between the United States and the Chinese Communist Party, a Republican-majority group whose members are on record expressing hardline views on this issue. The remarks of Tiktok’s CEO Shou Zi Chew (周受子 Zhōu Shòuzǐ), who will appear before the U.S. Energy and Commerce Committee on March 23, will certainly be worth tuning in for.</p></div>
<div><strong>Is TikTok a security threat? CT legislators ask for hard data on spying as ban considered</strong> <small>2023-03-16 18:28:03</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>The Government Administration and Elections Committee heard testimony (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tXUHL0z8mpA) on a bill (https://www.cga.ct.gov/2023/TOB/S/PDF/2023SB-01191-R00-SB.PDF) that would ban TikTok (https://www.ctinsider.com/politics/article/ct-legislature-considers-banning-tiktok-wechat-17771929.php) from being used by government employees or public officials on state-owned devices. The sole exception would be for law enforcement purposes.</p>
<p>You don’t need to be a member of Generation Z to know what TikTok is, said Sen. Bob Duff, D-Norwalk, during a Friday meeting. The Federal Bureau of Investigation has repeatedly pointed out the danger that this application poses to government entities.</p>
<p>Rep. Gale Mastrofranceso, R-Southington, said, I gotta be honest with you, I'm on the fence on it.Do you have any data besides the news outlets? Do we have hard facts?</p>
<p>The proposed bill before the General Assembly would also charge the chief information officer, chief information security officer, and the chief court administrator to jointly develop security standards for computer programs and state-issued devices to counter cybersecurity threats.</p>
<p>During the testimony, board members asked Duff and Sen. Ryan Fazio, R-Greenwich, if there was any concrete evidence about the espionage threat of TikTok.</p>
<p>I’m a freedom guy, as you know, said Sen. Rob Samson, R-Southington. Do you have any concrete evidence?”</p>
<p>Fazio replied The best example is that employees of ByteDance used TikTok geolocation data specifically to track journalists whom they suspected of speaking to employees of TikTok in the U.S. The ability of these applications to retain and collect data is immense.</p>
<p>In replies to requests for more data on the privacy threats of TikTok, Duff, and Fazio pointed to news reports about TikTok tracking journalists and the testimony of FBI Director Chris Wray.</p>
<p>In December 2022, Jeff Brown, the current chief information security officer, and Mark Raymond, the chief information officer, asked the various intelligence and security agencies, including the FBI, for guidance on TikTok</p>
<p>According to documents obtained by CT Insider via a Freedom of Information request, the FBI and the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency had no additional evidence to provide that TikTok was a security threat.</p>
<p>I asked one of my analysts to reach out to our HQ … She couldn’t find evidence that we had any additional information to share,” wrote FBI supervisory agent Connor Phoenix in an email to Connecticut officials. Sorry, we don’t have more to offer.</p>
<p>The discrepancy between what the cybersecurity agents could provide and what the FBI director is saying in public is likely political, says Milton Mueller, director of the Internet Governance Project of Georgetown University.</p>
<p>Chris Wray is not an expert on cybersecurity. The FBI director is a political appointee and he is touting a political line, Mueller said in an Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. debate earlier this month. (https://opentodebate.org/debate/should-the-u-s-ban-tiktok/#/) This is a foreign policy case. There are people who believe in decoupling from China, and they will interpret any connection to a Chinese company as a threat. There’s really no evidence that this is harming the United States.</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Social Media Is Good for Democracy</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Facebook, Cambridge Analytica & Democracy</u></p>
<p><u>Social Media as a Force for Change</u></p>
<p><u>Social Media as a Weapon</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> June 26, 2018</p>
<p>By connecting people across the world for free, platforms like Twitter and Facebook set the stage for a promising digital revolution, providing tools that helped foster global friendships, break down long-standing barriers that kept people and ideas from being heard, and served as the ultimate democratizing force for information. Now, lawmakers in the U.S. and beyond are reeling with questions of how to prevent the spread of digital political propaganda and protect citizens’ personal privacy online. Critics argue that rather than uniting and informing, social media deepens social and political divisions and erodes trust in the democratic process. Will the power of social media yet be harnessed and used as an unprecedented force for good in the world? Or do systemic platform flaws pose an irreversible threat to the world’s democratic institutions?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/CajecmPc-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/CajecmPc-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Jeff Jarvis</strong><br>Jeff Jarvis is a national leader in the development of online news, blogging, and the investigation of new business models for news. He is director of the Tow-Knight Center for Entrepreneurial Journalism at the City University of New York and serves as an executive committee member for the News Integrity Initiative. Funded in part by Facebook and Mozilla, the initiative supports news literacy and journalistic efforts around the world. Jarvis is also the author of several books, including “Geeks Bearing Gifts” and “What Would Google Do?” He blogs about media and news at <a href="http://Buzzmachine.com">Buzzmachine.com</a> and cohosts the podcast <a href="https://twit.tv/shows/this-week-in-google">This Week in Google</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Emily Parker</strong><br>Emily Parker is the author of “Now I Know Who My Comrades Are: Voices From the Internet Underground,” which tells the stories of internet activists in China, Cuba, and Russia. Parker was chief strategy officer at Parlio, a Silicon Valley start-up that aimed to bring civility to social media. Previously she was a member of the policy planning staff at the U.S. Department of State, where she advised on internet freedom. Parker is a former staff writer and editor at the Wall Street Journal and a former editor at the New York Times. She is currently the co-founder of Longhash, a global blockchain start-up.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Franklin Foer</strong><br>Franklin Foer is a staff writer at The Atlantic and the former editor of The New Republic. He is the author of “World Without Mind: The Existential Threat of Big Tech,” which explores the influence of Amazon, Facebook, Apple, and Google on modern life, and was named one of the best books of the year by the New York Times.</p>
<p><strong>Roger McNamee</strong><br>Roger McNamee has spent 35 years investing in the technology industry. He is a co-founder of three firms: "Integral Capital Partners", "Silver Lake Partners", and "Elevation Partners." An early investor in Facebook, he served as a mentor to Mark Zuckerberg from 2006 to 2009. He is the author of “The New Normal,” a regular commentator on CNBC and MSNBC, and a touring musician. He holds four patents related to broadcasting live video to cell phones.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Is Elon Musk killing Twitter? How bankruptcy might not be the end</strong> <small>2023-02-02 18:59:19</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>A debate between an investor and a journalist looks into what is happening at the social media company</p>
<p>Last October, Elon Musk completed his move to acquire Twitter (https://interestingengineering.com/culture/elon-musk-completes-twitter-takeover) after a short legal brawl, but the joy of the move was short-lived. Having fired the top brass the same day, Musk moved on to firing more than half of Twitter’s staff, and bad news kept poring out of the San Francisco headquarters quite regularly.</p>
<p>As we enter the New Year, the situation hasn’t changed much, and Twitter continues to be in the news for all the wrong reasons, like not paying rent for its office spaces and employees being forced out of buildings by landlords, The New York Times reported (https://www.nytimes.com/2022/12/13/technology/elon-musk-twitter-shakeup.html?smid=tw-nytimes&smtyp=cur). The question that crosses one’s mind is if Musk is out to kill Twitter once and for all.</p>
<p>Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S.Intelligence Squared (http://opentodebate.org), a platform known for organizing debates, took up this question and set up a debate between Kara Swisher, the editor-at-large at New York Magazine, and Anthony Scaramucci, managing partner at Skybridge capital and former communications director at the White House.</p>
<p>Neither Swisher nor Scaramucci have a personal or professional relationship with Musk, even though they have met and interacted with the now Twitter CEO on multiple occasions.</p>
<p>Here's a look at various aspects of the effects Elon Musk's takeover has had on Twitter.</p>
<p>Active Users
Musk’s actions have allegedly led to a drop in usage among active users, who usually contribute a lot of content to the platform, and is forcing users to give competitors, like Mastodon, a try, Swisher said while stating that Musk's leadership was leading to Twitter's downfall.</p>
<p>Comparing it to a proverbial town square, Scaramucci argued that Twitter, since Musk’s takeover had more active users and was at the center of many important events, whether it was the FIFA World Cup or the FTX debacle.</p>
<p>Journalists could cover nuances of a story thanks to Twitter while people get updates about people they follow from the platform. Twitter Spaces turned out to be an effective medium and preferable over ClubHouse. When Musk himself joined Twitter Space, more than 100,000 people were in attendance listening and asking questions, Scaramucci said while defending that Musk wasn't killing Twitter.</p>
<p>Return of banned accounts
Swisher pointed out Musk-led Twitter has allowed 60,000 accounts previously suspended back on the platform to “improve the conversation”. Worse still, the decision to allow these users back seems to have been made single-handedly by Musk, instead of a council that was supposed to be set up.</p>
<p>Scaramucci argued that by bringing people back, Musk was giving them a platform to voice their opinions rather than shut them off. This way, he was bringing them back into the social contract. He added that when individuals speak, think and speak freely, it creates economic innovation.</p>
<p>Loss of revenue
Swisher strongly argued that Musk was indeed killing Twitter after his arrival blew off $5 billion in advertising revenues for the social media company, which was significant for income in the pre-Musk days. His plans of launching the paid subscription model of revenue generation hurt corporate clients more as users faked companies after paying $8 a month and got verified checks to their fake usernames.</p>
<p>Scaramucci added that large corporations were risk averse and did not want to advertise on Twitter due to what Musk was doing.</p>
<p>Twitter’s valuation drops
Swisher also pointed out a report that the Bank of America and Morgan Stanley who lent Musk money to finance his Twitter deal have now halved the Twitter debt on their books, which means the company’s equity has been wiped out in just two months after Musk has arrived at the helm of the affairs.</p>
<p>Scaramucci ceded that Twitter’s valuations were down but argued that the company was far from dead and could see a revival in the coming months and years. Instead with a more active user base, the company was more vital than ever.</p>
<p>Could Twitter go bankrupt?
Swisher pointed out that Musk first spoke about Twitter's potential bankruptcy (https://interestingengineering.com/culture/twitter-possible-bankruptcy-top-executives-leave). While it is likely that Musk, the world’s richest person, will not let it happen, he had many wealthy friends who could put money into the company if it came to that.</p>
<p>However, she warned that if the loan ended up on Wall Street, it could be bought by someone else, who would want Musk out before he could fix what he had broken at Twitter. She argued that although Twitter got a lot of attention from politicians and the media, it wasn’t a great business when compared to other social media outlets, and with Musk at the helm had turned into a lousy business.</p>
<p>Comparison with Tesla, SpaceX
Scaramucci’s faith in Elon Musk to revive Twitter comes from his other companies, Tesla and SpaceX, staring at bankruptcy in 2008. Back then, it was Musk’s leadership that steered them away to levels that made him one of the richest people in the world (https://interestingengineering.com/culture/elon-musk-just-got-36-billion-richer-in-a-single-day).</p>
<p>He said that Musk may have started on the wrong foot with Twitter trying to give away verified badges for a fee but, having realized his mistake, reversed his decision. In the long run, Scaramucci expects Musk to get things right at Twitter.</p>
<p>Swisher, however, argued that too much faith was being put into Musk’s ability because of his history. Musk was good at making cars and rockets, but that does not mean he will be good at media too.</p>
<p>Twitter being a media company puts him in a very different situation, and his ideas to ‘unlock its potential’ are retreads of what many orders have suggested in the past. In fact, Musk has been unable to execute them properly and has made the site more erratic as of now.</p>
<p>Swisher also referred to Steve Jobs as a true visionary who stayed in his lane and did great things. Musk, on the other hand, does not seem to have a clue about what he is up to.</p>
<p>Musk’s vision for Twitter
Scaramucci, an investor, had access to a Powerpoint presentation for Musk’s vision for Twitter, which said that he wants to broaden the social media base and make it more inclusive. Going forward, Musk wants Twitter to become a ‘super app’ much like WeChat, which is used in China by users for social media, making payments, and personal communication.</p>
<p>Swisher, however, said that ‘super apps’ have not worked in the U.S. before, and even the likes of Apple and Amazon have tried to do it and failed so far. It might be working in China, but the U.S. was a different market, and people would trust Amazon or Apple with their payments but not Twitter.</p>
<p>Moreover, people used different apps for different purposes, like Snapchat for communication and TikTok for entertainment. Like Facebook usage has dropped, Twitter under Musk is heading the same way.</p>
<p>Twitter: Unassailable or Obsolete?
Due to its ability to connect people to events happening globally, Scaramucci said, Twitter had found a niche for itself in the past 15 years of its existence and become an indispensable part of our daily lives. Even if Musk failed in his mission to turn the company around, he would leave, and someone else could steady the ship.</p>
<p>With Musk planning to ring in many changes in how Twitter looks and behaves, users could be worried if the sudden changes would keep the platform usable. Swisher thinks that if the user experience dips and people find it hard to use Twitter, then it is likely that competitors will make something easier to use, shifting the user base away.</p>
<p>Swisher was pessimistic that the company could survive the Elon storm and compared his management style to building a rocket while it was in flight. Worse still, his decisions were taking the rocket on a downward trajectory, and Musk was single-handedly making the decisions. Swisher would not be surprised if Twitter soon became part of the graveyard of internet companies such as AOL, AIM, Yahoo, and MySpace, which were great at one time but have become obsolete over the years.</p>
<p>Impact on Musk
The time Musk spends at Twitter also affects his other ventures, such as Tesla, Swisher argued. The EV-making company had seen a steep decline in its valuation (https://interestingengineering.com/culture/musk-lose-200-billion), with Twitter serving as a larger distraction for Musk, the CEO, than when he was just a prolific user of the platform.</p>
<p>The competition in the EV market has grown, and Tesla is ceding its market share, which took years to build, very rapidly. The mass firing of staff at Twitter is also resulting in class action lawsuits and which are likely to be the biggest ones in Musk’s life.</p>
<p>Scaramucci quoting Warren Buffett that a high-quality business can endure a bad management team or terrible decisions to set the tone of his defense is a strong indicator of what’s happening at Twitter.</p>
<p>The debate was published across various podcast platforms today.</p></div>
<div><strong>Swisher v. Scaramucci: Is Elon Musk Killing Twitter?</strong> <small>2023-08-23 08:48:59</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>This week’s Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. debate asks the question: Is Elon Musk (https://www.valuewalk.com/should-you-worry-about-elon-musk-selling-his-tesla-shares/) Killing Twitter? Journalist Kara Swisher argues Yes. Investor Anthony Scaramucci argues No. Wired’s Steven Levy and Insider’s Monica Melton chime in as well with questions.</p>
<p>Check out the full article which has the transcript.</p></div>
<div><strong>Pod-Alization: Libsyn Finds Its “Lore”; Is Musk Killing Twitter; Podcast Interviews</strong> <small>2023-02-07 19:20:15</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Is Musk killing Twitter
This week’s Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S.debate podcast asks: Is Elon Musk Killing Twitter? Journalist Kara Swisher argues Yes. Investor Anthony Scaramucci argues No. Wired’s Steven Levy and Insider’s Monica Melton chime in as well with questions.</p>
<p>The 50-minute debate is now available on all podcast platforms (search “Intelligence Squared U.S.”) and on YouTube.</p>
<p>Of course, you could ask another question. Is Musk at Twitter causing Tesla to implode? Musk’s auto business has missed production targets, seen its stock price plummet, and its cars in self-driving mode have been involved in several accidents.</p></div>
<div><strong>Unsatisfying answers about possibly benign balloons leave congressional critics frustrated</strong> <small>2023-02-16 16:48:58</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Calendar</p>
<p>FRIDAY | FEBRUARY 17</p>
<p>TBA Munich, Germany Munich Security Conference 2023 begins, running through Sunday, Feb. 19 https://securityconference.org (https://securityconference.org/en/news/full/muenchner-sicherheitskonferenz-one-month-to-go/)</p>
<p>2 p.m. Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. virtual live debate recording: Should The U.S. Ban TikTok? with Kori Schake, senior fellow and director of foreign and defense policy studies, American Enterprise Institute, arguing Yes and Milton Mueller, professor, Georgia Institute of Technology School of Public Policy, founder and director, Internet Governance Project, arguing No.Moderated by John Donvan https://www.workcast.com/register (https://www.workcast.com/register?cpak=5204951257857492&mc_cid=c86fb254c9&mc_eid=fb0110d67b)</p></div>
<div><strong>TikTok: to ban or not to ban?</strong> <small>2023-03-03 19:05:33</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>On February 17, Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. hosted a debate. The question was: should the U.S. ban TikTok? Our reporter was there to question both speakers. Here’s what he found out.</p>
<p>The U.S. should ban Tiktok.</p>
<p>Arguing for the motion at a public debate hosted by the company Intelligence Squared was Kori Schake, Director of Foreign and Defense Policy at the American Enterprise Institute, and former official on the National Security Council.</p>
<p>On the other side of the virtual aisle sat Milton L Mueller, a Professor of Cybersecurity Policy at the Georgia Institute of Technology, and creator of theGlobal Internet Governance Academic (http://giga-net.org/)Network (GigaNet) (http://giga-net.org/), an international association of scholars.</p>
<p>The choice of these two figures reflects the two parallel (and rarely converging) trends in the discourse on Tiktok, to which both speakers adhered throughout the course of the session (https://opentodebate.org/debate/should-the-u-s-ban-tiktok/#/): the technical details of how these software platforms operate, and the political rhetoric of the current everything-is-national-security paradigm.</p>
<p>The debate</p>
<p>Setting the parameters of the debate in her opening remarks, Schake laid out the stakes, boiling the issue down to two main concerns: first, that American user data is making its way to China; and second, that Tiktok could be used as a propaganda tool by the Chinese government. And it is this second point that should be of primary concern, not least given Tiktok’s extraordinary reach — 1.53 billion globally, and just shy of 80 million monthly active users in the U.S.</p>
<p>Mueller argued that China is not exporting its propaganda via Tiktok, noting that while ByteDance (https://thechinaproject.com/company-profiles/bytedance/) (Tiktok’s owner) does do this on its domestic platform Douyin, it doesn’t make sense to do so on Tiktok and if it did, it would be to no avail, as users do not want to see such content, so the algorithm would suppress it, leading to negligible impact.</p>
<p>This argument an appeal to Tiktok’s business interests echoes the testimony (https://www.judiciary.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/Sacks%20Testimony.pdf) of Yale Senior Fellow Samm Sacks in May 2019 to the Senate Judiciary Committee. Despite agreeing that ultimately the Chinese government can compel companies to turn over their data, she cited examples from Didi (https://thechinaproject.com/company-profiles/didi-chuxing/), Alibaba (https://thechinaproject.com/company-profiles/alibaba/), and Tencent (https://thechinaproject.com/company-profiles/tencent/) to argue that many Chinese firms routinely push back against data requests from the government. In this vein, while Douyin might be obligated to promote Communist Party media on its platform just like any other domestic competitor, Tiktok operates in a different social media landscape where such tactics are unlikely to succeed.</p>
<p>Schake combatted this by surveying recent developments. She recounted how FBI Director Chris Wray and his U.K. counterpart, MI5’s Ken McCallum, have both argued that Tiktok presents a threat to the national security of their respective nations, which led in part to the Federal ban on Tiktok for government-owned devices. Indeed, in the days since the debate took place, Politico has reported (https://www.politico.eu/article/european-commission-to-staff-dont-use-tiktok/) that the European Commission has also announced a similar ban, with the European Council and EU Parliament said to be following suit.</p>
<p>But John Donvan, who chaired the debate, noted that Kori Schake was effectively providing an argument to authority: in her own words, “I am not an expert on espionage or tech.” As such, she was channeling credible experts. However, as Mueller was quick to point out, for all his access to intelligence, Wray himself is not a technology specialist either. And as far as we can tell, neither is McCallum. What’s more, in all these cases, “concern” over Tiktok’s purported exposure to be manipulated to influence American discourse abounds, but the evidence is thinner, or at least knowledge of it in the public domain seems harder to come by.</p>
<p>Beyond the source code</p>
<p>I tried to pin Mueller down on this in the questions I put to the panelists: given that Tiktok’s recommendation algorithm is so complex often likened to a black box and given that China’s internet regulation guidelines are explicit about platforms promoting core socialist values, how can we know that Tiktok isn’t adhering to those guidelines in some way?</p>
<p>The answer I received was this: While we will likely learn little from analyzing the source code or the functioning of the algorithm from the back end, we can learn more by looking at its outputs. Go on Tiktok, scroll, search, and see what content gets pushed your way. The only way CCP propaganda would rise to the top, Mueller quipped, was if America’s youth had latent communist sympathies. And for now, they are making billions of dollars with the algorithm operating as it is why should they change it?</p>
<p>This is a compelling argument. However, it seemed somewhat naive as a caricature of how PRC propaganda might look, and how media influence operations work. While subtlety and nuance are not characterizations redolent of China’s Foreign Ministry announcements, influence campaigns rarely appear so clunky: you’re unlikely to see hammers and sickles in promoted content sympathetic to Beijing’s preferred candidates or critical of others.</p>
<p>Of course, while such content is well documented on Facebook, Twitter, and other American platforms, it is apparently understudied on TikTok. However, when I asked Schake whether this should be tackled in legislation regulating algorithms across all platforms, she said: I don’t know enough about the functioning of AI algorithms to be able to answer.</p>
<p>This highlights the lack of convergence that characterizes much of the broader debate on Tiktok in the U.S.: a lack of nuanced understanding of the nature of the risks that various technologies pose, because of a general lack of literacy on how these new technologies function.</p>
<p>A Sisyphean task</p>
<p>Experts broadly agree that we should be wary of TikTok: they have proven themselves untrustworthy on numerous occasions, most recently by having Beijing-based employees access (https://www.forbes.com/sites/emilybaker-white/2022/12/22/tiktok-tracks-forbes-journalists-bytedance/) American user data to track journalists despite claiming that this was not possible.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, two substantial problems with a ban remain: Financially, many American small business owners use TikTok as their main revenue source, and would be adversely affected by a ban and legally, there are constitutional challenges on free speech grounds.</p>
<p>For now, we await the recommendations of the two-year-long review by the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States (CFIUS), as well as further actions by the recently anointed Select Committee (https://www.congress.gov/committee/house-select-committee-on-the-strategic-competition-between-the-united-states-and-the-chinese-communist-party/hlzs00) on the Strategic Competition Between the United States and the Chinese Communist Party, a Republican-majority group whose members are on record expressing hardline views on this issue. The remarks of Tiktok’s CEO Shou Zi Chew (周受子 Zhōu Shòuzǐ), who will appear before the U.S. Energy and Commerce Committee on March 23, will certainly be worth tuning in for.</p></div>
<div><strong>Is TikTok a security threat? CT legislators ask for hard data on spying as ban considered</strong> <small>2023-03-16 18:28:03</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>The Government Administration and Elections Committee heard testimony (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tXUHL0z8mpA) on a bill (https://www.cga.ct.gov/2023/TOB/S/PDF/2023SB-01191-R00-SB.PDF) that would ban TikTok (https://www.ctinsider.com/politics/article/ct-legislature-considers-banning-tiktok-wechat-17771929.php) from being used by government employees or public officials on state-owned devices. The sole exception would be for law enforcement purposes.</p>
<p>You don’t need to be a member of Generation Z to know what TikTok is, said Sen. Bob Duff, D-Norwalk, during a Friday meeting. The Federal Bureau of Investigation has repeatedly pointed out the danger that this application poses to government entities.</p>
<p>Rep. Gale Mastrofranceso, R-Southington, said, I gotta be honest with you, I'm on the fence on it.Do you have any data besides the news outlets? Do we have hard facts?</p>
<p>The proposed bill before the General Assembly would also charge the chief information officer, chief information security officer, and the chief court administrator to jointly develop security standards for computer programs and state-issued devices to counter cybersecurity threats.</p>
<p>During the testimony, board members asked Duff and Sen. Ryan Fazio, R-Greenwich, if there was any concrete evidence about the espionage threat of TikTok.</p>
<p>I’m a freedom guy, as you know, said Sen. Rob Samson, R-Southington. Do you have any concrete evidence?”</p>
<p>Fazio replied The best example is that employees of ByteDance used TikTok geolocation data specifically to track journalists whom they suspected of speaking to employees of TikTok in the U.S. The ability of these applications to retain and collect data is immense.</p>
<p>In replies to requests for more data on the privacy threats of TikTok, Duff, and Fazio pointed to news reports about TikTok tracking journalists and the testimony of FBI Director Chris Wray.</p>
<p>In December 2022, Jeff Brown, the current chief information security officer, and Mark Raymond, the chief information officer, asked the various intelligence and security agencies, including the FBI, for guidance on TikTok</p>
<p>According to documents obtained by CT Insider via a Freedom of Information request, the FBI and the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency had no additional evidence to provide that TikTok was a security threat.</p>
<p>I asked one of my analysts to reach out to our HQ … She couldn’t find evidence that we had any additional information to share,” wrote FBI supervisory agent Connor Phoenix in an email to Connecticut officials. Sorry, we don’t have more to offer.</p>
<p>The discrepancy between what the cybersecurity agents could provide and what the FBI director is saying in public is likely political, says Milton Mueller, director of the Internet Governance Project of Georgetown University.</p>
<p>Chris Wray is not an expert on cybersecurity. The FBI director is a political appointee and he is touting a political line, Mueller said in an Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. debate earlier this month. (https://opentodebate.org/debate/should-the-u-s-ban-tiktok/#/) This is a foreign policy case. There are people who believe in decoupling from China, and they will interpret any connection to a Chinese company as a threat. There’s really no evidence that this is harming the United States.</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Social Media Is Good for Democracy</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Facebook, Cambridge Analytica & Democracy</u></p>
<p><u>Social Media as a Force for Change</u></p>
<p><u>Social Media as a Weapon</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Trigger Warning: Safe Spaces Are Dangerous</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/trigger-warning-safe-spaces-are-dangerous</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10358</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> June 23, 2018</p>
<p>Long hailed as bastions of intellectual development and ground zero for the free and spirited exchange of ideas, today’s universities have come under attack by those who argue that a new generation of students and administrators are trading in academia’s most cherished values for political correctness and inclusion. At the heart of this debate is the question of safe spaces, how we define them, and whether they aid or hinder intellectual inquiry. Deeply rooted in social justice movements of the past, these spaces promise a reprieve from bigotry and oppression by allowing today’s students – the most culturally and racially diverse in history – the opportunity to express themselves in an empathetic environment. But to their critics, safe spaces pose a dire threat to free speech and undermine the resilience of a generation. Are safe spaces dangerously coddling young minds? Or are they a legitimate and necessary component of modern education?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/G1YiPBBl-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/G1YiPBBl-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>David L. Hudson Jr.</strong><br>David L. Hudson Jr. is a First Amendment expert and law professor at Vanderbilt University. He is the author, co-author, or co-editor of more than 40 books and has written several devoted to student-speech issues, including “Freedom of Speech: Documents Decoded” and “Let the Students Speak: A History of the Fight for Free Expression in American Schools.” Hudson also serves as the First Amendment Ombudsman for the Newseum Institute’s First Amendment Center.</p>
<p><strong>Suzanne Nossel</strong><br>Suzanne Nossel is a leading voice on free expression issues in the U.S. and globally. She is CEO of PEN America, the leading human rights and free expression organization, and was previously chief operating officer of Human Rights Watch and executive director of Amnesty International USA. She is a veteran of both the Obama and Clinton administrations, most recently serving as deputy assistant secretary of state for international organizations under President Obama.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://pen.org/user/suzanne-nossel/">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Ashutosh Bhagwat</strong><br>Ashutosh Bhagwat is a Martin Luther King Jr. professor of law at UC Davis and the author of "The Myth of Rights: The Purposes and Limits of Constitutional Rights." He has written numerous books, articles, and book chapters on a wide variety of subjects, ranging from the structure of constitutional rights to free speech law to the California electricity crisis. After graduating from the University of Chicago Law School, Bhagwat clerked for Associate Justice Anthony M. Kennedy of the United States Supreme Court.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://law.ucdavis.edu/faculty/bhagwat/">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Michael S. Roth</strong><br>Michael S. Roth is the president of Wesleyan University and is known as a historian, curator, author, and public advocate for liberal education. He has written a number of books, including "Beyond the University: Why Liberal Education Matters," which has been assigned to boards of trustees and incoming freshmen alike and serves as a powerful tool for students, their families, faculty, and policymakers who are wrestling with the future of higher education in America.
<br><a href="http://www.wesleyan.edu/president/biography/">Full bio available here. </a></p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Trigger Warning: Safe Spaces Are Dangerous</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Microaggressions</u></p>
<p><u>Student Experience</u></p>
<p><u>Recent Incidents</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> June 23, 2018</p>
<p>Long hailed as bastions of intellectual development and ground zero for the free and spirited exchange of ideas, today’s universities have come under attack by those who argue that a new generation of students and administrators are trading in academia’s most cherished values for political correctness and inclusion. At the heart of this debate is the question of safe spaces, how we define them, and whether they aid or hinder intellectual inquiry. Deeply rooted in social justice movements of the past, these spaces promise a reprieve from bigotry and oppression by allowing today’s students – the most culturally and racially diverse in history – the opportunity to express themselves in an empathetic environment. But to their critics, safe spaces pose a dire threat to free speech and undermine the resilience of a generation. Are safe spaces dangerously coddling young minds? Or are they a legitimate and necessary component of modern education?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/G1YiPBBl-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/G1YiPBBl-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>David L. Hudson Jr.</strong><br>David L. Hudson Jr. is a First Amendment expert and law professor at Vanderbilt University. He is the author, co-author, or co-editor of more than 40 books and has written several devoted to student-speech issues, including “Freedom of Speech: Documents Decoded” and “Let the Students Speak: A History of the Fight for Free Expression in American Schools.” Hudson also serves as the First Amendment Ombudsman for the Newseum Institute’s First Amendment Center.</p>
<p><strong>Suzanne Nossel</strong><br>Suzanne Nossel is a leading voice on free expression issues in the U.S. and globally. She is CEO of PEN America, the leading human rights and free expression organization, and was previously chief operating officer of Human Rights Watch and executive director of Amnesty International USA. She is a veteran of both the Obama and Clinton administrations, most recently serving as deputy assistant secretary of state for international organizations under President Obama.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://pen.org/user/suzanne-nossel/">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Ashutosh Bhagwat</strong><br>Ashutosh Bhagwat is a Martin Luther King Jr. professor of law at UC Davis and the author of "The Myth of Rights: The Purposes and Limits of Constitutional Rights." He has written numerous books, articles, and book chapters on a wide variety of subjects, ranging from the structure of constitutional rights to free speech law to the California electricity crisis. After graduating from the University of Chicago Law School, Bhagwat clerked for Associate Justice Anthony M. Kennedy of the United States Supreme Court.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://law.ucdavis.edu/faculty/bhagwat/">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Michael S. Roth</strong><br>Michael S. Roth is the president of Wesleyan University and is known as a historian, curator, author, and public advocate for liberal education. He has written a number of books, including "Beyond the University: Why Liberal Education Matters," which has been assigned to boards of trustees and incoming freshmen alike and serves as a powerful tool for students, their families, faculty, and policymakers who are wrestling with the future of higher education in America.
<br><a href="http://www.wesleyan.edu/president/biography/">Full bio available here. </a></p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Trigger Warning: Safe Spaces Are Dangerous</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Microaggressions</u></p>
<p><u>Student Experience</u></p>
<p><u>Recent Incidents</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Automation Will Crash Democracy</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/automation-will-crash-democracy</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10011</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> May 14, 2018</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Tech, U.S., World</p>
<p>Around the world, technology is disrupting the workforce, with automation poised to displace humans in the fields of medicine, agriculture, and beyond. Will the rise of robots fuel a new wave of “us versus them” populism capable of undermining democracy?
For some, the answer is yes. They argue that as people lose jobs to robots, the gap between the rich and poor widens, distrust in government and democratic institutions grows, and populist ideas become more attractive to those who feel left behind. The importance of work trumps the importance of democracy, leaving a clear path for authoritarians to rise under nationalist messages that pit groups of people against one another. But others paint a different picture: They argue that humans have adapted to – and benefited from – new innovations for centuries. From the advent of water and steam power to computers, work has changed, but never disappeared. And as automation drives higher productivity growth, humans can reach their full potential and pursue societal innovation, allowing more citizens to feel fulfilled and strengthening democracy on the whole.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/fBLsvUpo-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/fBLsvUpo-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Ian Bremmer</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO102471467 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO102471467 BCX0">Ian Bremmer is the president and founder of Eurasia Group, the leading global political risk research and consulting firm, and president of GZERO Media. He is the foreign affairs columnist and editor-at-large at Time magazine, where he writes about China, U.S. foreign policy, and geopolitics. A prolific writer, he is the author of eleven books, including the New York Times best-seller "Us vs. Them: The Failure of Globalism," which explores the consequences of globalism.</span></span></p>
<p><strong>Yascha Mounk</strong><br>Yascha Mounk is an associate professor of practice in international affairs at Johns Hopkins University and a postdoctoral fellow at the German Marshall Fund. A columnist at Slate and the host of "The Good Fight" podcast, he is an expert on the rise of populism and the crisis of liberal democracy. He is also the author of "The People vs. Democracy: Why Our Freedom Is in Danger and How to Save It."
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.yaschamounk.com/about">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Andrew Keen</strong><br>Named one of the "100 most connected men" by GQ magazine, Andrew Keen is one of the world’s best-known broadcasters and commentators on democracy. He is the host of, "How to Fix Democracy", the long-running internet show that includes Margaret Atwood and Madeleine Albright among its many illustrious guests. In 2023 and 2024, the show will focus on the 100-year history of American democracy between 1924 and 2024. Andrew wrote and produced the 2020, "How to Fix Democracy", movie, a documentary about democracy shot in Greece, Germany, the United Kingdom, and the United States. He also presents, "Keen on Democracy", a popular podcast show that gets several million downloads and views a year. He is the author of four acclaimed books on the relationship between technology and democracy, including the best-selling "Cult of the Amateur" and "The Internet Is Not the Answer." Andrew studied contemporary history and politics at the Universities of London and Berkeley. He is currently working on a book about democracy in America.</p>
<p><strong>Alina Polyakova</strong><br><span data-contrast="auto">Dr. Alina Polyakova is President and CEO of the Center for European Policy Analysis (CEPA) as well as the Donald Marron Senior Fellow at the Henry A. Kissinger Center for Global Affairs at the Johns Hopkins University’s School of Advanced International Studies (SAIS).</span>
<span data-contrast="auto">Dr. Polyakova is a recognized expert on transatlantic relations, European security including Russia and Ukraine, tech policy, and populism. She is the author of the book, The Dark Side of European Integration, which examines the rise of far-right political movements in Europe, as well as dozens of major policy reports and articles in outlets such as The Washington Post, The New York Times, The Wall Street Journal, Foreign Affairs, and The Atlantic, and others. She is a frequent commentator in major media outlets, such as Fox News, CNN, and BBC.</span>
<span data-contrast="auto">Dr. Polyakova is an experienced leader with previous roles as the Founding Director for Global Democracy and Emerging Technology at the Brookings Institution, Director of Research for Europe and Eurasia at the Atlantic Council, among others. She has also held numerous prestigious fellowships, including at the National Science Foundation, the Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars, and the Fulbright Foundation, among others. She serves on the board of the Free Russia Foundation and is a member of the Leadership Council for Women in National Security (LCWINS) and the Scientific Council of the Elcano Royal Institute.</span>
<span data-contrast="auto">Dr. Polyakova holds a Ph.D. and MA in Sociology from the University of California, Berkeley, and a BA in Economics and Sociology from Emory University.</span></p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Can Democracy Survive The Future Of Automation?</strong> <small>2018-05-22 15:50:06</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Can we all agree that Google Duplex demo was eerie? A robot, posing as a human being, scheduled a reservation over the phone. We all knew artificial intelligence was coming, but it was breathtaking to hear software come to life.</p>
<p>Before we go any further, let's get our terms straight. Automation and artificial intelligence are not the same thing. According to Dave Evans, "Automation is software that follows pre-programmed rules. Artificial intelligence is designed to simulate human thinking." Automation, in this context, refers to the impact of artificial intelligence on tasks that only humans can perform today.</p>
<p>Even if you're skeptical of Google Duplex in light of the current backlash, Alexa has made her way into millions of homes. Amazon and Google are proving the value of artificial intelligence to consumers. (Apple still has a ways to go with Siri.) While Alexa won’t take down the government, there was a recent debate about the impact of automation on democracy that's worth watching.</p>
<p>Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. features debates about current events. Each episode puts forward a provocative motion like “Automation Will Crash Democracy.” Two teams of two debate the motion. There are polls conducted at the beginning and at the end of the debate. A team wins by persuading audience members to change their opinion. Ian Bremmer and Yascha Mounk argued for the motion, insisting automation will crash democracy. Andrew Keen and Alina Polyakova argued against the motion.</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Automation Will Crash Democracy</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>The Rise of Populism</u></p>
<p><u>The State of Democracy</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> May 14, 2018</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Tech, U.S., World</p>
<p>Around the world, technology is disrupting the workforce, with automation poised to displace humans in the fields of medicine, agriculture, and beyond. Will the rise of robots fuel a new wave of “us versus them” populism capable of undermining democracy?
For some, the answer is yes. They argue that as people lose jobs to robots, the gap between the rich and poor widens, distrust in government and democratic institutions grows, and populist ideas become more attractive to those who feel left behind. The importance of work trumps the importance of democracy, leaving a clear path for authoritarians to rise under nationalist messages that pit groups of people against one another. But others paint a different picture: They argue that humans have adapted to – and benefited from – new innovations for centuries. From the advent of water and steam power to computers, work has changed, but never disappeared. And as automation drives higher productivity growth, humans can reach their full potential and pursue societal innovation, allowing more citizens to feel fulfilled and strengthening democracy on the whole.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/fBLsvUpo-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/fBLsvUpo-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Ian Bremmer</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO102471467 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO102471467 BCX0">Ian Bremmer is the president and founder of Eurasia Group, the leading global political risk research and consulting firm, and president of GZERO Media. He is the foreign affairs columnist and editor-at-large at Time magazine, where he writes about China, U.S. foreign policy, and geopolitics. A prolific writer, he is the author of eleven books, including the New York Times best-seller "Us vs. Them: The Failure of Globalism," which explores the consequences of globalism.</span></span></p>
<p><strong>Yascha Mounk</strong><br>Yascha Mounk is an associate professor of practice in international affairs at Johns Hopkins University and a postdoctoral fellow at the German Marshall Fund. A columnist at Slate and the host of "The Good Fight" podcast, he is an expert on the rise of populism and the crisis of liberal democracy. He is also the author of "The People vs. Democracy: Why Our Freedom Is in Danger and How to Save It."
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.yaschamounk.com/about">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Andrew Keen</strong><br>Named one of the "100 most connected men" by GQ magazine, Andrew Keen is one of the world’s best-known broadcasters and commentators on democracy. He is the host of, "How to Fix Democracy", the long-running internet show that includes Margaret Atwood and Madeleine Albright among its many illustrious guests. In 2023 and 2024, the show will focus on the 100-year history of American democracy between 1924 and 2024. Andrew wrote and produced the 2020, "How to Fix Democracy", movie, a documentary about democracy shot in Greece, Germany, the United Kingdom, and the United States. He also presents, "Keen on Democracy", a popular podcast show that gets several million downloads and views a year. He is the author of four acclaimed books on the relationship between technology and democracy, including the best-selling "Cult of the Amateur" and "The Internet Is Not the Answer." Andrew studied contemporary history and politics at the Universities of London and Berkeley. He is currently working on a book about democracy in America.</p>
<p><strong>Alina Polyakova</strong><br><span data-contrast="auto">Dr. Alina Polyakova is President and CEO of the Center for European Policy Analysis (CEPA) as well as the Donald Marron Senior Fellow at the Henry A. Kissinger Center for Global Affairs at the Johns Hopkins University’s School of Advanced International Studies (SAIS).</span>
<span data-contrast="auto">Dr. Polyakova is a recognized expert on transatlantic relations, European security including Russia and Ukraine, tech policy, and populism. She is the author of the book, The Dark Side of European Integration, which examines the rise of far-right political movements in Europe, as well as dozens of major policy reports and articles in outlets such as The Washington Post, The New York Times, The Wall Street Journal, Foreign Affairs, and The Atlantic, and others. She is a frequent commentator in major media outlets, such as Fox News, CNN, and BBC.</span>
<span data-contrast="auto">Dr. Polyakova is an experienced leader with previous roles as the Founding Director for Global Democracy and Emerging Technology at the Brookings Institution, Director of Research for Europe and Eurasia at the Atlantic Council, among others. She has also held numerous prestigious fellowships, including at the National Science Foundation, the Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars, and the Fulbright Foundation, among others. She serves on the board of the Free Russia Foundation and is a member of the Leadership Council for Women in National Security (LCWINS) and the Scientific Council of the Elcano Royal Institute.</span>
<span data-contrast="auto">Dr. Polyakova holds a Ph.D. and MA in Sociology from the University of California, Berkeley, and a BA in Economics and Sociology from Emory University.</span></p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Can Democracy Survive The Future Of Automation?</strong> <small>2018-05-22 15:50:06</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Can we all agree that Google Duplex demo was eerie? A robot, posing as a human being, scheduled a reservation over the phone. We all knew artificial intelligence was coming, but it was breathtaking to hear software come to life.</p>
<p>Before we go any further, let's get our terms straight. Automation and artificial intelligence are not the same thing. According to Dave Evans, "Automation is software that follows pre-programmed rules. Artificial intelligence is designed to simulate human thinking." Automation, in this context, refers to the impact of artificial intelligence on tasks that only humans can perform today.</p>
<p>Even if you're skeptical of Google Duplex in light of the current backlash, Alexa has made her way into millions of homes. Amazon and Google are proving the value of artificial intelligence to consumers. (Apple still has a ways to go with Siri.) While Alexa won’t take down the government, there was a recent debate about the impact of automation on democracy that's worth watching.</p>
<p>Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. features debates about current events. Each episode puts forward a provocative motion like “Automation Will Crash Democracy.” Two teams of two debate the motion. There are polls conducted at the beginning and at the end of the debate. A team wins by persuading audience members to change their opinion. Ian Bremmer and Yascha Mounk argued for the motion, insisting automation will crash democracy. Andrew Keen and Alina Polyakova argued against the motion.</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Automation Will Crash Democracy</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>The Rise of Populism</u></p>
<p><u>The State of Democracy</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Negotiations Can Denuclearize North Korea</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/negotiations-can-denuclearize-north-korea</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10318</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> May 02, 2018</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> World</p>
<p>How should the United States respond to North Korea’s rapidly advancing nuclear capabilities? Some experts suggest the upcoming summit between President Trump and Kim Jong-un might provide a pivotal diplomatic opportunity to persuade North Korea to give up its nuclear weapons – especially in light of the announcement of harsh new sanctions. But others are more pessimistic, arguing that we’ve been down this road before and that denuclearizing North Korea is more of a pipedream than a legitimate strategic goal. Can Trump and Kim strike a deal to halt North Korea’s nuclear aggression? Or will the talks inevitably fail, heightening tensions and increasing the likelihood of fatal miscalculations?
<em>Presented in partnership with Georgetown University, LIVE at the first Georgetown University Women’s Forum.</em></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/zM48y3NP-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/zM48y3NP-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Suzanne DiMaggio</strong><br>Suzanne DiMaggio is a director and senior fellow at New America, where she focuses on U.S. foreign policy, the Middle East, and Asia. She has been leading Track 1.5 and Track 2 diplomatic initiatives on regional security, terrorism, nonproliferation, and governance for nearly 20 years. DiMaggio is currently directing a U.S.-DPRK dialogue that has included several visits to North Korea, most recently in February 2017. As part of that process, she facilitated the first official discussions between the Trump administration and North Korean government representatives in Oslo in May 2017. Before joining New America, DiMaggio was the vice president of global policy programs at the Asia Society and the vice president of policy programs at the United Nations Association of the USA. She is a frequent commentator in the news media, and her op-eds have appeared in national and international press outlets.</p>
<p><strong>Bonnie Jenkins</strong><br>Ambassador Bonnie Jenkins is a non-resident senior fellow at the Brookings Institution, where she focuses on nuclear security, weapons of mass destruction, and geopolitics. In 2009, she was nominated by President Barack Obama as the Department of State’s Coordinator for Threat Reduction Programs in the Bureau of International Security and Nonproliferation. In her role, she promoted the coordination of Department of State Cooperative Threat Reduction and U.S. government programs in chemical, biological, nuclear, and radiological security and was the Department of State lead on the Nuclear Security Summit. Jenkins is the founder and president of Women of Color Advancing Peace and Security and has taught at Georgetown University Law School, where she earned an LL.M. in international and comparative law. A retired Naval Reserve officer, she completed a year-long deployment to U.S. Central Command and received numerous awards for her service.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Sue Mi Terry</strong><br>Sue Mi Terry is a senior fellow with the Korea Chair at the Center for Strategic and International Studies in Washington. Prior to joining CSIS, she had a long and distinguished career in academia, policymaking, and intelligence, serving as the deputy national intelligence officer for East Asia at the National Intelligence Council from 2009 to 2010, the director for Korea, Japan, and Oceanic affairs at the National Security Council from 2008 to 2009, and a senior analyst on Korean issues at the CIA from 2001 and 2008. She has received numerous awards for her leadership and mission support, including the CIA Foreign Language Award in 2008. Terry is a regular contributor to the Wall Street Journal, New York Times, Washington Post, Foreign Affairs, and other publications.</p>
<p><strong>Mira Rapp-Hooper</strong><br>Mira Rapp-Hooper is a senior research scholar at Yale Law School and a senior fellow at Yale’s Paul Tsai China Center. She studies and writes on U.S.-China relations and national security issues in Asia. Rapp-Hooper was formerly a senior fellow with the Asia-Pacific Security Program at the Center for a New American Security, a fellow with the Center for Strategic and International Studies Asia Program, and the director of the CSIS Asia Maritime Transparency Initiative. Rapp-Hooper’s academic writings have appeared in Political Science Quarterly, Security Studies, and Survival, and her analysis is published in The National Interest, Foreign Affairs, The Washington Quarterly, The New York Times, and The Washington Post. She is a David Rockefeller Fellow of the Trilateral Commission, an associate editor with the International Security Studies Forum, and a senior editor at War on the Rocks.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Open to Debate Presents: It’s Time to Expand Nuclear Power with Bill Nye</strong> <small>2023-02-08 18:52:41</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>On Thursday, January 23, Bill Nye takes the Open to Debate stage to kick off the veteran debate series’ spring season. Nye, a longtime fan who publicly changed his mind about GMOs after attending the 2014 Open to Debate on the subject, will offer a nuclear power explainer to introduce the nonprofit’s live debate on the motion “It’s Time to Expand Nuclear Power.”</p>
<p>Proponents claim that nuclear energy is the most effective way to combat climate change while still meeting the world’s growing demand for energy. But critics argue that expanding nuclear energy is dangerous, costly, and ill-advised. Should nuclear energy fuel our future? Arguing yes will be Daniel Poneman, Deputy Secretary of Energy under President Obama, and the co-founder of Energy for Humanity, Kirsty Gogan. Arguing against them will be former chairman of the US Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Gregory B. Jaczko, and the president of the Institute for Energy and Environmental Research, Arjun Makhijani.</p>
<p>The “It’s Time to Expand Nuclear Power” debate will mark Open to Debate debut at their new NYC home, the Florence Gould Hall, then air soon after as part of the syndicated public radio show, podcast, and video series “Open to Debate”</p>
<p>KEYNOTE SPEAKER</p>
<p>* Bill Nye: Scientist and CEO of the Planetary Society
Bill Nye, scientist, engineer, comedian, author, and inventor, is a man with a mission: to help foster a scientifically literate society and to help people everywhere understand and appreciate the science that makes our world work. After Nye attended a 2014 Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. debate on GMOs, he spent time with panelist Dr. Robert Fraley and publicly changed his mind on the topic. He is CEO of the Planetary Society, a space-interest group, and hosts the “Science Rules!” podcast. Nye is best known for hosting the children’s science show “Bill Nye the Science Guy,” “Bill Nye Saves the World,” and is the author of multiple bestselling books.</p>
<p>For the Motion</p>
<p>* Kirsty Gogan: Co-founder and Executive Director of Energy for Humanity
Kirsty Gogan is the co-founder and executive director of Energy for Humanity (EFH), an NGO focused on decarbonization and energy access. EFH led a delegation of climate scientists to defend nuclear energy at the Paris Climate Conference. A founding director of CleanTech Catalyst, Gogan has advised the UK government on nuclear power and evaluated the national response to Fukushima.</p>
<p>* Daniel Poneman: President and CEO of Centrus Energy
Daniel Poneman is a former government official and nuclear energy executive. Under President Obama, he was the Deputy Secretary of Energy and also served as a COO of the Department of Energy. He is now the president and CEO of Centrus Energy, a global energy company that supplies low enriched uranium for commercial nuclear power plants. He is a senior fellow at the Belfer Center for Science and International Affairs and author of the recent book “Double Jeopardy: Combating Nuclear Terror and Climate Change.”</p>
<p>Arguing Against the Motion</p>
<p>* Gregory B. Jaczko: Former Chairman of the US Nuclear Regulatory Commission
Gregory B. Jaczko is the former chairman of the US Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC), where he handled the American government’s response to the Fukushima meltdown. After leaving the NRC, he wrote “Confessions of A Nuclear Regulator” and founded the wind energy company Wind Future LLC.</p>
<p>* Arjun Makhijani: President of the Institute for Energy and Environmental Research
Arjun Makhijani is the president of the Institute for Energy and Environmental Research and the author of “Carbon-Free and Nuclear Free: A Roadmap for US Energy Policy.” He has spent decades studying nuclear disarmament and energy efficiency. Makhijani has a Ph.D. from University of California at Berkeley, where he specialized in nuclear fusion.</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Negotiations Can Denuclearize North Korea</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Denuclearization</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>In the Neighborhood</u></p>
<p><u>Kim Jong-un</u></p>
<p><u>Preemptive Strike & Prospects of War</u></p>
<p><u>Inside North Korea</u></p>
<p><u>Suki Kim</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> May 02, 2018</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> World</p>
<p>How should the United States respond to North Korea’s rapidly advancing nuclear capabilities? Some experts suggest the upcoming summit between President Trump and Kim Jong-un might provide a pivotal diplomatic opportunity to persuade North Korea to give up its nuclear weapons – especially in light of the announcement of harsh new sanctions. But others are more pessimistic, arguing that we’ve been down this road before and that denuclearizing North Korea is more of a pipedream than a legitimate strategic goal. Can Trump and Kim strike a deal to halt North Korea’s nuclear aggression? Or will the talks inevitably fail, heightening tensions and increasing the likelihood of fatal miscalculations?
<em>Presented in partnership with Georgetown University, LIVE at the first Georgetown University Women’s Forum.</em></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/zM48y3NP-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/zM48y3NP-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Suzanne DiMaggio</strong><br>Suzanne DiMaggio is a director and senior fellow at New America, where she focuses on U.S. foreign policy, the Middle East, and Asia. She has been leading Track 1.5 and Track 2 diplomatic initiatives on regional security, terrorism, nonproliferation, and governance for nearly 20 years. DiMaggio is currently directing a U.S.-DPRK dialogue that has included several visits to North Korea, most recently in February 2017. As part of that process, she facilitated the first official discussions between the Trump administration and North Korean government representatives in Oslo in May 2017. Before joining New America, DiMaggio was the vice president of global policy programs at the Asia Society and the vice president of policy programs at the United Nations Association of the USA. She is a frequent commentator in the news media, and her op-eds have appeared in national and international press outlets.</p>
<p><strong>Bonnie Jenkins</strong><br>Ambassador Bonnie Jenkins is a non-resident senior fellow at the Brookings Institution, where she focuses on nuclear security, weapons of mass destruction, and geopolitics. In 2009, she was nominated by President Barack Obama as the Department of State’s Coordinator for Threat Reduction Programs in the Bureau of International Security and Nonproliferation. In her role, she promoted the coordination of Department of State Cooperative Threat Reduction and U.S. government programs in chemical, biological, nuclear, and radiological security and was the Department of State lead on the Nuclear Security Summit. Jenkins is the founder and president of Women of Color Advancing Peace and Security and has taught at Georgetown University Law School, where she earned an LL.M. in international and comparative law. A retired Naval Reserve officer, she completed a year-long deployment to U.S. Central Command and received numerous awards for her service.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Sue Mi Terry</strong><br>Sue Mi Terry is a senior fellow with the Korea Chair at the Center for Strategic and International Studies in Washington. Prior to joining CSIS, she had a long and distinguished career in academia, policymaking, and intelligence, serving as the deputy national intelligence officer for East Asia at the National Intelligence Council from 2009 to 2010, the director for Korea, Japan, and Oceanic affairs at the National Security Council from 2008 to 2009, and a senior analyst on Korean issues at the CIA from 2001 and 2008. She has received numerous awards for her leadership and mission support, including the CIA Foreign Language Award in 2008. Terry is a regular contributor to the Wall Street Journal, New York Times, Washington Post, Foreign Affairs, and other publications.</p>
<p><strong>Mira Rapp-Hooper</strong><br>Mira Rapp-Hooper is a senior research scholar at Yale Law School and a senior fellow at Yale’s Paul Tsai China Center. She studies and writes on U.S.-China relations and national security issues in Asia. Rapp-Hooper was formerly a senior fellow with the Asia-Pacific Security Program at the Center for a New American Security, a fellow with the Center for Strategic and International Studies Asia Program, and the director of the CSIS Asia Maritime Transparency Initiative. Rapp-Hooper’s academic writings have appeared in Political Science Quarterly, Security Studies, and Survival, and her analysis is published in The National Interest, Foreign Affairs, The Washington Quarterly, The New York Times, and The Washington Post. She is a David Rockefeller Fellow of the Trilateral Commission, an associate editor with the International Security Studies Forum, and a senior editor at War on the Rocks.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Open to Debate Presents: It’s Time to Expand Nuclear Power with Bill Nye</strong> <small>2023-02-08 18:52:41</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>On Thursday, January 23, Bill Nye takes the Open to Debate stage to kick off the veteran debate series’ spring season. Nye, a longtime fan who publicly changed his mind about GMOs after attending the 2014 Open to Debate on the subject, will offer a nuclear power explainer to introduce the nonprofit’s live debate on the motion “It’s Time to Expand Nuclear Power.”</p>
<p>Proponents claim that nuclear energy is the most effective way to combat climate change while still meeting the world’s growing demand for energy. But critics argue that expanding nuclear energy is dangerous, costly, and ill-advised. Should nuclear energy fuel our future? Arguing yes will be Daniel Poneman, Deputy Secretary of Energy under President Obama, and the co-founder of Energy for Humanity, Kirsty Gogan. Arguing against them will be former chairman of the US Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Gregory B. Jaczko, and the president of the Institute for Energy and Environmental Research, Arjun Makhijani.</p>
<p>The “It’s Time to Expand Nuclear Power” debate will mark Open to Debate debut at their new NYC home, the Florence Gould Hall, then air soon after as part of the syndicated public radio show, podcast, and video series “Open to Debate”</p>
<p>KEYNOTE SPEAKER</p>
<p>* Bill Nye: Scientist and CEO of the Planetary Society
Bill Nye, scientist, engineer, comedian, author, and inventor, is a man with a mission: to help foster a scientifically literate society and to help people everywhere understand and appreciate the science that makes our world work. After Nye attended a 2014 Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. debate on GMOs, he spent time with panelist Dr. Robert Fraley and publicly changed his mind on the topic. He is CEO of the Planetary Society, a space-interest group, and hosts the “Science Rules!” podcast. Nye is best known for hosting the children’s science show “Bill Nye the Science Guy,” “Bill Nye Saves the World,” and is the author of multiple bestselling books.</p>
<p>For the Motion</p>
<p>* Kirsty Gogan: Co-founder and Executive Director of Energy for Humanity
Kirsty Gogan is the co-founder and executive director of Energy for Humanity (EFH), an NGO focused on decarbonization and energy access. EFH led a delegation of climate scientists to defend nuclear energy at the Paris Climate Conference. A founding director of CleanTech Catalyst, Gogan has advised the UK government on nuclear power and evaluated the national response to Fukushima.</p>
<p>* Daniel Poneman: President and CEO of Centrus Energy
Daniel Poneman is a former government official and nuclear energy executive. Under President Obama, he was the Deputy Secretary of Energy and also served as a COO of the Department of Energy. He is now the president and CEO of Centrus Energy, a global energy company that supplies low enriched uranium for commercial nuclear power plants. He is a senior fellow at the Belfer Center for Science and International Affairs and author of the recent book “Double Jeopardy: Combating Nuclear Terror and Climate Change.”</p>
<p>Arguing Against the Motion</p>
<p>* Gregory B. Jaczko: Former Chairman of the US Nuclear Regulatory Commission
Gregory B. Jaczko is the former chairman of the US Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC), where he handled the American government’s response to the Fukushima meltdown. After leaving the NRC, he wrote “Confessions of A Nuclear Regulator” and founded the wind energy company Wind Future LLC.</p>
<p>* Arjun Makhijani: President of the Institute for Energy and Environmental Research
Arjun Makhijani is the president of the Institute for Energy and Environmental Research and the author of “Carbon-Free and Nuclear Free: A Roadmap for US Energy Policy.” He has spent decades studying nuclear disarmament and energy efficiency. Makhijani has a Ph.D. from University of California at Berkeley, where he specialized in nuclear fusion.</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Negotiations Can Denuclearize North Korea</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Denuclearization</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>In the Neighborhood</u></p>
<p><u>Kim Jong-un</u></p>
<p><u>Preemptive Strike & Prospects of War</u></p>
<p><u>Inside North Korea</u></p>
<p><u>Suki Kim</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Bitcoin Is More Than a Bubble and Here to Stay</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/bitcoin-more-bubble-and-here-stay</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10023</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> April 21, 2018</p>
<p>Is Bitcoin here to stay, or is it a bubble waiting to pop? Less than a decade old, Bitcoin is worth billions. The cryptocurrency promises to revolutionize global finance by placing control of currency in the hands of users, not nations, and make financial exchanges more transparent, efficient, and democratic. And it seems to be taking hold: Earlier this year both the Cboe and CME debuted Bitcoin futures. But is Bitcoin really a safe bet? Proponents say the hype around the cryptocurrency is warranted, and previous critics – including executives at JPMorgan and Goldman Sachs – are increasingly jumping on the Bitcoin (block)train. On the other hand, skeptics suggest this highly volatile digital currency offers a platform for illicit activity, including money laundering and trafficking of humans and drugs, free from government oversight and regulation. And, they argue, Bitcoin has no intrinsic value – the price is based on market enthusiasm rather than actual utility. This debate is presented in partnership with the Adam Smith Society. The <a href="http://adamsmithsociety.com/">Adam Smith Society</a> — a project of the Manhattan Institute — is an expansive, chapter-based network of MBA students, professionals, and business leaders who work to foster debate about the moral, social, and economic benefits of capitalism.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/1U2CSDGG-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/1U2CSDGG-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Patrick Byrne</strong><br>Patrick Byrne is CEO and co-founder of the internet retail company <a href="http://Overstock.com">Overstock.com</a> and CEO of tZero, an ICO training platform he founded. Under his leadership, Overstock.com became the first business with more than $1 million in revenue to accept bitcoin as a payment method. Later, using the familiarity gained with the blockchain technology at the heart of digital currencies such as bitcoin, Byrne created Medici Ventures, a subsidiary within Overstock.com devoted to advancing blockchain-based technology solutions. In 2015, he used Medici’s <a href="https://to.com/">t0.com</a> securities trading platform to become the first person to purchase a digital bond entirely on the bitcoin blockchain.</p>
<p><strong>Tim Draper</strong><br>Tim Draper is a venture capital investor and the founder of Draper Associates and Draper Fisher Jurvetson. His original suggestion to use "viral marketing" in e-mail to geometrically spread an internet product to its market was instrumental to the successes of Hotmail, Skype, and Yahoo Mail. It has since been adopted as a standard marketing technique by hundreds of businesses. Draper has been recognized as a leader in his field through numerous awards and honors. He has been ranked 46th on the list of the 100 most influential Harvard alumni and 7th on the Forbes Midas List.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Eric Posner</strong><br>Eric Posner is a legal scholar and frequent media commentator, having written op-eds and columns for a number of national publications, including the Wall Street Journal and Slate. He is currently the Kirkland and Ellis Distinguished Service Professor of Law at the University of Chicago. Posner is the author of several books, including "Radical Markets: Uprooting Capitalism and Democracy for a Just Society," which will be published in May. Posner is a fellow of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences and a member of the American Law Institute.</p>
<p><strong>Gillian Tett</strong><br>Gillian Tett is chair of the editorial board and U.S. editor-at-large of the Financial Times, where she oversees global coverage of the financial markets. An award-winning journalist and best-selling author, Tett is also the co-founder of "Moral Money," a twice-weekly newsletter on socially responsible business. Her most recent book, "The Silo Effect," analyzes the financial system through the lens of cultural anthropology. She has been named Columnist of the Year (2014), Journalist of the Year (2009), and Business Journalist of the Year (2008) in the British Press Awards and received three awards from America's Society of Business and Economic Writers Awards. She is a best-selling author and has received the Royal Anthropological Institute Marsh Award and the American Anthropological Association President Medal for her work in social science.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Bitcoin Is More Than a Bubble and Here to Stay</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Regulations</u></p>
<p><u>Mining Coins</u></p>
<p><u>Blockchain Technology</u></p>
<p><u>Bitcoin Around the World</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> April 21, 2018</p>
<p>Is Bitcoin here to stay, or is it a bubble waiting to pop? Less than a decade old, Bitcoin is worth billions. The cryptocurrency promises to revolutionize global finance by placing control of currency in the hands of users, not nations, and make financial exchanges more transparent, efficient, and democratic. And it seems to be taking hold: Earlier this year both the Cboe and CME debuted Bitcoin futures. But is Bitcoin really a safe bet? Proponents say the hype around the cryptocurrency is warranted, and previous critics – including executives at JPMorgan and Goldman Sachs – are increasingly jumping on the Bitcoin (block)train. On the other hand, skeptics suggest this highly volatile digital currency offers a platform for illicit activity, including money laundering and trafficking of humans and drugs, free from government oversight and regulation. And, they argue, Bitcoin has no intrinsic value – the price is based on market enthusiasm rather than actual utility. This debate is presented in partnership with the Adam Smith Society. The <a href="http://adamsmithsociety.com/">Adam Smith Society</a> — a project of the Manhattan Institute — is an expansive, chapter-based network of MBA students, professionals, and business leaders who work to foster debate about the moral, social, and economic benefits of capitalism.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/1U2CSDGG-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/1U2CSDGG-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Patrick Byrne</strong><br>Patrick Byrne is CEO and co-founder of the internet retail company <a href="http://Overstock.com">Overstock.com</a> and CEO of tZero, an ICO training platform he founded. Under his leadership, Overstock.com became the first business with more than $1 million in revenue to accept bitcoin as a payment method. Later, using the familiarity gained with the blockchain technology at the heart of digital currencies such as bitcoin, Byrne created Medici Ventures, a subsidiary within Overstock.com devoted to advancing blockchain-based technology solutions. In 2015, he used Medici’s <a href="https://to.com/">t0.com</a> securities trading platform to become the first person to purchase a digital bond entirely on the bitcoin blockchain.</p>
<p><strong>Tim Draper</strong><br>Tim Draper is a venture capital investor and the founder of Draper Associates and Draper Fisher Jurvetson. His original suggestion to use "viral marketing" in e-mail to geometrically spread an internet product to its market was instrumental to the successes of Hotmail, Skype, and Yahoo Mail. It has since been adopted as a standard marketing technique by hundreds of businesses. Draper has been recognized as a leader in his field through numerous awards and honors. He has been ranked 46th on the list of the 100 most influential Harvard alumni and 7th on the Forbes Midas List.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Eric Posner</strong><br>Eric Posner is a legal scholar and frequent media commentator, having written op-eds and columns for a number of national publications, including the Wall Street Journal and Slate. He is currently the Kirkland and Ellis Distinguished Service Professor of Law at the University of Chicago. Posner is the author of several books, including "Radical Markets: Uprooting Capitalism and Democracy for a Just Society," which will be published in May. Posner is a fellow of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences and a member of the American Law Institute.</p>
<p><strong>Gillian Tett</strong><br>Gillian Tett is chair of the editorial board and U.S. editor-at-large of the Financial Times, where she oversees global coverage of the financial markets. An award-winning journalist and best-selling author, Tett is also the co-founder of "Moral Money," a twice-weekly newsletter on socially responsible business. Her most recent book, "The Silo Effect," analyzes the financial system through the lens of cultural anthropology. She has been named Columnist of the Year (2014), Journalist of the Year (2009), and Business Journalist of the Year (2008) in the British Press Awards and received three awards from America's Society of Business and Economic Writers Awards. She is a best-selling author and has received the Royal Anthropological Institute Marsh Award and the American Anthropological Association President Medal for her work in social science.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Bitcoin Is More Than a Bubble and Here to Stay</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Regulations</u></p>
<p><u>Mining Coins</u></p>
<p><u>Blockchain Technology</u></p>
<p><u>Bitcoin Around the World</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Preserve Net Neutrality: All Data is Created Equal</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/preserve-net-neutrality-all-data-created-equal</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10387</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> April 17, 2018</p>
<p>What if a single policy could impact American democracy, culture, and competitiveness?  What if that policy might either empower citizens and consumers, or burden them?  And what if the decision on that policy sparked a frenzy of legislative proposals, judicial challenges, and citizen outrage, all across the country?
The Federal Communications Commission’s decision to end net neutrality regulations has fueled a national debate about the future of the internet.  Adopted in 2015, net neutrality promised to preserve the democratic spirit of the web by ensuring that all data would be treated equally, regardless of where it originated. Under these regulations, internet service providers (ISPs) such as Verizon, Comcast and AT&T, the corporate giants who deliver the internet into our homes, could supply web infrastructure, but could not preference how data passed through it.  Denying them that power, supporters argue, remains critical to ensuring that users and content-creators can discover ideas and information without censorship, or charges, from these prospective gatekeepers.  After all, no person should have to pay for every video streamed on YouTube; no startup should be hobbled against established companies who buy faster access to consumers; and no minority voice should have its ideas throttled by wealthier interests.
On the other hand, net neutrality opponents argue that the genius of the Internet has been its individually driven, organic development, free from the heavy hand of so-called net neutrality.  These burdensome regulations constitute dangerous governmental overreach, stifle innovation, and spike costs for both consumers and providers.  The result, they maintain, will be a less interesting, less democratic, less innovative web.  Moreover, Americans will enjoy uninterrupted access to their favorite sites – without net neutrality – because ISPs make more money from an open, rather than closed, internet.  Consequently, the backlash against the FCC’s decision is overblown, and ending net neutrality is the right policy for the future of America’s internet.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/QeRMIStm-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/QeRMIStm-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Mitchell Baker</strong><br>Mitchell Baker is chairwoman of the Mozilla Corporation and Foundation. She is a strong advocate for the open web and open source applications and is highly regarded as one of the pioneers responsible for designing the web into what it is today. Baker was instrumental in Netscape’s 1998 decision to release its source code to the public. This led to the release of the Firefox browser and the creation of the Mozilla Project, one of the most influential technology organizations in the world. Time magazine has included Baker in its global list of the 100 most influential people, and Bloomberg listed her as one of the 25 most influential people on the web.</p>
<p><strong>Tom Wheeler</strong><br>Tom Wheeler is a businessman, author, and former chairman of the Federal Communications Commission. He led the FCC's efforts that resulted in the adoption of net neutrality, privacy protections for consumers, and increased cybersecurity, among other policies. His chairmanship has been described as "the most productive commission in the history of the agency." From 1979 to 1984, he was president and CEO of the National Cable Television Association. He is currently a fellow at the Brookings Institution and the Harvard Kennedy School.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Nick Gillespie</strong><br>Nick Gillespie is the editor-at-large of Reason, the libertarian magazine of "free minds and free markets," and the host of The Reason Interview podcast with Nick Gillespie. A two-time finalist for the digital National Magazine Awards, he is co-author of "The Declaration of Independents: How Libertarian Politics Can Fix What's Wrong with America" and holds a Ph.D. in American literature.
Full bio is available <a href="https://reason.com/people/nick-gillespie/">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Michael Katz</strong><br>Michael Katz is a professor at Berkeley and a member of the Economic Analysis and Policy Group at the Haas School of Business. He was previously the chief economist for the Federal Communications Commission, where he received the Chairman's Special Achievement Award. He has also served as deputy assistant attorney general for economic analysis in the antitrust division of the Department of Justice. He is a two-time recipient of the Earl F. Cheit Award for Excellence in Teaching and was an Alfred P. Sloan Research Fellow.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Preserve Net Neutrality: All Data Is Created Equal</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Current Events</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Responses From ISPs & Tech Giants</u></p>
<p><u>Polls & Public Opinion</u></p>
<p><u>Economic Implications</u></p>
<p><u>Consumer Implications</u></p>
<p><u>International Perspectives</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> April 17, 2018</p>
<p>What if a single policy could impact American democracy, culture, and competitiveness?  What if that policy might either empower citizens and consumers, or burden them?  And what if the decision on that policy sparked a frenzy of legislative proposals, judicial challenges, and citizen outrage, all across the country?
The Federal Communications Commission’s decision to end net neutrality regulations has fueled a national debate about the future of the internet.  Adopted in 2015, net neutrality promised to preserve the democratic spirit of the web by ensuring that all data would be treated equally, regardless of where it originated. Under these regulations, internet service providers (ISPs) such as Verizon, Comcast and AT&T, the corporate giants who deliver the internet into our homes, could supply web infrastructure, but could not preference how data passed through it.  Denying them that power, supporters argue, remains critical to ensuring that users and content-creators can discover ideas and information without censorship, or charges, from these prospective gatekeepers.  After all, no person should have to pay for every video streamed on YouTube; no startup should be hobbled against established companies who buy faster access to consumers; and no minority voice should have its ideas throttled by wealthier interests.
On the other hand, net neutrality opponents argue that the genius of the Internet has been its individually driven, organic development, free from the heavy hand of so-called net neutrality.  These burdensome regulations constitute dangerous governmental overreach, stifle innovation, and spike costs for both consumers and providers.  The result, they maintain, will be a less interesting, less democratic, less innovative web.  Moreover, Americans will enjoy uninterrupted access to their favorite sites – without net neutrality – because ISPs make more money from an open, rather than closed, internet.  Consequently, the backlash against the FCC’s decision is overblown, and ending net neutrality is the right policy for the future of America’s internet.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/QeRMIStm-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/QeRMIStm-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Mitchell Baker</strong><br>Mitchell Baker is chairwoman of the Mozilla Corporation and Foundation. She is a strong advocate for the open web and open source applications and is highly regarded as one of the pioneers responsible for designing the web into what it is today. Baker was instrumental in Netscape’s 1998 decision to release its source code to the public. This led to the release of the Firefox browser and the creation of the Mozilla Project, one of the most influential technology organizations in the world. Time magazine has included Baker in its global list of the 100 most influential people, and Bloomberg listed her as one of the 25 most influential people on the web.</p>
<p><strong>Tom Wheeler</strong><br>Tom Wheeler is a businessman, author, and former chairman of the Federal Communications Commission. He led the FCC's efforts that resulted in the adoption of net neutrality, privacy protections for consumers, and increased cybersecurity, among other policies. His chairmanship has been described as "the most productive commission in the history of the agency." From 1979 to 1984, he was president and CEO of the National Cable Television Association. He is currently a fellow at the Brookings Institution and the Harvard Kennedy School.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Nick Gillespie</strong><br>Nick Gillespie is the editor-at-large of Reason, the libertarian magazine of "free minds and free markets," and the host of The Reason Interview podcast with Nick Gillespie. A two-time finalist for the digital National Magazine Awards, he is co-author of "The Declaration of Independents: How Libertarian Politics Can Fix What's Wrong with America" and holds a Ph.D. in American literature.
Full bio is available <a href="https://reason.com/people/nick-gillespie/">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Michael Katz</strong><br>Michael Katz is a professor at Berkeley and a member of the Economic Analysis and Policy Group at the Haas School of Business. He was previously the chief economist for the Federal Communications Commission, where he received the Chairman's Special Achievement Award. He has also served as deputy assistant attorney general for economic analysis in the antitrust division of the Department of Justice. He is a two-time recipient of the Earl F. Cheit Award for Excellence in Teaching and was an Alfred P. Sloan Research Fellow.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Preserve Net Neutrality: All Data Is Created Equal</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Current Events</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Responses From ISPs & Tech Giants</u></p>
<p><u>Polls & Public Opinion</u></p>
<p><u>Economic Implications</u></p>
<p><u>Consumer Implications</u></p>
<p><u>International Perspectives</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The More We Evolve, The Less We Need God</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/more-we-evolve-less-we-need-god</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10254</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> March 27, 2018</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Religion, Science</p>
<p>Does God have a place in 21st century human affairs? For many, the answer is an unapologetic yes. Belief in a higher power, they argue, is the foundation of human consciousness and the soul of all social, political, and scientific progress. Further, some claim, humans are biologically predisposed to embrace religion and require faith to live moral lives. Others are far more skeptical. For them, adherence to faith and religious tradition serves only to fracture communities and prevent humanity from embracing a more enlightened, reasoned, and just social order. As we look to the future in uncertain times, should spirituality and religion play a central role in human evolution, innovation, and discovery? Or has God become obsolete?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/GoIj7yBI-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/GoIj7yBI-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Heather Berlin</strong><br>Heather Berlin, Ph.D., M.P.H., is a cognitive neuroscientist and assistant professor of psychiatry at the Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai. She practices clinical neuropsychology at Weill Cornell Medicine in the Department of Neurological Surgery and is a visiting scholar at the New York Psychoanalytic Society and Institute. She explores the neural basis of psychiatric and neurological disorders, consciousness, dynamic unconscious processes, and creativity. Passionate about science communication, she is a founding committee member of the National Academy of Sciences’ Science and Entertainment Exchange, host of "Startalk All-Stars" with Neil DeGrasse Tyson, and has hosted series on PBS and the Discovery Channel.</p>
<p><strong>Michael Shermer</strong><br>Michael Shermer is the publisher of Skeptic magazine, a monthly columnist for Scientific American, and a Presidential Fellow at Chapman University. He is the best-selling author of several books, including “The Moral Arc: How Science and Reason Lead Humanity Toward Truth, Justice, and Freedom.<em>” </em>As a public intellectual, he regularly contributes op-eds, book reviews, and essays to the Wall Street Journal, Los Angeles Times, Science, Nature, and other publications. His two TED talks, viewed nearly 8 million times, were voted in the top 100 of the more than 2,000 TED talks.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Deepak Chopra</strong><br>Deepak Chopra, M.D., founder of the Chopra Foundation, is a world-renowned pioneer in integrative medicine and personal transformation. He is board certified in internal medicine, endocrinology, and metabolism. Chopra is also a fellow of the American College of Physicians and a clinical professor of medicine at the University of California, San Diego. Time magazine has described Chopra as "one of the top 100 heroes and icons of the century." The World Post and HuffPost global internet survey ranked Chopra as "the #17 influential thinker in the world and #1 in medicine." Chopra has written more than 85 books translated into over 43 languages, including 25 New York Times best-sellers. In his recent national best-seller, "The Healing Self," he and Rudolph E. Tanzi tackle the issue of lifelong health and heightened immunity.</p>
<p><strong>Anoop Kumar</strong><br>Anoop Kumar, M.D., is a board-certified emergency physician practicing in the Washington, D.C., metro area, where he also leads meditation gatherings for clinicians. He is a frequent public speaker and the author of "Michelangelo’s Medicine: How Redefining the Human Body Will Transform Health and Healthcare." As a child, Kumar was surrounded by the teachings of Eastern philosophy. He came to recognize a common message woven through philosophy, science, and spirituality — a practical message of well-being cloaked in esoteric language. His passion is translating this message into modern applications.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>The More We Evolve, The Less We Need God</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Current Events</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> March 27, 2018</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Religion, Science</p>
<p>Does God have a place in 21st century human affairs? For many, the answer is an unapologetic yes. Belief in a higher power, they argue, is the foundation of human consciousness and the soul of all social, political, and scientific progress. Further, some claim, humans are biologically predisposed to embrace religion and require faith to live moral lives. Others are far more skeptical. For them, adherence to faith and religious tradition serves only to fracture communities and prevent humanity from embracing a more enlightened, reasoned, and just social order. As we look to the future in uncertain times, should spirituality and religion play a central role in human evolution, innovation, and discovery? Or has God become obsolete?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/GoIj7yBI-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/GoIj7yBI-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Heather Berlin</strong><br>Heather Berlin, Ph.D., M.P.H., is a cognitive neuroscientist and assistant professor of psychiatry at the Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai. She practices clinical neuropsychology at Weill Cornell Medicine in the Department of Neurological Surgery and is a visiting scholar at the New York Psychoanalytic Society and Institute. She explores the neural basis of psychiatric and neurological disorders, consciousness, dynamic unconscious processes, and creativity. Passionate about science communication, she is a founding committee member of the National Academy of Sciences’ Science and Entertainment Exchange, host of "Startalk All-Stars" with Neil DeGrasse Tyson, and has hosted series on PBS and the Discovery Channel.</p>
<p><strong>Michael Shermer</strong><br>Michael Shermer is the publisher of Skeptic magazine, a monthly columnist for Scientific American, and a Presidential Fellow at Chapman University. He is the best-selling author of several books, including “The Moral Arc: How Science and Reason Lead Humanity Toward Truth, Justice, and Freedom.<em>” </em>As a public intellectual, he regularly contributes op-eds, book reviews, and essays to the Wall Street Journal, Los Angeles Times, Science, Nature, and other publications. His two TED talks, viewed nearly 8 million times, were voted in the top 100 of the more than 2,000 TED talks.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Deepak Chopra</strong><br>Deepak Chopra, M.D., founder of the Chopra Foundation, is a world-renowned pioneer in integrative medicine and personal transformation. He is board certified in internal medicine, endocrinology, and metabolism. Chopra is also a fellow of the American College of Physicians and a clinical professor of medicine at the University of California, San Diego. Time magazine has described Chopra as "one of the top 100 heroes and icons of the century." The World Post and HuffPost global internet survey ranked Chopra as "the #17 influential thinker in the world and #1 in medicine." Chopra has written more than 85 books translated into over 43 languages, including 25 New York Times best-sellers. In his recent national best-seller, "The Healing Self," he and Rudolph E. Tanzi tackle the issue of lifelong health and heightened immunity.</p>
<p><strong>Anoop Kumar</strong><br>Anoop Kumar, M.D., is a board-certified emergency physician practicing in the Washington, D.C., metro area, where he also leads meditation gatherings for clinicians. He is a frequent public speaker and the author of "Michelangelo’s Medicine: How Redefining the Human Body Will Transform Health and Healthcare." As a child, Kumar was surrounded by the teachings of Eastern philosophy. He came to recognize a common message woven through philosophy, science, and spirituality — a practical message of well-being cloaked in esoteric language. His passion is translating this message into modern applications.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>The More We Evolve, The Less We Need God</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Current Events</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Humanitarian Intervention Does More Harm Than Good</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/humanitarian-intervention-does-more-harm-good</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10161</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> March 09, 2018</p>
<p>The international community currently faces a global refugee crisis and mass atrocities in Iraq, Myanmar, Syria, Yemen, and beyond. How should the West respond?
Proponents of humanitarian intervention – the use of force to halt human rights abuses – argue that the world’s most powerful militaries have a responsibility to protect innocent civilians around the world. Beyond saving lives, they argue, intervention deters would-be abusers and ensures global stability, thereby strengthening the liberal world order. But opponents argue that military intervention is thinly veiled Western imperialism, and subsequently, an assault on state sovereignty. And, it’s ineffective: the West, with its military might, increases the death toll and worsens the conflicts it sets out to solve. Further, given recent waves of populism in the U.S., France, and U.K., they suggest that Western nations should spend their time looking inward rather than policing activity around the world.  This debate is presented in partnership with <a href="http://brussels.gmfus.org/">The German Marshall Fund's Brussels Forum</a>, broadcast live from Brussels, Belgium.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/n2e0uct1-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/n2e0uct1-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Frank Ledwidge</strong><br>Frank Ledwidge is a senior fellow at the Royal Air Force College and a former military intelligence officer. He spent fifteen years at the front end of British foreign policy, dealing with issues such as torture, human trafficking, and war crimes. In Kosovo, Albania, the former Soviet Union, Afghanistan, and Ethiopia, Ledwidge advised governments on international human rights protection, criminal law reform, and institution building. In Libya, he worked on stabilization during and after the conflict, focusing on justice and security. Prior to that, he was a barrister in Liverpool and throughout the North of England. He is the author of several well-reviewed books, including "Losing Small Wars" and "Investment in Blood," and is a regular commentator on national and international print and broadcast media, including the BBC, The Guardian, Al Jazeera, and BBC Radio.</p>
<p><strong>Rajan Menon</strong><br>Rajan Menon is an author and scholar who has held several esteemed teaching positions at Columbia University, the City College of New York, Vanderbilt University, and others. He is the author of several books, including "The Conceit of Humanitarian Intervention," which offers a wide-ranging critique of the ideology underlying military intervention. Rajan has been a fellow at the New American Foundation, a senior adviser for the Carnegia Corporation, and a senior fellow at the Council on Foreign Relations. His current work concerns American foreign and national security policy, international security, and globalization.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.ccny.cuny.edu/profiles/rajan-menon">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Bernard Kouchner</strong><br>Bernard Kouchner, a medical doctor by training, is the co-founder and former president of Médecins Sans Frontières (Doctors Without Borders). Kouchner, the first person to challenge the Red Cross's stance of neutrality and silence in wars and massacres, has played an important role in international humanitarian efforts for more than 20 years. As France's minister of health and humanitarian affairs, he convinced the UN to accept "the right to interfere" resolution, and after devastating civil wars in the Balkans, he served as a special representative to UN Secretary General Kofi Annan in Kosovo. He is the author of several books and the co-founder of the news magazines L'Evénement and Actuel. He is the recipient of several human rights awards, including the Dag Hammarskjold Prize and the Prix Europa.</p>
<p><strong>Kori Schake</strong><br>Kori Schake is a senior fellow and the director of foreign and defense policy studies at the American Enterprise Institute (AEI). Dr. Schake is the former deputy director-general of the International Institute for Strategic Studies in London. She has worked at the U.S. State Department, the U.S. Department of Defense, and the National Security Council at the White House. Author of five books, most recently "America vs. the West: Can the Liberal World Order Be Preserved?" Dr. Schake is widely published in policy journals and the popular press. She has a doctorate in government and politics from the University of Maryland.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Humanitarian Intervention Does More Harm Than Good</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Non-Western Interventions</u></p>
<p><u>Women & Intervention</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Costs of Intervention</u></p>
<p><u>Responsibility to Protect, Sovereignty & International Law</u></p>
<p><u>Refugees & Intervention</u></p>
<p><u>Terrorism & Intervention</u></p>
<p><u>China, Russia & the Politics of Intervention</u></p>
<p><u>Post-9/11 Case Studies</u></p>
<p><u>Pre-9/11 Case Studies</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> March 09, 2018</p>
<p>The international community currently faces a global refugee crisis and mass atrocities in Iraq, Myanmar, Syria, Yemen, and beyond. How should the West respond?
Proponents of humanitarian intervention – the use of force to halt human rights abuses – argue that the world’s most powerful militaries have a responsibility to protect innocent civilians around the world. Beyond saving lives, they argue, intervention deters would-be abusers and ensures global stability, thereby strengthening the liberal world order. But opponents argue that military intervention is thinly veiled Western imperialism, and subsequently, an assault on state sovereignty. And, it’s ineffective: the West, with its military might, increases the death toll and worsens the conflicts it sets out to solve. Further, given recent waves of populism in the U.S., France, and U.K., they suggest that Western nations should spend their time looking inward rather than policing activity around the world.  This debate is presented in partnership with <a href="http://brussels.gmfus.org/">The German Marshall Fund's Brussels Forum</a>, broadcast live from Brussels, Belgium.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/n2e0uct1-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/n2e0uct1-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Frank Ledwidge</strong><br>Frank Ledwidge is a senior fellow at the Royal Air Force College and a former military intelligence officer. He spent fifteen years at the front end of British foreign policy, dealing with issues such as torture, human trafficking, and war crimes. In Kosovo, Albania, the former Soviet Union, Afghanistan, and Ethiopia, Ledwidge advised governments on international human rights protection, criminal law reform, and institution building. In Libya, he worked on stabilization during and after the conflict, focusing on justice and security. Prior to that, he was a barrister in Liverpool and throughout the North of England. He is the author of several well-reviewed books, including "Losing Small Wars" and "Investment in Blood," and is a regular commentator on national and international print and broadcast media, including the BBC, The Guardian, Al Jazeera, and BBC Radio.</p>
<p><strong>Rajan Menon</strong><br>Rajan Menon is an author and scholar who has held several esteemed teaching positions at Columbia University, the City College of New York, Vanderbilt University, and others. He is the author of several books, including "The Conceit of Humanitarian Intervention," which offers a wide-ranging critique of the ideology underlying military intervention. Rajan has been a fellow at the New American Foundation, a senior adviser for the Carnegia Corporation, and a senior fellow at the Council on Foreign Relations. His current work concerns American foreign and national security policy, international security, and globalization.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.ccny.cuny.edu/profiles/rajan-menon">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Bernard Kouchner</strong><br>Bernard Kouchner, a medical doctor by training, is the co-founder and former president of Médecins Sans Frontières (Doctors Without Borders). Kouchner, the first person to challenge the Red Cross's stance of neutrality and silence in wars and massacres, has played an important role in international humanitarian efforts for more than 20 years. As France's minister of health and humanitarian affairs, he convinced the UN to accept "the right to interfere" resolution, and after devastating civil wars in the Balkans, he served as a special representative to UN Secretary General Kofi Annan in Kosovo. He is the author of several books and the co-founder of the news magazines L'Evénement and Actuel. He is the recipient of several human rights awards, including the Dag Hammarskjold Prize and the Prix Europa.</p>
<p><strong>Kori Schake</strong><br>Kori Schake is a senior fellow and the director of foreign and defense policy studies at the American Enterprise Institute (AEI). Dr. Schake is the former deputy director-general of the International Institute for Strategic Studies in London. She has worked at the U.S. State Department, the U.S. Department of Defense, and the National Security Council at the White House. Author of five books, most recently "America vs. the West: Can the Liberal World Order Be Preserved?" Dr. Schake is widely published in policy journals and the popular press. She has a doctorate in government and politics from the University of Maryland.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Humanitarian Intervention Does More Harm Than Good</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Non-Western Interventions</u></p>
<p><u>Women & Intervention</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Costs of Intervention</u></p>
<p><u>Responsibility to Protect, Sovereignty & International Law</u></p>
<p><u>Refugees & Intervention</u></p>
<p><u>Terrorism & Intervention</u></p>
<p><u>China, Russia & the Politics of Intervention</u></p>
<p><u>Post-9/11 Case Studies</u></p>
<p><u>Pre-9/11 Case Studies</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Have Dating Apps Killed Romance?</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/swipe-left-dating-apps-have-killed-romance</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10172</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> February 06, 2018</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Culture, Tech</p>
<p>Every day millions of people turn to dating apps to find love. To date, more than 49 million Americans have given digital dating a try and the companies facilitating these matches are raking in billions. But are dating apps really designed to promote long-lasting romance? Apps like Tinder and Bumble make finding a date as easy as swiping right, while digital platforms like Match.com and OkCupid use specialized algorithms to help users find the perfect partner, regardless of age or personal preferences. Further, a range of niche sites connect people with highly specific interests, whether it’s single parenthood, a gluten-free lifestyle, or a devotion to Ayn Rand. But some argue that online dating is rife with sexism, racism, and misogyny, and that dating apps ultimately create a culture that prioritizes sex over committed and lasting love. After all, why settle on one match when there may be someone better just a swipe away?
To view the full debate visit <a href="https://www.wondrium.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wondrium.</a></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/DmxfA9WO-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/DmxfA9WO-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Eric Klinenberg</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO139068403 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO139068403 BCX0">Eric Klinenberg is a professor of sociology and director of the Institute for Public Knowledge at New York University. He is a co-author of "Modern Romance", which investigates the nature of dating in the digital era. Klinenberg is also the author of "Going Solo: The Extraordinary Rise and Surprising Appeal of Living Alone." His scholarly work has been published in academic journals including the American Sociological Review, Theory and Society, and Ethnography. He has contributed to numerous leading news platforms as well as the radio program, "This American Life."</span></span></p>
<p><strong>Manoush Zomorodi</strong><br>Manoush Zomorodi is the host and managing editor of Note to Self, "the tech show about being human," from WNYC Studios. She has won numerous awards for her work, including four from the New York Press Club. In 2014, the Alliance for Women in Media named her Outstanding Host. Zomorodi is the author of "Bored and Brilliant: How Spacing Out Can Unlock Your Most Productive and Creative Self." She is a self-proclaimed relentless examiner of the modern human condition.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Helen Fisher</strong><br><span data-contrast="none">Helen Fisher, PhD, a biological anthropologist, is a senior research fellow at The Kinsey Institute at Indiana University, a member of the Center for Human Evolutionary Studies at Rutgers University, and Chief Scientific Adviser to Match.com. She uses brain scanning (fMRI) to study the neural systems associated with romantic love, attachment, and partner happiness. She has written six internationally best-selling books on courtship, romantic love, and future sex, including "Why We Love, Why Him? Why Her?", and "Anatomy of Love." Fisher is also the co-founder of NeuroColor, where she is a pioneer in examining the neurochemistry of business team-building, innovation, and leadership.</span></p>
<p><strong>Tom Jacques</strong><br>Tom Jacques is vice president of engineering at OkCupid, a leading dating site that boasts more than 3.5 million users and sees over seven million messages exchanged per day. OkCupid, which relies on a dating algorithm to determine digital matches, was recently deemed the site most likely to appear in the New York Times’ marriage announcements, ranking above Tinder, <a href="https://www.match.com/">Match.com</a>, and eHarmony. As a software engineer, Tom engages in data analysis designed to make dating more efficient and less time-consuming. He is a graduate of Carnegie Mellon University.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Should People Date AI? Thao Ha Says ‘Yes, But…’</strong> <small>2025-07-10 12:03:53</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Key Takeaways</p>
<p>At an Open to Debate event, Professor Thao Ha explained why she argued “yes” to the question “Could dating an AI be better than dating a human?” (https://www.datingnews.com/movers-and-shakers/should-people-date-ai-thao-ha-debate/#Debate)
 Ha emphasized the healing potential of AI as a tool in romantic relationships, especially for adolescents experiencing confusing feelings. (https://www.datingnews.com/movers-and-shakers/should-people-date-ai-thao-ha-debate/#AI)
 Adults in vulnerable situations, such as caregivers and clashing couples, can use AI and VR to work through emotional obstacles. (https://www.datingnews.com/movers-and-shakers/should-people-date-ai-thao-ha-debate/#emotional)</p>
<p>At June 10th’s Open to Debate event (https://mailchi.mp/opentodebate.org/debatecould-dating-an-ai-be-better-than-a-human-2686564?e=23379795b6) in New York City, dating industry pros asked the question on everybody’s lips: Could dating an AI be better than dating a human?</p>
<p>Thao Ha (https://search.asu.edu/profile/2162867), Associate Professor of Psychology at Arizona State University, argued “yes”, while Justin Garcia, Executive Director & Senior Scientist at the Kinsey Institute and Chief Scientific Advisor to Match.com (http://match.com/), argued “no.”
In the overarching AI debate in the dating industry, the greatest fear is that AI will come to replace the uniquely human ability to love. Ha’s claim that dating an AI bot (https://www.datingnews.com/uncategorized/what-are-bots/) could, in some ways, be preferable to dating a human being is certainly controversial.</p>
<p>After the debate, DatingNews spoke to Ha about her unconventional viewpoint, and the surprising benefits of connecting emotionally with AI.</p>
<p>To “Date” AI is to Use it as a Romantic Tool
Ha is the director of the @HEART lab (https://search.asu.edu/profile/2162867) (Healthy Experiences Across Relationships and Transitions), which studies a buzzy topic: The mental, emotional, and social impacts AI has on adolescent relationships.</p>
<p>On the “pro” side of the debate, Ha argues that intuitive tech, like VR and AI, have the potential to ease loneliness and meet short-term emotional needs. For people who struggle to make satisfying in-person connections, AI and VR could be transformative tools.</p>
<p>When dating someone in real life isn’t an option — which, for some people, it isn’t — developing an emotional attachment to an AI bot could help satisfy several crucial emotional needs: the need to explore one’s romantic and sexual feelings in a healthy way, or to express thoughts and feelings without judgement, for example.</p>
<p>Ha doesn’t advocate for no-holds-barred access to AI. Instead, she argues that people, and the platforms that use AI, should promote a healthy balance between IRL and AI connections.</p>
<p>“It’s not my goal that everybody’s going to start dating AI,” she told us. On the contrary, Ha simply wants to acknowledge the potential AI has as a therapeutic tool, particularly for vulnerable groups, like adolescents and struggling couples.
As someone who specifically studies AI’s impact on adolescent relationships, Ha warns against offering shortcuts to human connection to people at such an impressionable age.</p>
<p>“Learning how to date with the current AI, when you don’t have any experiences yet and you have someone who’s constantly responsive, I actually think that might not be the greatest idea,” she told us.</p>
<p>But an AI relationship coach is a particularly promising role for an AI bot. Instead of taking over the role of healthcare provider or friend, AI could be “a non-biased, evidence-based, science-based relationship coach” that acts as “a different kind of socialization agent,” Ha said.</p>
<p>And in the fight against the loneliness epidemic, it’s only a matter of time before people turn to non-human forms of communication, Ha said. “It’s a really adaptive signal for us to survive as humans, actually,” she said. “The fact that AI now all of a sudden is an option actually makes total sense.”
AI Shows Promise for Supporting Couples in Distress
Ha supports the use of AI in some social situations and for some people, but she acknowledges that it’s far from a relationship cure-all.</p>
<p>She describes her stance on AI dating as more “nuanced” than some AI enthusiasts may expect.</p>
<p>She feels that people at the debate resonated specifically with the idea of augmented intimacy — when tech like AI and VR are used to enhance the typically-human experience of intimacy and connection.
People who have been through painful divorces, break-ups, and/or the loss of a spouse may benefit from chatting with an AI date before they get back into the swing of IRL dating.</p>
<p>Then there are adults in relationships with emotional or physical barriers, such as people who act as caretakers for their spouses, or are in otherwise emotionally-stymied relationships. “[AI dating] could be a buffer,” Ha explained. “If you’re a caregiver, it actually might give you the support that your partner cannot give you, [which] is actually really helpful.”</p>
<p>For others, a little AI flirtation can simply add some excitement back into a long-term relationship. “A lot of people are satisfied with their relationship but are missing that spark that they had in the beginning,” she said.</p>
<p>When AI temporarily supplements a missing emotional need, it’s working “in very synergistic ways,” Ha said.</p>
<p>As the AI boom continues, Ha cautions against diving into AI relationships without considering the potential long term effects — a difficult task, considering we don’t really know yet what those long term effects will be.</p>
<p>“I think the big point that I was trying to make [at the debate] is like, yeah, we have all these anecdotes of people really enjoying [AI]… but we don’t really know the long term effects of what happens to people’s mental health and their real life relationships,” Ha said. “There’s no studies on that and I think I would love to see more work in that area.”</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Swipe Left: Dating Apps Have Killed Romance</em></p>
<p><u>Q&A With Daniel Jones</u></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>International Perspective</u></p>
<p><u>The Future of Online Dating</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>The Business of Love</u></p>
<p><u>Polls & Stats</u></p>
<p><u>Algorithms</u></p>
<p><u>Race, Gender & Dating Apps</u></p>
<p><u>User Experience</u></p>
<p><u>Niche Dating Sites</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> February 06, 2018</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Culture, Tech</p>
<p>Every day millions of people turn to dating apps to find love. To date, more than 49 million Americans have given digital dating a try and the companies facilitating these matches are raking in billions. But are dating apps really designed to promote long-lasting romance? Apps like Tinder and Bumble make finding a date as easy as swiping right, while digital platforms like Match.com and OkCupid use specialized algorithms to help users find the perfect partner, regardless of age or personal preferences. Further, a range of niche sites connect people with highly specific interests, whether it’s single parenthood, a gluten-free lifestyle, or a devotion to Ayn Rand. But some argue that online dating is rife with sexism, racism, and misogyny, and that dating apps ultimately create a culture that prioritizes sex over committed and lasting love. After all, why settle on one match when there may be someone better just a swipe away?
To view the full debate visit <a href="https://www.wondrium.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wondrium.</a></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/DmxfA9WO-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/DmxfA9WO-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Eric Klinenberg</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO139068403 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO139068403 BCX0">Eric Klinenberg is a professor of sociology and director of the Institute for Public Knowledge at New York University. He is a co-author of "Modern Romance", which investigates the nature of dating in the digital era. Klinenberg is also the author of "Going Solo: The Extraordinary Rise and Surprising Appeal of Living Alone." His scholarly work has been published in academic journals including the American Sociological Review, Theory and Society, and Ethnography. He has contributed to numerous leading news platforms as well as the radio program, "This American Life."</span></span></p>
<p><strong>Manoush Zomorodi</strong><br>Manoush Zomorodi is the host and managing editor of Note to Self, "the tech show about being human," from WNYC Studios. She has won numerous awards for her work, including four from the New York Press Club. In 2014, the Alliance for Women in Media named her Outstanding Host. Zomorodi is the author of "Bored and Brilliant: How Spacing Out Can Unlock Your Most Productive and Creative Self." She is a self-proclaimed relentless examiner of the modern human condition.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Helen Fisher</strong><br><span data-contrast="none">Helen Fisher, PhD, a biological anthropologist, is a senior research fellow at The Kinsey Institute at Indiana University, a member of the Center for Human Evolutionary Studies at Rutgers University, and Chief Scientific Adviser to Match.com. She uses brain scanning (fMRI) to study the neural systems associated with romantic love, attachment, and partner happiness. She has written six internationally best-selling books on courtship, romantic love, and future sex, including "Why We Love, Why Him? Why Her?", and "Anatomy of Love." Fisher is also the co-founder of NeuroColor, where she is a pioneer in examining the neurochemistry of business team-building, innovation, and leadership.</span></p>
<p><strong>Tom Jacques</strong><br>Tom Jacques is vice president of engineering at OkCupid, a leading dating site that boasts more than 3.5 million users and sees over seven million messages exchanged per day. OkCupid, which relies on a dating algorithm to determine digital matches, was recently deemed the site most likely to appear in the New York Times’ marriage announcements, ranking above Tinder, <a href="https://www.match.com/">Match.com</a>, and eHarmony. As a software engineer, Tom engages in data analysis designed to make dating more efficient and less time-consuming. He is a graduate of Carnegie Mellon University.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Should People Date AI? Thao Ha Says ‘Yes, But…’</strong> <small>2025-07-10 12:03:53</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Key Takeaways</p>
<p>At an Open to Debate event, Professor Thao Ha explained why she argued “yes” to the question “Could dating an AI be better than dating a human?” (https://www.datingnews.com/movers-and-shakers/should-people-date-ai-thao-ha-debate/#Debate)
 Ha emphasized the healing potential of AI as a tool in romantic relationships, especially for adolescents experiencing confusing feelings. (https://www.datingnews.com/movers-and-shakers/should-people-date-ai-thao-ha-debate/#AI)
 Adults in vulnerable situations, such as caregivers and clashing couples, can use AI and VR to work through emotional obstacles. (https://www.datingnews.com/movers-and-shakers/should-people-date-ai-thao-ha-debate/#emotional)</p>
<p>At June 10th’s Open to Debate event (https://mailchi.mp/opentodebate.org/debatecould-dating-an-ai-be-better-than-a-human-2686564?e=23379795b6) in New York City, dating industry pros asked the question on everybody’s lips: Could dating an AI be better than dating a human?</p>
<p>Thao Ha (https://search.asu.edu/profile/2162867), Associate Professor of Psychology at Arizona State University, argued “yes”, while Justin Garcia, Executive Director & Senior Scientist at the Kinsey Institute and Chief Scientific Advisor to Match.com (http://match.com/), argued “no.”
In the overarching AI debate in the dating industry, the greatest fear is that AI will come to replace the uniquely human ability to love. Ha’s claim that dating an AI bot (https://www.datingnews.com/uncategorized/what-are-bots/) could, in some ways, be preferable to dating a human being is certainly controversial.</p>
<p>After the debate, DatingNews spoke to Ha about her unconventional viewpoint, and the surprising benefits of connecting emotionally with AI.</p>
<p>To “Date” AI is to Use it as a Romantic Tool
Ha is the director of the @HEART lab (https://search.asu.edu/profile/2162867) (Healthy Experiences Across Relationships and Transitions), which studies a buzzy topic: The mental, emotional, and social impacts AI has on adolescent relationships.</p>
<p>On the “pro” side of the debate, Ha argues that intuitive tech, like VR and AI, have the potential to ease loneliness and meet short-term emotional needs. For people who struggle to make satisfying in-person connections, AI and VR could be transformative tools.</p>
<p>When dating someone in real life isn’t an option — which, for some people, it isn’t — developing an emotional attachment to an AI bot could help satisfy several crucial emotional needs: the need to explore one’s romantic and sexual feelings in a healthy way, or to express thoughts and feelings without judgement, for example.</p>
<p>Ha doesn’t advocate for no-holds-barred access to AI. Instead, she argues that people, and the platforms that use AI, should promote a healthy balance between IRL and AI connections.</p>
<p>“It’s not my goal that everybody’s going to start dating AI,” she told us. On the contrary, Ha simply wants to acknowledge the potential AI has as a therapeutic tool, particularly for vulnerable groups, like adolescents and struggling couples.
As someone who specifically studies AI’s impact on adolescent relationships, Ha warns against offering shortcuts to human connection to people at such an impressionable age.</p>
<p>“Learning how to date with the current AI, when you don’t have any experiences yet and you have someone who’s constantly responsive, I actually think that might not be the greatest idea,” she told us.</p>
<p>But an AI relationship coach is a particularly promising role for an AI bot. Instead of taking over the role of healthcare provider or friend, AI could be “a non-biased, evidence-based, science-based relationship coach” that acts as “a different kind of socialization agent,” Ha said.</p>
<p>And in the fight against the loneliness epidemic, it’s only a matter of time before people turn to non-human forms of communication, Ha said. “It’s a really adaptive signal for us to survive as humans, actually,” she said. “The fact that AI now all of a sudden is an option actually makes total sense.”
AI Shows Promise for Supporting Couples in Distress
Ha supports the use of AI in some social situations and for some people, but she acknowledges that it’s far from a relationship cure-all.</p>
<p>She describes her stance on AI dating as more “nuanced” than some AI enthusiasts may expect.</p>
<p>She feels that people at the debate resonated specifically with the idea of augmented intimacy — when tech like AI and VR are used to enhance the typically-human experience of intimacy and connection.
People who have been through painful divorces, break-ups, and/or the loss of a spouse may benefit from chatting with an AI date before they get back into the swing of IRL dating.</p>
<p>Then there are adults in relationships with emotional or physical barriers, such as people who act as caretakers for their spouses, or are in otherwise emotionally-stymied relationships. “[AI dating] could be a buffer,” Ha explained. “If you’re a caregiver, it actually might give you the support that your partner cannot give you, [which] is actually really helpful.”</p>
<p>For others, a little AI flirtation can simply add some excitement back into a long-term relationship. “A lot of people are satisfied with their relationship but are missing that spark that they had in the beginning,” she said.</p>
<p>When AI temporarily supplements a missing emotional need, it’s working “in very synergistic ways,” Ha said.</p>
<p>As the AI boom continues, Ha cautions against diving into AI relationships without considering the potential long term effects — a difficult task, considering we don’t really know yet what those long term effects will be.</p>
<p>“I think the big point that I was trying to make [at the debate] is like, yeah, we have all these anecdotes of people really enjoying [AI]… but we don’t really know the long term effects of what happens to people’s mental health and their real life relationships,” Ha said. “There’s no studies on that and I think I would love to see more work in that area.”</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Swipe Left: Dating Apps Have Killed Romance</em></p>
<p><u>Q&A With Daniel Jones</u></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>International Perspective</u></p>
<p><u>The Future of Online Dating</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>The Business of Love</u></p>
<p><u>Polls & Stats</u></p>
<p><u>Algorithms</u></p>
<p><u>Race, Gender & Dating Apps</u></p>
<p><u>User Experience</u></p>
<p><u>Niche Dating Sites</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Unresolved: America&#x27;s Economic Outlook</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/unresolved-americas-economic-outlook</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10368</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> January 16, 2018</p>
<p>By most accounts, the American economy is booming — manufacturing is at a 13-year high, unemployment is at a 16-year low, and both the stock market and consumer confidence are soaring. But just what is driving this upturn? And can Americans trust that current economic conditions will hold up in the months ahead? In our season premiere, five esteemed economic thinkers debate the state of the American economy, from tax cuts to trade policy.
Closing in on the Trump administration’s first year, we’ll ask: Is deregulation driving the booming economy? Can the Republican tax bill spur economic growth? And is the stock market too high?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/jjijI7vC-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/jjijI7vC-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Jason Furman</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">Jason Furman is the Aetna Professor of the Practice of Economic Policy jointly at Harvard Kennedy School and the Department of Economics at Harvard University. He is also a nonresident senior fellow at the Peterson Institute for International Economics. Previously he served as a top economic adviser to President Obama, including serving as the 28th Chairman of the Council of Economic Advisers, acting as President Obama’s chief economist and a cabinet member. During this time, Furman played a major role in most of the major economic policies of the Obama Administration. Furman also served under President Clinton. Furman engages in public policy through research, writing, and teaching, focusing on U.S. and international macroeconomics, fiscal policy, labor markets, and competition policy. He is a member of numerous organizations, including the Council on Foreign Relations, the Group of Thirty, and the Economic Strategy Group. He also serves as a Trustee of the Russell Sage Foundation and the advisory boards for the Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, the Bund Summit, the Hamilton Project, and the Washington Center for Equitable Growth. In addition to articles in scholarly journals and periodicals, Furman is a regular contributor to the </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">W</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">all Street Journal</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0"> and </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">Project Syndicate</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0"> and the editor of two books on economic policy.</span></span></p>
<p><strong>Simon Johnson</strong><br>Simon Johnson, former chief economist of the International Monetary Fund, is the Ronald A. Kurtz Professor of Entrepreneurship at the MIT Sloan School of Management and a senior fellow at the Peterson Institute for International Economics. He is a co-founder of <a href="https://baselinescenario.com/">BaselineScenario.com</a> and a member of the FDIC’s Systemic Resolution Advisory Committee. In 2014, he joined the Financial Research Advisory Committee of the U.S. Treasury’s Office of Financial Research, and from 2009 to 2015, he was a member of the Congressional Budget Office's Panel of Economic Advisers. Johnson has published more than 300 high-impact articles on leading news platforms and is the co-author of several books, including "White House Burning: The Founding Fathers, Our National Debt, and Why It Matters to You."</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Dambisa Moyo</strong><br>Dambisa Moyo is a global economist and author who analyzes the macroeconomy and international affairs. She advises companies, corporate boards, CEOs, and management on investment decisions, capital allocation, and risk management. Her work examines the interplay of international business and the global economy while highlighting key opportunities for investment, capitalizing on her rare ability to translate trends in markets, politics, regulatory matters, and economics into their likely impact on global business. She serves on the boards of Barclays Bank, the financial services group; Barrick Gold, the global miner; and Chevron, the energy corporation. She previously served on the boards of SABMiller, the Global Brewer, and Seagate Technology. Dambisa was named by TIME Magazine as one of the "100 Most Influential People in the World" and was awarded the 2013 Hayek Lifetime Achievement Award.</p>
<p><strong>Gillian Tett</strong><br>Gillian Tett is chair of the editorial board and U.S. editor-at-large of the Financial Times, where she oversees global coverage of the financial markets. An award-winning journalist and best-selling author, Tett is also the co-founder of "Moral Money," a twice-weekly newsletter on socially responsible business. Her most recent book, "The Silo Effect," analyzes the financial system through the lens of cultural anthropology. She has been named Columnist of the Year (2014), Journalist of the Year (2009), and Business Journalist of the Year (2008) in the British Press Awards and received three awards from America's Society of Business and Economic Writers Awards. She is a best-selling author and has received the Royal Anthropological Institute Marsh Award and the American Anthropological Association President Medal for her work in social science.</p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> January 16, 2018</p>
<p>By most accounts, the American economy is booming — manufacturing is at a 13-year high, unemployment is at a 16-year low, and both the stock market and consumer confidence are soaring. But just what is driving this upturn? And can Americans trust that current economic conditions will hold up in the months ahead? In our season premiere, five esteemed economic thinkers debate the state of the American economy, from tax cuts to trade policy.
Closing in on the Trump administration’s first year, we’ll ask: Is deregulation driving the booming economy? Can the Republican tax bill spur economic growth? And is the stock market too high?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/jjijI7vC-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/jjijI7vC-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Jason Furman</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">Jason Furman is the Aetna Professor of the Practice of Economic Policy jointly at Harvard Kennedy School and the Department of Economics at Harvard University. He is also a nonresident senior fellow at the Peterson Institute for International Economics. Previously he served as a top economic adviser to President Obama, including serving as the 28th Chairman of the Council of Economic Advisers, acting as President Obama’s chief economist and a cabinet member. During this time, Furman played a major role in most of the major economic policies of the Obama Administration. Furman also served under President Clinton. Furman engages in public policy through research, writing, and teaching, focusing on U.S. and international macroeconomics, fiscal policy, labor markets, and competition policy. He is a member of numerous organizations, including the Council on Foreign Relations, the Group of Thirty, and the Economic Strategy Group. He also serves as a Trustee of the Russell Sage Foundation and the advisory boards for the Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, the Bund Summit, the Hamilton Project, and the Washington Center for Equitable Growth. In addition to articles in scholarly journals and periodicals, Furman is a regular contributor to the </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">W</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">all Street Journal</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0"> and </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">Project Syndicate</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0"> and the editor of two books on economic policy.</span></span></p>
<p><strong>Simon Johnson</strong><br>Simon Johnson, former chief economist of the International Monetary Fund, is the Ronald A. Kurtz Professor of Entrepreneurship at the MIT Sloan School of Management and a senior fellow at the Peterson Institute for International Economics. He is a co-founder of <a href="https://baselinescenario.com/">BaselineScenario.com</a> and a member of the FDIC’s Systemic Resolution Advisory Committee. In 2014, he joined the Financial Research Advisory Committee of the U.S. Treasury’s Office of Financial Research, and from 2009 to 2015, he was a member of the Congressional Budget Office's Panel of Economic Advisers. Johnson has published more than 300 high-impact articles on leading news platforms and is the co-author of several books, including "White House Burning: The Founding Fathers, Our National Debt, and Why It Matters to You."</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Dambisa Moyo</strong><br>Dambisa Moyo is a global economist and author who analyzes the macroeconomy and international affairs. She advises companies, corporate boards, CEOs, and management on investment decisions, capital allocation, and risk management. Her work examines the interplay of international business and the global economy while highlighting key opportunities for investment, capitalizing on her rare ability to translate trends in markets, politics, regulatory matters, and economics into their likely impact on global business. She serves on the boards of Barclays Bank, the financial services group; Barrick Gold, the global miner; and Chevron, the energy corporation. She previously served on the boards of SABMiller, the Global Brewer, and Seagate Technology. Dambisa was named by TIME Magazine as one of the "100 Most Influential People in the World" and was awarded the 2013 Hayek Lifetime Achievement Award.</p>
<p><strong>Gillian Tett</strong><br>Gillian Tett is chair of the editorial board and U.S. editor-at-large of the Financial Times, where she oversees global coverage of the financial markets. An award-winning journalist and best-selling author, Tett is also the co-founder of "Moral Money," a twice-weekly newsletter on socially responsible business. Her most recent book, "The Silo Effect," analyzes the financial system through the lens of cultural anthropology. She has been named Columnist of the Year (2014), Journalist of the Year (2009), and Business Journalist of the Year (2008) in the British Press Awards and received three awards from America's Society of Business and Economic Writers Awards. She is a best-selling author and has received the Royal Anthropological Institute Marsh Award and the American Anthropological Association President Medal for her work in social science.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
    
</rss>
