<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">

    <channel>
        <title>Open to Debate – Debates</title>
        <link>https://opentodebate.org</link>
        <description>Debates with related research and news</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 03:03:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
        <item>
            <title>Is Capitalism a Blessing?</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/capitalism-blessing</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10043</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> November 12, 2019</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Finance, Politics</p>
<p>Recent polls show that two out of three Americans support capitalism. But with the wealth gap widening and democratic socialist politicians gaining support, some Americans are starting to consider socialism as a viable economic and political model. Supporters of capitalism claim that no other system has been as effective in creating value, increasing prosperity, and producing the wealth that has lifted billions of people out of poverty. The free market, they argue, encourages competition and human ingenuity, values individual choice, and organizes society in a fair and just way. Critics of capitalism, however, paint a different picture. They argue that capitalism is inherently exploitative and that business owners seek profits above all else, leading to the distortion of human worth as one distilled to an individual’s labor power. Further, they claim that a capitalist system is inherently rigged to benefit the wealthy and powerful, and the byproducts of which have created unsustainable waste and decimated the world’s wildlife and natural resources. Who is right, and is capitalism here to stay?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://www.youtube.com/embed/ROT2HjxovsE' target='_blank'>https://www.youtube.com/embed/ROT2HjxovsE</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Mackey</strong><br>John Mackey, co-founder and CEO of Whole Foods Market, has led the natural and organic grocer to become an $18 billion company that is now owned by Amazon. With more than 500 stores and 95,000 team members in three countries, the company was named by Fortune magazine as one of "The Hundred Best Companies to Work For" for 20 consecutive years. A strong believer in free market principles, Mackey co-founded the Conscious Capitalism Movement and co-authored a New York Times and Wall Street Journal best-selling book titled "Conscious Capitalism: Liberating the Heroic Spirit of Business."</p>
<p><strong>Katherine Mangu-Ward</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO119895023 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO119895023 BCX0">Katherine Mangu-Ward is editor-in-chief of </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO119895023 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO119895023 BCX0">Reason</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO119895023 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO119895023 BCX0">, the libertarian magazine of “free minds and free markets,” and co-host of the “The Reason Roundtable” (formerly the “Reason Podcast”). A Future Tense fellow at New America, her writing has appeared in the </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO119895023 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO119895023 BCX0">Wall Street Journal, the Washington Post, the Los Angeles Times, Slate</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO119895023 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO119895023 BCX0">, and numerous other publications. She is a frequent commentator on radio and television networks, including National Public Radio, CNBC, C-SPAN, Fox Business, Fox News, and MSNBC.</span></span></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Bhaskar Sunkara</strong><br>Bhaskar Sunkara is the founding editor of Jacobin magazine and publisher of Catalyst journal, both of which offer socialist perspectives on politics, economics, and culture, as well as critiques of capitalism from a global perspective. An advocate of democratic socialism, he is the author of "The Socialist Manifesto: The Case for Radical Politics in an Era of Extreme Inequality" and a columnist at The Guardian.</p>
<p><strong>Richard D. Wolff</strong><br>Richard D. Wolff is a Marxian economist and professor emeritus of economics at the University of Massachusetts Amherst. He is currently a visiting professor at the New School University and previously taught at Yale University. Wolff is the founder of Democracy at Work and has written or contributed to over a dozen books, including his most recent, “Capitalism's Crisis Deepens: Essays on the Global Economic Meltdown,” and “Understanding Marxism.” Wolff earned his bachelor’s at Harvard and his master’s in economics and history, as well as a doctorate in economics, at Yale.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Capitalism Is a Blessing</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>The American Economy and 2020 Implications</u></p>
<p><u>Working Conditions</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> November 12, 2019</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Finance, Politics</p>
<p>Recent polls show that two out of three Americans support capitalism. But with the wealth gap widening and democratic socialist politicians gaining support, some Americans are starting to consider socialism as a viable economic and political model. Supporters of capitalism claim that no other system has been as effective in creating value, increasing prosperity, and producing the wealth that has lifted billions of people out of poverty. The free market, they argue, encourages competition and human ingenuity, values individual choice, and organizes society in a fair and just way. Critics of capitalism, however, paint a different picture. They argue that capitalism is inherently exploitative and that business owners seek profits above all else, leading to the distortion of human worth as one distilled to an individual’s labor power. Further, they claim that a capitalist system is inherently rigged to benefit the wealthy and powerful, and the byproducts of which have created unsustainable waste and decimated the world’s wildlife and natural resources. Who is right, and is capitalism here to stay?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://www.youtube.com/embed/ROT2HjxovsE' target='_blank'>https://www.youtube.com/embed/ROT2HjxovsE</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Mackey</strong><br>John Mackey, co-founder and CEO of Whole Foods Market, has led the natural and organic grocer to become an $18 billion company that is now owned by Amazon. With more than 500 stores and 95,000 team members in three countries, the company was named by Fortune magazine as one of "The Hundred Best Companies to Work For" for 20 consecutive years. A strong believer in free market principles, Mackey co-founded the Conscious Capitalism Movement and co-authored a New York Times and Wall Street Journal best-selling book titled "Conscious Capitalism: Liberating the Heroic Spirit of Business."</p>
<p><strong>Katherine Mangu-Ward</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO119895023 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO119895023 BCX0">Katherine Mangu-Ward is editor-in-chief of </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO119895023 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO119895023 BCX0">Reason</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO119895023 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO119895023 BCX0">, the libertarian magazine of “free minds and free markets,” and co-host of the “The Reason Roundtable” (formerly the “Reason Podcast”). A Future Tense fellow at New America, her writing has appeared in the </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO119895023 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO119895023 BCX0">Wall Street Journal, the Washington Post, the Los Angeles Times, Slate</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO119895023 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO119895023 BCX0">, and numerous other publications. She is a frequent commentator on radio and television networks, including National Public Radio, CNBC, C-SPAN, Fox Business, Fox News, and MSNBC.</span></span></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Bhaskar Sunkara</strong><br>Bhaskar Sunkara is the founding editor of Jacobin magazine and publisher of Catalyst journal, both of which offer socialist perspectives on politics, economics, and culture, as well as critiques of capitalism from a global perspective. An advocate of democratic socialism, he is the author of "The Socialist Manifesto: The Case for Radical Politics in an Era of Extreme Inequality" and a columnist at The Guardian.</p>
<p><strong>Richard D. Wolff</strong><br>Richard D. Wolff is a Marxian economist and professor emeritus of economics at the University of Massachusetts Amherst. He is currently a visiting professor at the New School University and previously taught at Yale University. Wolff is the founder of Democracy at Work and has written or contributed to over a dozen books, including his most recent, “Capitalism's Crisis Deepens: Essays on the Global Economic Meltdown,” and “Understanding Marxism.” Wolff earned his bachelor’s at Harvard and his master’s in economics and history, as well as a doctorate in economics, at Yale.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Capitalism Is a Blessing</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>The American Economy and 2020 Implications</u></p>
<p><u>Working Conditions</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Is Parenting Overrated?</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/parenting-overrated</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10375</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> October 29, 2019</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Culture, Science</p>
<p>What shapes us more: our DNA, or the way we’re raised? This debate, commonly recognized as “nature versus nurture,” has drawn disagreement for thousands of years. So which one matters more? Emerging genetic research indicates that the scale may be tipping toward biology – but not all trust the research. Proponents of the “nature” camp argue it is DNA that determines who we are, as evidenced by identical twins and triplets who are separated at birth and, once reunited, show remarkable similarities despite different upbringings. Rather than trying to identify the perfect parenting style, they argue, caregivers should look to their children’s DNA to identify natural strengths and challenges to promote overall health and well-being. But others strongly disagree, saying that parenting is very important, and the individuals who rear us influence our development, growth, and, ultimately, our lives. The “nurture” camp also points to studies that show how beliefs and behaviors are not innate, as evidenced by stark differences in the expression of adolescence and other life stages across different cultures. Are they right? Or is parenting overrated?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/l4z5CdmE-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/l4z5CdmE-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Robert Plomin</strong><br>Robert Plomin is a leading behavioral geneticist who works at the Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology, and Neuroscience at King’s College London. He has published more than 800 papers in scientific journals and is the author of the best-selling textbook in the field. In 2012, he was awarded a highly prestigious five-year Advanced Investigator award from the European Research Council, and he was given a lifetime achievement award from the American Psychological Association, among others. Plomin is the author of the recent book, "Blueprint: How DNA Makes Us Who We Are."</p>
<p><strong>Nancy Segal</strong><br>Nancy Segal is a professor of psychology at California State University, Fullerton, and the director of the Twin Studies Center, which she founded in 1991. Segal has authored approximately 200 scientific articles and book chapters on the study of genetics and twins. She has also published many books on the subject of twin research, including "Born Together-Reared Apart: The Landmark Minnesota Twin Study," "Twin Mythconceptions: False Beliefs, Fables, and Facts About Twins," and her most recent, "Accidental Brothers: The Story of Twins Exchanged at Birth and the Power of Nature and Nurture."</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Paige Harden</strong><br>Paige Harden is a tenured psychology professor at the University of Texas, where she leads the Developmental Behavior Genetics lab and co-directs the Texas Twin Project, a study of the interplay between genes, hormones, risky behavior, and cognitive functioning in child and adolescent twins. She has published over 100 scientific articles on genetic influences on complex human behavior, and in 2017, she was honored by the American Psychological Association for her scientific contributions to the study of genetics and human individual differences.</p>
<p><strong>Ann Pleshette Murphy</strong><br>Ann Pleshette Murphy is a therapist, parenting counselor, and passionate advocate for young children and their families. She is the author of "The 7 Stages of Motherhood: Loving Your Life Without Losing Your Mind" and "The Secret of Play: How to Raise Smart, Healthy, Caring Kids from Birth to Age 12." Previously, she was the parenting correspondent for ABC’s, "Good Morning America." A renowned magazine journalist and editor, Pleshette Murphy was editor-in-chief of Parents magazine from 1988 to 1998 and a contributing editor from 1998 to 2002.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Parenting Experts Debate If Parenting Is Simply Overrated</strong> <small>2023-02-07 18:51:28</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>The age-old nature v. nurture debate took a different turn a couple of months ago during a live debate held at New York City’s Kaye Playhouse and live streamed before becoming part of a syndicated public radio show and podcast called “Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S.“.</p>
<p>The side arguing against the motion “Parenting Is Overrated” won.</p>
<p>Arguing in favor of the motion are behavioral geneticist Robert Plomin and psychology professor and twin researcher Nancy Segal. Arguing against the motion are psychology professor Paige Harden also a twin researcher, who had reached very different conclusions and parenting counselor and journalist Ann Pleshette Murphy.</p>
<p>“Research over 40 years has convinced most scientists that inherited DNA differences account for about 50 percent of the differences between children on all psychological traits: their personalities, their mental health and illness, and their cognitive abilities and disabilities,” moderator John Donvan says. “What amazes me is that if you look at all the parenting books that are out there, and there are very popular books, not one mentions genetics, and that discrepancy is enough to say parenting is overrated because it discounts the importance of genetics.”</p>
<p>It’s about an hour and a half long but so worth the watch:</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Parenting Is Overrated</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Twins Studies and Human Genetics</u></p>
<p><u>Parenting</u></p>
<p><u>In the Classroom</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> October 29, 2019</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Culture, Science</p>
<p>What shapes us more: our DNA, or the way we’re raised? This debate, commonly recognized as “nature versus nurture,” has drawn disagreement for thousands of years. So which one matters more? Emerging genetic research indicates that the scale may be tipping toward biology – but not all trust the research. Proponents of the “nature” camp argue it is DNA that determines who we are, as evidenced by identical twins and triplets who are separated at birth and, once reunited, show remarkable similarities despite different upbringings. Rather than trying to identify the perfect parenting style, they argue, caregivers should look to their children’s DNA to identify natural strengths and challenges to promote overall health and well-being. But others strongly disagree, saying that parenting is very important, and the individuals who rear us influence our development, growth, and, ultimately, our lives. The “nurture” camp also points to studies that show how beliefs and behaviors are not innate, as evidenced by stark differences in the expression of adolescence and other life stages across different cultures. Are they right? Or is parenting overrated?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/l4z5CdmE-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/l4z5CdmE-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Robert Plomin</strong><br>Robert Plomin is a leading behavioral geneticist who works at the Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology, and Neuroscience at King’s College London. He has published more than 800 papers in scientific journals and is the author of the best-selling textbook in the field. In 2012, he was awarded a highly prestigious five-year Advanced Investigator award from the European Research Council, and he was given a lifetime achievement award from the American Psychological Association, among others. Plomin is the author of the recent book, "Blueprint: How DNA Makes Us Who We Are."</p>
<p><strong>Nancy Segal</strong><br>Nancy Segal is a professor of psychology at California State University, Fullerton, and the director of the Twin Studies Center, which she founded in 1991. Segal has authored approximately 200 scientific articles and book chapters on the study of genetics and twins. She has also published many books on the subject of twin research, including "Born Together-Reared Apart: The Landmark Minnesota Twin Study," "Twin Mythconceptions: False Beliefs, Fables, and Facts About Twins," and her most recent, "Accidental Brothers: The Story of Twins Exchanged at Birth and the Power of Nature and Nurture."</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Paige Harden</strong><br>Paige Harden is a tenured psychology professor at the University of Texas, where she leads the Developmental Behavior Genetics lab and co-directs the Texas Twin Project, a study of the interplay between genes, hormones, risky behavior, and cognitive functioning in child and adolescent twins. She has published over 100 scientific articles on genetic influences on complex human behavior, and in 2017, she was honored by the American Psychological Association for her scientific contributions to the study of genetics and human individual differences.</p>
<p><strong>Ann Pleshette Murphy</strong><br>Ann Pleshette Murphy is a therapist, parenting counselor, and passionate advocate for young children and their families. She is the author of "The 7 Stages of Motherhood: Loving Your Life Without Losing Your Mind" and "The Secret of Play: How to Raise Smart, Healthy, Caring Kids from Birth to Age 12." Previously, she was the parenting correspondent for ABC’s, "Good Morning America." A renowned magazine journalist and editor, Pleshette Murphy was editor-in-chief of Parents magazine from 1988 to 1998 and a contributing editor from 1998 to 2002.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Parenting Experts Debate If Parenting Is Simply Overrated</strong> <small>2023-02-07 18:51:28</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>The age-old nature v. nurture debate took a different turn a couple of months ago during a live debate held at New York City’s Kaye Playhouse and live streamed before becoming part of a syndicated public radio show and podcast called “Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S.“.</p>
<p>The side arguing against the motion “Parenting Is Overrated” won.</p>
<p>Arguing in favor of the motion are behavioral geneticist Robert Plomin and psychology professor and twin researcher Nancy Segal. Arguing against the motion are psychology professor Paige Harden also a twin researcher, who had reached very different conclusions and parenting counselor and journalist Ann Pleshette Murphy.</p>
<p>“Research over 40 years has convinced most scientists that inherited DNA differences account for about 50 percent of the differences between children on all psychological traits: their personalities, their mental health and illness, and their cognitive abilities and disabilities,” moderator John Donvan says. “What amazes me is that if you look at all the parenting books that are out there, and there are very popular books, not one mentions genetics, and that discrepancy is enough to say parenting is overrated because it discounts the importance of genetics.”</p>
<p>It’s about an hour and a half long but so worth the watch:</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Parenting Is Overrated</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Twins Studies and Human Genetics</u></p>
<p><u>Parenting</u></p>
<p><u>In the Classroom</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Europe Has Declared War on American Tech Companies</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/europe-has-declared-war-american-tech-companies</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10099</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> October 22, 2019</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Tech, World</p>
<p>European regulators are taking on American technology companies, including Apple, Facebook, and Google, in a big way. Is Brussels waging war against Silicon Valley? Proponents of European regulations argue that these tech giants make billions of dollars while avoiding taxes, and they engage in risky activities that jeopardize user privacy with little to no consequence. Regulations like the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), they say, will bring power back into the hands of tech consumers by protecting their data and will restore faith in tech companies, ultimately benefitting all. But not everyone agrees. Their opponents argue that regulations like the GDPR are bad for business, and Silicon Valley was built on the idea that innovators need the room and freedom to create without constraint. Tight regulations, they say, will stifle innovation, which will be a detriment to the West’s global influence – and an impediment to societal progress. Is Europe right to wield a regulatory sword at American tech companies?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/ZuGpyXEo-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/ZuGpyXEo-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Roslyn Layton</strong><br>Roslyn Layton is a visiting scholar at the American Enterprise Institute, where she focuses on evidence-based policy for the information, communications, and digital technology industries. Using empirical methods, she assesses regulations and policies for digitally connected domains such as mobile wireless, telecom, cable, the internet, online advertising, e-government, media, software, financial technology, and telehealth, among others. Layton is also a visiting researcher at the Aalborg University Center for Communication, Media, and Information Technologies and vice president at Strand Consult, both in Denmark.</p>
<p><strong>Berin Szóka</strong><br>Berin Szóka is the founder and president of TechFreedom, a Washington, D.C.-based think tank dedicated to analyzing the policy and legal questions raised by technological change. He is a former senior fellow and director of the Center for Internet Freedom at The Progress & Freedom Foundation, and prior to that, he was an associate in the Communications Practice Group at Latham & Watkins LLP.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Marietje Schaake</strong><br>Marietje Schaake is international policy director and international policy fellow at Stanford’s Cyber Policy Center and Institute for Human-Centered Artificial Intelligence, respectively. She is a former member of the European Parliament from the Netherlands and was a member of D66, part of the Alliance of Liberals and Democrats for Europe political group. She is also the founder of the European Parliament Intergroup on the Digital Agenda for Europe, a member of the European Council on Foreign Relations, and an adviser to the Center for Humane Technology. Schaake was featured by Politico as one of the 28 most influential Europeans in the class of 2017.</p>
<p><strong>Ramesh Srinivasan</strong><br>Ramesh Srinivasan studies the relationship between technology, politics, and society and is a professor at the University of California, Los Angeles, where he is also the founder and director of the UC Digital Cultures Lab. Srinivasan is the author of “Whose Global Village?: Rethinking How Technology Impacts Our World” and “After the Internet.” He earned his doctorate in design studies at Harvard and is a regular speaker for TEDx Talks. Srinivasan’s writings have been widely published by CNN, Wired, and Forbes, among others.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Europe Has Declared War on American Tech Companies</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Copyright</u></p>
<p><u>Speech Regulations</u></p>
<p><u>Right To Be Forgotten</u></p>
<p><u>Taxes & Financial Penalties</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Industry Reaction</u></p>
<p><u>Recent Cases & Regulations</u></p>
<p><u>European-Style Regulations in the United States</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> October 22, 2019</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Tech, World</p>
<p>European regulators are taking on American technology companies, including Apple, Facebook, and Google, in a big way. Is Brussels waging war against Silicon Valley? Proponents of European regulations argue that these tech giants make billions of dollars while avoiding taxes, and they engage in risky activities that jeopardize user privacy with little to no consequence. Regulations like the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), they say, will bring power back into the hands of tech consumers by protecting their data and will restore faith in tech companies, ultimately benefitting all. But not everyone agrees. Their opponents argue that regulations like the GDPR are bad for business, and Silicon Valley was built on the idea that innovators need the room and freedom to create without constraint. Tight regulations, they say, will stifle innovation, which will be a detriment to the West’s global influence – and an impediment to societal progress. Is Europe right to wield a regulatory sword at American tech companies?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/ZuGpyXEo-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/ZuGpyXEo-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Roslyn Layton</strong><br>Roslyn Layton is a visiting scholar at the American Enterprise Institute, where she focuses on evidence-based policy for the information, communications, and digital technology industries. Using empirical methods, she assesses regulations and policies for digitally connected domains such as mobile wireless, telecom, cable, the internet, online advertising, e-government, media, software, financial technology, and telehealth, among others. Layton is also a visiting researcher at the Aalborg University Center for Communication, Media, and Information Technologies and vice president at Strand Consult, both in Denmark.</p>
<p><strong>Berin Szóka</strong><br>Berin Szóka is the founder and president of TechFreedom, a Washington, D.C.-based think tank dedicated to analyzing the policy and legal questions raised by technological change. He is a former senior fellow and director of the Center for Internet Freedom at The Progress & Freedom Foundation, and prior to that, he was an associate in the Communications Practice Group at Latham & Watkins LLP.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Marietje Schaake</strong><br>Marietje Schaake is international policy director and international policy fellow at Stanford’s Cyber Policy Center and Institute for Human-Centered Artificial Intelligence, respectively. She is a former member of the European Parliament from the Netherlands and was a member of D66, part of the Alliance of Liberals and Democrats for Europe political group. She is also the founder of the European Parliament Intergroup on the Digital Agenda for Europe, a member of the European Council on Foreign Relations, and an adviser to the Center for Humane Technology. Schaake was featured by Politico as one of the 28 most influential Europeans in the class of 2017.</p>
<p><strong>Ramesh Srinivasan</strong><br>Ramesh Srinivasan studies the relationship between technology, politics, and society and is a professor at the University of California, Los Angeles, where he is also the founder and director of the UC Digital Cultures Lab. Srinivasan is the author of “Whose Global Village?: Rethinking How Technology Impacts Our World” and “After the Internet.” He earned his doctorate in design studies at Harvard and is a regular speaker for TEDx Talks. Srinivasan’s writings have been widely published by CNN, Wired, and Forbes, among others.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Europe Has Declared War on American Tech Companies</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Copyright</u></p>
<p><u>Speech Regulations</u></p>
<p><u>Right To Be Forgotten</u></p>
<p><u>Taxes & Financial Penalties</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Industry Reaction</u></p>
<p><u>Recent Cases & Regulations</u></p>
<p><u>European-Style Regulations in the United States</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Is It time for Medicare for All?</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/replace-private-insurance-medicare-all</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10133</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> September 17, 2019</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Health, Politics, World</p>
<p>As the nation gears up for the 2020 election, Democrats are promising bold new changes to the American health care system. One idea championed by many on the progressive left is “Medicare for All,” or a single-payer system, which would do away with private health insurance for most forms of care. Advocates of this plan promise that nationalizing health insurance will cut costs by reducing overhead and promote overall health by giving all Americans access to preventive health care. And in doing so, the United States will join the ranks of many other developed nations that have already mandated a national insurance program to guarantee medical care as a basic human right. Their opponents argue Medicare for All is a political non-starter that would force Americans off employer-based plans, reduce incentives for doctors and providers, increase bureaucracy and inefficiencies in the system, and lead to worse care overall, all the while inflating the already swelled federal deficit. Should private health insurance exist? Or is it time for Medicare for All?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/HfSF8BcA-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/HfSF8BcA-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Adam Gaffney</strong><br>Dr. Gaffney is a pulmonary specialist at Cambridge Health Alliance at Harvard Medical School and is president of Physicians for a National Health Program (PNHP). He is also chair of the Massachusetts chapter of PNHP and co-chair of the Working Group on Single-Payer Program Design, which developed the "Physicians’ Proposal for Single-Payer Health Care Reform," recently published in the American Journal of Public Health. Dr. Gaffney is a prolific writer and blogger on health policy, frequently appears on radio, and is the author of "To Heal Humankind: The Right to Health in History."</p>
<p><strong>Joseph Sanberg</strong><br>Joseph Sanberg is a progressive entrepreneur who works through both the public and private sectors to improve public policy with the aim of ending poverty and making people’s lives better. Sanberg has been one of the nation’s leading advocates for the earned-income tax credit (EITC) for low-income families, and in 2015, he successfully lobbied legislators in his home state of California to create the state’s first EITC. A founding investor in Blue Apron, Sanberg also serves on the boards of the Economic Innovation Group and the Jefferson Awards Foundation.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Nick Gillespie</strong><br>Nick Gillespie is the editor-at-large of Reason, the libertarian magazine of "free minds and free markets," and the host of The Reason Interview podcast with Nick Gillespie. A two-time finalist for the digital National Magazine Awards, he is co-author of "The Declaration of Independents: How Libertarian Politics Can Fix What's Wrong with America" and holds a Ph.D. in American literature.
Full bio is available <a href="https://reason.com/people/nick-gillespie/">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Sally Pipes</strong><br>Sally C. Pipes is president and chief executive officer of the Pacific Research Institute (PRI), a San Francisco-based think tank founded in 1979, where she is also the Thomas W. Smith fellow in health care policy. Prior to becoming president of PRI in 1991, she was the assistant director of the Fraser Institute, a public policy think-tank based in Vancouver, Canada. She is a frequent contributor to major news sources, including the bi-weekly healthcare column "Piping Up" for Forbes.com. Pipes is a prolific author on healthcare trends and policy, including "Miracle Cure: How to Solve America’s Health Care Crisis and Why Canada Isn’t the Answer," "The Truth About ObamaCare," and "False Premise, False Promise: The Disastrous Reality of Medicare for All."</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Replace Private Insurance With Medicare for All</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Employer-Based Coverage</u></p>
<p><u>Federal Debt & The Costs of Medicare for All</u></p>
<p><u>Global Health Care Examples</u></p>
<p><u>Industry Coalitions & 2020 Implications</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> September 17, 2019</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Health, Politics, World</p>
<p>As the nation gears up for the 2020 election, Democrats are promising bold new changes to the American health care system. One idea championed by many on the progressive left is “Medicare for All,” or a single-payer system, which would do away with private health insurance for most forms of care. Advocates of this plan promise that nationalizing health insurance will cut costs by reducing overhead and promote overall health by giving all Americans access to preventive health care. And in doing so, the United States will join the ranks of many other developed nations that have already mandated a national insurance program to guarantee medical care as a basic human right. Their opponents argue Medicare for All is a political non-starter that would force Americans off employer-based plans, reduce incentives for doctors and providers, increase bureaucracy and inefficiencies in the system, and lead to worse care overall, all the while inflating the already swelled federal deficit. Should private health insurance exist? Or is it time for Medicare for All?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/HfSF8BcA-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/HfSF8BcA-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Adam Gaffney</strong><br>Dr. Gaffney is a pulmonary specialist at Cambridge Health Alliance at Harvard Medical School and is president of Physicians for a National Health Program (PNHP). He is also chair of the Massachusetts chapter of PNHP and co-chair of the Working Group on Single-Payer Program Design, which developed the "Physicians’ Proposal for Single-Payer Health Care Reform," recently published in the American Journal of Public Health. Dr. Gaffney is a prolific writer and blogger on health policy, frequently appears on radio, and is the author of "To Heal Humankind: The Right to Health in History."</p>
<p><strong>Joseph Sanberg</strong><br>Joseph Sanberg is a progressive entrepreneur who works through both the public and private sectors to improve public policy with the aim of ending poverty and making people’s lives better. Sanberg has been one of the nation’s leading advocates for the earned-income tax credit (EITC) for low-income families, and in 2015, he successfully lobbied legislators in his home state of California to create the state’s first EITC. A founding investor in Blue Apron, Sanberg also serves on the boards of the Economic Innovation Group and the Jefferson Awards Foundation.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Nick Gillespie</strong><br>Nick Gillespie is the editor-at-large of Reason, the libertarian magazine of "free minds and free markets," and the host of The Reason Interview podcast with Nick Gillespie. A two-time finalist for the digital National Magazine Awards, he is co-author of "The Declaration of Independents: How Libertarian Politics Can Fix What's Wrong with America" and holds a Ph.D. in American literature.
Full bio is available <a href="https://reason.com/people/nick-gillespie/">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Sally Pipes</strong><br>Sally C. Pipes is president and chief executive officer of the Pacific Research Institute (PRI), a San Francisco-based think tank founded in 1979, where she is also the Thomas W. Smith fellow in health care policy. Prior to becoming president of PRI in 1991, she was the assistant director of the Fraser Institute, a public policy think-tank based in Vancouver, Canada. She is a frequent contributor to major news sources, including the bi-weekly healthcare column "Piping Up" for Forbes.com. Pipes is a prolific author on healthcare trends and policy, including "Miracle Cure: How to Solve America’s Health Care Crisis and Why Canada Isn’t the Answer," "The Truth About ObamaCare," and "False Premise, False Promise: The Disastrous Reality of Medicare for All."</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Replace Private Insurance With Medicare for All</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Employer-Based Coverage</u></p>
<p><u>Federal Debt & The Costs of Medicare for All</u></p>
<p><u>Global Health Care Examples</u></p>
<p><u>Industry Coalitions & 2020 Implications</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Unresolved: Shifting Power in the Middle East</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/unresolved-shifting-power-middle-east</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10337</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> September 12, 2019</p>
<p>Saudi Arabia and Iran are vying for regional dominance. Turkey is cozying up to Russia and China. And instability, conflict, and proxy wars have engulfed Syria, Yemen, and beyond. How should the United States respond to shifting power in the Middle East?
Staged in our “Unresolved” format, this debate brings together five foreign policy experts to tackle pressing questions on geopolitics in the Middle East, including: Is Trump right on Saudi Arabia? Is the world safer without the JCPOA? And is Turkey an asset to NATO?</p>
<p><strong>Unresolved Questions:</strong></p>
<p>• Trump Is Right on Saudi Arabia</p>
<p>• The World Is Safer Without the JCPOA</p>
<p>• Turkey Is an Asset to NATO</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/KfoVm0Sx-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/KfoVm0Sx-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Michael Doran</strong><br>Michael Doran is a senior fellow at the Hudson Institute in Washington, D.C., where he specializes in Middle East security issues and co-hosts the foreign policy-focused “Counterbalance” podcast. Doran previously served as a senior fellow at the Brookings Institution and was a senior director on the National Security Council where he was responsible for helping to devise and coordinate U.S. strategy on a variety of Middle East issues, including Arab-Israeli relations and U.S. efforts to contain Iran and Syria. He also served as a senior advisor in the State Department and was a deputy assistant secretary of defense in the Pentagon. Doran has testified before Congress, written two books, “Ike’s Gamble: America’s Rise to Dominance in the Middle East” and “Pan-Arabism Before Nasser: Egyptian Power Politics And The Palestine Question”, and published articles in <i data-stringify-type="italic">Foreign Affairs</i>, the <i data-stringify-type="italic">American Interest</i>, <i data-stringify-type="italic">Commentary</i>, <i data-stringify-type="italic">Mosaic</i>, the<i data-stringify-type="italic"> Wall Street Journal</i>, <i data-stringify-type="italic">The</i> <i data-stringify-type="italic">Washington Post</i>, and <i data-stringify-type="italic">The</i> <i data-stringify-type="italic">New York Times</i>.</p>
<p><strong>Reuel Marc Gerecht</strong><br>Reuel Marc Gerecht is a former case officer for the CIA, where he served as a Middle Eastern targets officer with the CIA's directorate of operations. He is a senior fellow at the Foundation for Defense of Democracies, a non-partisan organization centered on national security, where he focuses on Iran, sanctions, terrorism, and the Middle East. He is the author of "Know Thy Enemy: A Spy’s Journey into Revolutionary Iran" and "The Islamic Paradox: Shiite Clerics, Sunni Fundamentalists, and the Coming of Arab Democracy," among others.</p>
<p><strong>Bernard Haykel</strong><br>Bernard Haykel is a professor of Near Eastern Studies and the director of the Institute for Transregional Study of the Contemporary Middle East, North Africa, and Central Asia at Princeton University. After working as a post-doctoral research fellow at Oxford University in Islamic Studies, he joined New York University in 1998 as an associate professor before taking up his post at Princeton. He became a Guggenheim fellow in 2010 and is co-editor of the book "Saudi Arabia in Transition: Insights on Social, Political, Economic, and Religious Change."</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Brett McGurk</strong><br>Brett McGurk served as Special Presidential Envoy for the Global Coalition to Defeat ISIS at the U.S. Department of State, where he helped build and then lead the coalition of 75 countries and four international organizations in the global campaign against ISIS. He served in senior positions in the Bush and Obama administrations and has led some of the most sensitive diplomatic missions in the Middle East over the last decade. McGurk is currently the Frank E. and Arthur W. Payne distinguished lecturer at the Freeman Spogli Institute and Center for Security and Cooperation at Stanford University.</p>
<p><strong>Barbara Slavin</strong><br><p style="font-weight: 400;">Barbara Slavin is a distinguished fellow at the Stimson Center, where she is an expert on the Middle East & North Africa. She is also a lecturer in international affairs at George Washington University. Before joining the Stimson Center, she was director of the Future of Iran Initiative and a nonresident senior fellow at the Atlantic Council. She is the author of “Bitter Friends, Bosom Enemies: Iran, the U.S., and the Twisted Path to Confrontation.” She is a regular commentator on U.S. foreign policy and Iran on <em>NPR, PBS, and C-SPAN</em>. Previously, Slavin served as a public policy scholar at the Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars. Slavin is a former career journalist and previously wrote as a columnist for Al-Monitor.com, the assistant managing editor for world and national security at <em>The Washington Times</em>, a senior diplomatic reporter for <em>USA Today</em>, the Cairo and Beijing correspondent for <em>The Economist</em>, and an editor at <em>The New York Times Week in Review</em>.</p></p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Unresolved: Shifting Power in the Middle East</em></p>
<p><u>Trump Is Right on Saudi Arabia</u></p>
<p><u>The World Is Safer Without the JCPOA</u></p>
<p><u>Turkey Is an Asset to NATO</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> September 12, 2019</p>
<p>Saudi Arabia and Iran are vying for regional dominance. Turkey is cozying up to Russia and China. And instability, conflict, and proxy wars have engulfed Syria, Yemen, and beyond. How should the United States respond to shifting power in the Middle East?
Staged in our “Unresolved” format, this debate brings together five foreign policy experts to tackle pressing questions on geopolitics in the Middle East, including: Is Trump right on Saudi Arabia? Is the world safer without the JCPOA? And is Turkey an asset to NATO?</p>
<p><strong>Unresolved Questions:</strong></p>
<p>• Trump Is Right on Saudi Arabia</p>
<p>• The World Is Safer Without the JCPOA</p>
<p>• Turkey Is an Asset to NATO</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/KfoVm0Sx-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/KfoVm0Sx-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Michael Doran</strong><br>Michael Doran is a senior fellow at the Hudson Institute in Washington, D.C., where he specializes in Middle East security issues and co-hosts the foreign policy-focused “Counterbalance” podcast. Doran previously served as a senior fellow at the Brookings Institution and was a senior director on the National Security Council where he was responsible for helping to devise and coordinate U.S. strategy on a variety of Middle East issues, including Arab-Israeli relations and U.S. efforts to contain Iran and Syria. He also served as a senior advisor in the State Department and was a deputy assistant secretary of defense in the Pentagon. Doran has testified before Congress, written two books, “Ike’s Gamble: America’s Rise to Dominance in the Middle East” and “Pan-Arabism Before Nasser: Egyptian Power Politics And The Palestine Question”, and published articles in <i data-stringify-type="italic">Foreign Affairs</i>, the <i data-stringify-type="italic">American Interest</i>, <i data-stringify-type="italic">Commentary</i>, <i data-stringify-type="italic">Mosaic</i>, the<i data-stringify-type="italic"> Wall Street Journal</i>, <i data-stringify-type="italic">The</i> <i data-stringify-type="italic">Washington Post</i>, and <i data-stringify-type="italic">The</i> <i data-stringify-type="italic">New York Times</i>.</p>
<p><strong>Reuel Marc Gerecht</strong><br>Reuel Marc Gerecht is a former case officer for the CIA, where he served as a Middle Eastern targets officer with the CIA's directorate of operations. He is a senior fellow at the Foundation for Defense of Democracies, a non-partisan organization centered on national security, where he focuses on Iran, sanctions, terrorism, and the Middle East. He is the author of "Know Thy Enemy: A Spy’s Journey into Revolutionary Iran" and "The Islamic Paradox: Shiite Clerics, Sunni Fundamentalists, and the Coming of Arab Democracy," among others.</p>
<p><strong>Bernard Haykel</strong><br>Bernard Haykel is a professor of Near Eastern Studies and the director of the Institute for Transregional Study of the Contemporary Middle East, North Africa, and Central Asia at Princeton University. After working as a post-doctoral research fellow at Oxford University in Islamic Studies, he joined New York University in 1998 as an associate professor before taking up his post at Princeton. He became a Guggenheim fellow in 2010 and is co-editor of the book "Saudi Arabia in Transition: Insights on Social, Political, Economic, and Religious Change."</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Brett McGurk</strong><br>Brett McGurk served as Special Presidential Envoy for the Global Coalition to Defeat ISIS at the U.S. Department of State, where he helped build and then lead the coalition of 75 countries and four international organizations in the global campaign against ISIS. He served in senior positions in the Bush and Obama administrations and has led some of the most sensitive diplomatic missions in the Middle East over the last decade. McGurk is currently the Frank E. and Arthur W. Payne distinguished lecturer at the Freeman Spogli Institute and Center for Security and Cooperation at Stanford University.</p>
<p><strong>Barbara Slavin</strong><br><p style="font-weight: 400;">Barbara Slavin is a distinguished fellow at the Stimson Center, where she is an expert on the Middle East & North Africa. She is also a lecturer in international affairs at George Washington University. Before joining the Stimson Center, she was director of the Future of Iran Initiative and a nonresident senior fellow at the Atlantic Council. She is the author of “Bitter Friends, Bosom Enemies: Iran, the U.S., and the Twisted Path to Confrontation.” She is a regular commentator on U.S. foreign policy and Iran on <em>NPR, PBS, and C-SPAN</em>. Previously, Slavin served as a public policy scholar at the Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars. Slavin is a former career journalist and previously wrote as a columnist for Al-Monitor.com, the assistant managing editor for world and national security at <em>The Washington Times</em>, a senior diplomatic reporter for <em>USA Today</em>, the Cairo and Beijing correspondent for <em>The Economist</em>, and an editor at <em>The New York Times Week in Review</em>.</p></p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Unresolved: Shifting Power in the Middle East</em></p>
<p><u>Trump Is Right on Saudi Arabia</u></p>
<p><u>The World Is Safer Without the JCPOA</u></p>
<p><u>Turkey Is an Asset to NATO</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Recent U.S. Policy Towards China Is Productive</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/recent-us-policy-towards-china-productive</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10265</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> August 02, 2019</p>
<p>The United States is cracking down on China in an attempt to create a more favorable balance of trade. Other concerns include continuing Chinese thefts of intellectual property and the imposition of technology transfer requirements to do business in China. The U.S. seeks to frustrate China’s program to achieve dominance in a range of advanced technologies. And it wants to cripple Huawei, the telecoms giant, which it sees as a potential security threat.
Both parties have instituted punitive tariffs, and both are feeling the impact. China is struggling to maintain its growth rate, yet is still projecting strength as a social, political, and economic leader on the world stage by building ports and bridges all over the world and developing military technology capable of denying the U.S. access to the South China Sea and Taiwan Strait. If successful, Beijing’s ambitious projects and advanced AI and cyber weapons could put Washington on its heels.
Are recent U.S. policies tough and focused enough to achieve key economic and strategic objectives? Or will U.S. policy escalate tensions too much, ultimately reducing the chances that the world’s two major powers can achieve a sensible accommodation?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/cGXkUMxd-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/cGXkUMxd-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Michael Pillsbury</strong><br>Michael Pillsbury is a distinguished defense policy adviser, a former high-ranking government official, and the author of numerous books and reports on China. During the Reagan administration, Pillsbury was assistant undersecretary of defense for policy planning and was responsible for implementing the program of covert aid known as the Reagan Doctrine. He also served as a special assistant for Asian affairs in the Office of the Secretary of Defense under President George H. W. Bush. Pillsbury is a senior fellow and the director for Chinese strategy at the Hudson Institute.</p>
<p><strong>Kori Schake</strong><br>Kori Schake is a senior fellow and the director of foreign and defense policy studies at the American Enterprise Institute (AEI). Dr. Schake is the former deputy director-general of the International Institute for Strategic Studies in London. She has worked at the U.S. State Department, the U.S. Department of Defense, and the National Security Council at the White House. Author of five books, most recently "America vs. the West: Can the Liberal World Order Be Preserved?" Dr. Schake is widely published in policy journals and the popular press. She has a doctorate in government and politics from the University of Maryland.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Graham Allison</strong><br>Graham Allison is the Douglas Dillon professor of government at Harvard Kennedy School, where he has taught for five decades, and a leading analyst of national security. Allison was the founding dean of Harvard’s John F. Kennedy School of Government and served as director of its Belfer Center for Science and International Affairs until 2017. He was assistant secretary of defense under President Clinton and special adviser to the secretary of defense under President Reagan. A best-selling author, Allison’s latest book is "Destined for War: Can America and China Escape Thucydides' Trap?"</p>
<p><strong>Jake Sullivan</strong><br><span data-contrast="none">Jake Sullivan was the 28th Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs (National Security Advisor) during the Biden Administration. In the Obama Administration, he served as National Security Advisor to then-Vice President Biden, Director of the Policy Planning Staff at the U.S. Department of State, and Deputy Chief of Staff to Secretary of State Hillary Clinton. He is currently the Kissinger Professor of the Practice of Statecraft and World Order at the Harvard Kennedy School and a Senior Fellow at the Carsey School of Public Policy at the University of New Hampshire.</span>
<span data-contrast="none">In the years between government service, Sullivan was a Senior Fellow at the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, where he helped conceive a bipartisan task force project on a foreign policy for the middle class. He held teaching posts at the University of New Hampshire, Dartmouth College, and Yale Law School and he co-founded and co-chaired the advisory board for National Security Action. Before entering public office, he clerked for Justice Stephen Breyer of the Supreme Court of the United States.</span></p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>The Recent U.S. Policy Towards China Is Productive</em></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Trade, Tariffs & the TPP</u></p>
<p><u>Huawei & Security Risks</u></p>
<p><u>Intellectual Property Theft</u></p>
<p><u>South China Sea & Taiwan Strait</u></p>
<p><u>Human Rights</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> August 02, 2019</p>
<p>The United States is cracking down on China in an attempt to create a more favorable balance of trade. Other concerns include continuing Chinese thefts of intellectual property and the imposition of technology transfer requirements to do business in China. The U.S. seeks to frustrate China’s program to achieve dominance in a range of advanced technologies. And it wants to cripple Huawei, the telecoms giant, which it sees as a potential security threat.
Both parties have instituted punitive tariffs, and both are feeling the impact. China is struggling to maintain its growth rate, yet is still projecting strength as a social, political, and economic leader on the world stage by building ports and bridges all over the world and developing military technology capable of denying the U.S. access to the South China Sea and Taiwan Strait. If successful, Beijing’s ambitious projects and advanced AI and cyber weapons could put Washington on its heels.
Are recent U.S. policies tough and focused enough to achieve key economic and strategic objectives? Or will U.S. policy escalate tensions too much, ultimately reducing the chances that the world’s two major powers can achieve a sensible accommodation?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/cGXkUMxd-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/cGXkUMxd-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Michael Pillsbury</strong><br>Michael Pillsbury is a distinguished defense policy adviser, a former high-ranking government official, and the author of numerous books and reports on China. During the Reagan administration, Pillsbury was assistant undersecretary of defense for policy planning and was responsible for implementing the program of covert aid known as the Reagan Doctrine. He also served as a special assistant for Asian affairs in the Office of the Secretary of Defense under President George H. W. Bush. Pillsbury is a senior fellow and the director for Chinese strategy at the Hudson Institute.</p>
<p><strong>Kori Schake</strong><br>Kori Schake is a senior fellow and the director of foreign and defense policy studies at the American Enterprise Institute (AEI). Dr. Schake is the former deputy director-general of the International Institute for Strategic Studies in London. She has worked at the U.S. State Department, the U.S. Department of Defense, and the National Security Council at the White House. Author of five books, most recently "America vs. the West: Can the Liberal World Order Be Preserved?" Dr. Schake is widely published in policy journals and the popular press. She has a doctorate in government and politics from the University of Maryland.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Graham Allison</strong><br>Graham Allison is the Douglas Dillon professor of government at Harvard Kennedy School, where he has taught for five decades, and a leading analyst of national security. Allison was the founding dean of Harvard’s John F. Kennedy School of Government and served as director of its Belfer Center for Science and International Affairs until 2017. He was assistant secretary of defense under President Clinton and special adviser to the secretary of defense under President Reagan. A best-selling author, Allison’s latest book is "Destined for War: Can America and China Escape Thucydides' Trap?"</p>
<p><strong>Jake Sullivan</strong><br><span data-contrast="none">Jake Sullivan was the 28th Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs (National Security Advisor) during the Biden Administration. In the Obama Administration, he served as National Security Advisor to then-Vice President Biden, Director of the Policy Planning Staff at the U.S. Department of State, and Deputy Chief of Staff to Secretary of State Hillary Clinton. He is currently the Kissinger Professor of the Practice of Statecraft and World Order at the Harvard Kennedy School and a Senior Fellow at the Carsey School of Public Policy at the University of New Hampshire.</span>
<span data-contrast="none">In the years between government service, Sullivan was a Senior Fellow at the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, where he helped conceive a bipartisan task force project on a foreign policy for the middle class. He held teaching posts at the University of New Hampshire, Dartmouth College, and Yale Law School and he co-founded and co-chaired the advisory board for National Security Action. Before entering public office, he clerked for Justice Stephen Breyer of the Supreme Court of the United States.</span></p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>The Recent U.S. Policy Towards China Is Productive</em></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Trade, Tariffs & the TPP</u></p>
<p><u>Huawei & Security Risks</u></p>
<p><u>Intellectual Property Theft</u></p>
<p><u>South China Sea & Taiwan Strait</u></p>
<p><u>Human Rights</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Transatlantic Relationship Has Been Irreparably Damaged</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/transatlantic-relationship-has-been-irreparably-damaged</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10290</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> June 28, 2019</p>
<p>The transatlantic relationship has been a hallmark of the liberal international order for decades and, for many, a source of global peace and stability. But rising populism and inequality, coupled with surprising election outcomes in the United States and Europe, may signal an end to this historic relationship. Some worry that President Trump's support for Brexit, attacks on NATO, and tariff threats against the EU mark a significant departure from past administrations. And anti-establishment sentiments are growing on the other side of the Atlantic, too, as nationalist leaders gain ground across Europe. But others aren’t as worried, saying the relationship has weathered turbulent times before, including the Iraq War. As long as the U.S. and Europe face common threats, including China, election-hacking, and terrorism, they argue, the bond will remain strong. Is the transatlantic relationship as we know it doomed? Or will it prevail for decades to come?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/Mx0ePVuD-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/Mx0ePVuD-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Federiga Bindi</strong><br>Dr. Federiga Bindi holds the Jean Monnet chair at the University of Rome Tor Vergata, where she was the founding director of the EU Center of Excellence. Dr. Bindi is also a nonresident scholar at the Carnegie Endowment and the director of the Foreign Policy Initiative at the Institute for Women Policy Research in Washington, D.C. Previously, she was a visiting fellow at the Brookings Institution and John Hopkins University, and she served as director of the Italian Cultural Institute in Brussels. Dr. Bindi has published eight books, including "The Foreign Policy of the European Union: Assessing Europe’s Role in the World," "Analyzing European Union Politics," "Italy and the EU," and, most recently, the 2019 book "Europe and America: The End of Transatlantic Relations?"</p>
<p><strong>Constanze Stelzenmüller</strong><br>Dr. Constanze Stelzenmüller is the inaugural Robert Bosch senior fellow at the Center on the United States and Europe at the Brookings Institution. Prior to joining Brookings, she was a senior transatlantic fellow and Berlin office director with the German Marshall Fund of the United States. Her areas of expertise include, among others, transatlantic relations, German foreign policy, and the European Union’s foreign, security, and defense policies. Stelzenmüller was a writer and editor at the German weekly Die Zeit from 1994 to 2005, and her essays and articles have appeared in a wide range of publications, including Foreign Affairs and the Financial Times.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John J. Mearsheimer</strong><br><b></b><span data-contrast="none">John Mearsheimer is a political scientist and the R. Wendell Harrison Distinguished Service Professor in the Political Science Department at the University of Chicago. Before joining the University of Chicago, he was an officer in the U.S. Air Force, a research fellow at the Brookings Institution, and a post-doctoral fellow at Harvard University’s Center for International Affairs. He was also the Whitney H. Shepardson Fellow at the Council on Foreign Relations during the 1998-1999 academic year. Mearsheimer is the author of seven books, including </span><span data-contrast="auto">“Conventional Deterrence”, “The Tragedy of Great Power Politics”, the </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">New York Times</span></i><span data-contrast="auto"> best-seller “The Israel Lobby and U.S. Foreign Policy” (with Stephen M. Walt), and his most recent book “How States Think: The Rationality of Foreign Policy” (with Sebastian Rosato). He has also written many articles that have appeared in academic journals like </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">International Security</span></i><span data-contrast="auto">, and for newspapers and magazines including </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">Foreign Affairs</span></i><span data-contrast="auto">, </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">London Review of Books</span></i><span data-contrast="auto"> </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">The</span></i><span data-contrast="auto"> </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">New York Times,</span></i><span data-contrast="auto"> and the </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">Financial Times</span></i><span data-contrast="auto">, among other publications. He is the recipient of the James Madison Award from the American Political Science Association, received honorary doctorates from universities in China, Greece, and Romania, and was elected to the American Academy of Arts and Sciences.</span></p>
<p><strong>Carla Norrlof</strong><br>Carla Norrlof is an associate professor of political science at the University of Toronto, where she researches international cooperation with a special focus on great powers and, in particular, U.S. hegemony. She is the author of "America’s Global Advantage: US Hegemony and International Cooperation," and her works on cooperation, hegemony, and the international political economy of trade, investment, and conflict have been widely published, including by Cambridge University Press, MIT Press, and Oxford University Press. A Swedish national born in Addis Ababa, Norrlof has lived in Stockholm, Gaborone, New York, Paris, Geneva, and Toronto.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>The Transatlantic Relationship Has Been Irreparably Damaged</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Inside Europe</u></p>
<p><u>American Hegemony</u></p>
<p><u>Looking at NATO</u></p>
<p><u>Free Riding or Burden Sharing?</u></p>
<p><u>Trade & Tariff Threats</u></p>
<p><u>Europe & the Iran Deal</u></p>
<p><u>Rise of China</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> June 28, 2019</p>
<p>The transatlantic relationship has been a hallmark of the liberal international order for decades and, for many, a source of global peace and stability. But rising populism and inequality, coupled with surprising election outcomes in the United States and Europe, may signal an end to this historic relationship. Some worry that President Trump's support for Brexit, attacks on NATO, and tariff threats against the EU mark a significant departure from past administrations. And anti-establishment sentiments are growing on the other side of the Atlantic, too, as nationalist leaders gain ground across Europe. But others aren’t as worried, saying the relationship has weathered turbulent times before, including the Iraq War. As long as the U.S. and Europe face common threats, including China, election-hacking, and terrorism, they argue, the bond will remain strong. Is the transatlantic relationship as we know it doomed? Or will it prevail for decades to come?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/Mx0ePVuD-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/Mx0ePVuD-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Federiga Bindi</strong><br>Dr. Federiga Bindi holds the Jean Monnet chair at the University of Rome Tor Vergata, where she was the founding director of the EU Center of Excellence. Dr. Bindi is also a nonresident scholar at the Carnegie Endowment and the director of the Foreign Policy Initiative at the Institute for Women Policy Research in Washington, D.C. Previously, she was a visiting fellow at the Brookings Institution and John Hopkins University, and she served as director of the Italian Cultural Institute in Brussels. Dr. Bindi has published eight books, including "The Foreign Policy of the European Union: Assessing Europe’s Role in the World," "Analyzing European Union Politics," "Italy and the EU," and, most recently, the 2019 book "Europe and America: The End of Transatlantic Relations?"</p>
<p><strong>Constanze Stelzenmüller</strong><br>Dr. Constanze Stelzenmüller is the inaugural Robert Bosch senior fellow at the Center on the United States and Europe at the Brookings Institution. Prior to joining Brookings, she was a senior transatlantic fellow and Berlin office director with the German Marshall Fund of the United States. Her areas of expertise include, among others, transatlantic relations, German foreign policy, and the European Union’s foreign, security, and defense policies. Stelzenmüller was a writer and editor at the German weekly Die Zeit from 1994 to 2005, and her essays and articles have appeared in a wide range of publications, including Foreign Affairs and the Financial Times.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John J. Mearsheimer</strong><br><b></b><span data-contrast="none">John Mearsheimer is a political scientist and the R. Wendell Harrison Distinguished Service Professor in the Political Science Department at the University of Chicago. Before joining the University of Chicago, he was an officer in the U.S. Air Force, a research fellow at the Brookings Institution, and a post-doctoral fellow at Harvard University’s Center for International Affairs. He was also the Whitney H. Shepardson Fellow at the Council on Foreign Relations during the 1998-1999 academic year. Mearsheimer is the author of seven books, including </span><span data-contrast="auto">“Conventional Deterrence”, “The Tragedy of Great Power Politics”, the </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">New York Times</span></i><span data-contrast="auto"> best-seller “The Israel Lobby and U.S. Foreign Policy” (with Stephen M. Walt), and his most recent book “How States Think: The Rationality of Foreign Policy” (with Sebastian Rosato). He has also written many articles that have appeared in academic journals like </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">International Security</span></i><span data-contrast="auto">, and for newspapers and magazines including </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">Foreign Affairs</span></i><span data-contrast="auto">, </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">London Review of Books</span></i><span data-contrast="auto"> </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">The</span></i><span data-contrast="auto"> </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">New York Times,</span></i><span data-contrast="auto"> and the </span><i><span data-contrast="auto">Financial Times</span></i><span data-contrast="auto">, among other publications. He is the recipient of the James Madison Award from the American Political Science Association, received honorary doctorates from universities in China, Greece, and Romania, and was elected to the American Academy of Arts and Sciences.</span></p>
<p><strong>Carla Norrlof</strong><br>Carla Norrlof is an associate professor of political science at the University of Toronto, where she researches international cooperation with a special focus on great powers and, in particular, U.S. hegemony. She is the author of "America’s Global Advantage: US Hegemony and International Cooperation," and her works on cooperation, hegemony, and the international political economy of trade, investment, and conflict have been widely published, including by Cambridge University Press, MIT Press, and Oxford University Press. A Swedish national born in Addis Ababa, Norrlof has lived in Stockholm, Gaborone, New York, Paris, Geneva, and Toronto.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>The Transatlantic Relationship Has Been Irreparably Damaged</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Inside Europe</u></p>
<p><u>American Hegemony</u></p>
<p><u>Looking at NATO</u></p>
<p><u>Free Riding or Burden Sharing?</u></p>
<p><u>Trade & Tariff Threats</u></p>
<p><u>Europe & the Iran Deal</u></p>
<p><u>Rise of China</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Is Engineering Solar Radiation A Crazy Idea?</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/engineering-solar-radiation-crazy-idea</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10097</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> April 18, 2019</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Energy, Environment, Science</p>
<p>Geoengineering is an ambitious set of experiments proposed by scientists to help mitigate the effects of climate change. And one type in particular, called solar geoengineering, has been the subject of debate. This process involves, among other techniques, injecting reflective particles into the stratosphere to reduce the amount of sun and heat that reaches the planet. The goal? To decrease global temperatures. Proponents argue this process would be inexpensive and effective. Plus, they say, it could limit changes in glacier melt and lessen the intensity of tropical storms. But challengers argue these techniques do not address the underlying issues of climate change, and they worry that solar geoengineering could alter weather systems or possibly even cool the planet too much. They also point to governance issues: Any country could engage these strategies, triggering the possibility of unintended consequences that could affect us all. Is solar geoengineering a radical idea? Or is it likely to emerge as an important, supplemental tool in the fight against climate change?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/XLKotiQa-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/XLKotiQa-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Clive Hamilton</strong><br>Clive Hamilton is a professor of public ethics at Charles Sturt University in Canberra. Previously, he founded the Australia Institute, a leading progressive think tank, and he was appointed by the Australian government to the Climate Change Authority in 2012. His books on climate change include "Requiem for a Species: Why We Resist the Truth About Climate Change," "Earthmasters: The Dawn of the Age of Climate Engineering," and "Defiant Earth: The Fate of Humans in the Anthropocene." Most recently, Hamilton is the author of "Silent Invasion: China’s Influence in Australia," which became an immediate best-seller.</p>
<p><strong>Anjali Viswamohanan</strong><br>Anjali Viswamohanan is a Chevening scholar at the Blavatnik School of Government at Oxford University and an energy policy enthusiast. She focuses on developing and assessing the feasibility of energy transition scenarios in response to the perpetually evolving technology mix. Viswamohanan has previously worked with the Council on Energy, Environment, and Water in New Delhi on renewable energy policy, finance, and governance issues. She is a lawyer by training and has worked at some of India’s top law firms on energy projects and public-private partnerships in the Indian infrastructure space.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>David Keith</strong><br>David Keith has worked at the interface between climate science, energy technology, and public policy for 25 years. Best known for his work on the science, technology, and public policy of solar geoengineering, he led the development of Harvard’s Solar Geoengineering Research Program. He took first prize in Canada's national physics prize exam, won MIT’s prize for excellence in experimental physics, and was one of TIME magazine's "Heroes of the Environment." Keith is a professor at the Harvard School of Engineering and Applied Sciences  and the Harvard Kennedy School and the founder of Carbon Engineering, a company developing technology to capture CO2 from ambient air.</p>
<p><strong>Ted Parson</strong><br>Edward Parson is the faculty co-director of the Emmett Institute on Climate Change and the Environment at UCLA, where he is also the Dan and Rae Emmett professor of environmental law. Parson studies international environmental law and policy, the role of science and technology in policymaking, and the political economy of regulation. His books include "The Science and Politics of Global Climate Change" and "Protecting the Ozone Layer: Science and Strategy," which won the International Studies Association’s Sprout award. He has worked for and consulted for the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy and the U.N. Environment Program.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Engineering Solar Radiation Is a Crazy Idea</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Climate Change</u></p>
<p><u>Governance</u></p>
<p><u>Playing God?</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> April 18, 2019</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Energy, Environment, Science</p>
<p>Geoengineering is an ambitious set of experiments proposed by scientists to help mitigate the effects of climate change. And one type in particular, called solar geoengineering, has been the subject of debate. This process involves, among other techniques, injecting reflective particles into the stratosphere to reduce the amount of sun and heat that reaches the planet. The goal? To decrease global temperatures. Proponents argue this process would be inexpensive and effective. Plus, they say, it could limit changes in glacier melt and lessen the intensity of tropical storms. But challengers argue these techniques do not address the underlying issues of climate change, and they worry that solar geoengineering could alter weather systems or possibly even cool the planet too much. They also point to governance issues: Any country could engage these strategies, triggering the possibility of unintended consequences that could affect us all. Is solar geoengineering a radical idea? Or is it likely to emerge as an important, supplemental tool in the fight against climate change?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/XLKotiQa-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/XLKotiQa-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Clive Hamilton</strong><br>Clive Hamilton is a professor of public ethics at Charles Sturt University in Canberra. Previously, he founded the Australia Institute, a leading progressive think tank, and he was appointed by the Australian government to the Climate Change Authority in 2012. His books on climate change include "Requiem for a Species: Why We Resist the Truth About Climate Change," "Earthmasters: The Dawn of the Age of Climate Engineering," and "Defiant Earth: The Fate of Humans in the Anthropocene." Most recently, Hamilton is the author of "Silent Invasion: China’s Influence in Australia," which became an immediate best-seller.</p>
<p><strong>Anjali Viswamohanan</strong><br>Anjali Viswamohanan is a Chevening scholar at the Blavatnik School of Government at Oxford University and an energy policy enthusiast. She focuses on developing and assessing the feasibility of energy transition scenarios in response to the perpetually evolving technology mix. Viswamohanan has previously worked with the Council on Energy, Environment, and Water in New Delhi on renewable energy policy, finance, and governance issues. She is a lawyer by training and has worked at some of India’s top law firms on energy projects and public-private partnerships in the Indian infrastructure space.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>David Keith</strong><br>David Keith has worked at the interface between climate science, energy technology, and public policy for 25 years. Best known for his work on the science, technology, and public policy of solar geoengineering, he led the development of Harvard’s Solar Geoengineering Research Program. He took first prize in Canada's national physics prize exam, won MIT’s prize for excellence in experimental physics, and was one of TIME magazine's "Heroes of the Environment." Keith is a professor at the Harvard School of Engineering and Applied Sciences  and the Harvard Kennedy School and the founder of Carbon Engineering, a company developing technology to capture CO2 from ambient air.</p>
<p><strong>Ted Parson</strong><br>Edward Parson is the faculty co-director of the Emmett Institute on Climate Change and the Environment at UCLA, where he is also the Dan and Rae Emmett professor of environmental law. Parson studies international environmental law and policy, the role of science and technology in policymaking, and the political economy of regulation. His books include "The Science and Politics of Global Climate Change" and "Protecting the Ozone Layer: Science and Strategy," which won the International Studies Association’s Sprout award. He has worked for and consulted for the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy and the U.N. Environment Program.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Engineering Solar Radiation Is a Crazy Idea</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Climate Change</u></p>
<p><u>Governance</u></p>
<p><u>Playing God?</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Republican Party Should Not Re-Nominate Trump</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/republican-party-should-not-re-nominate-trump</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10268</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> March 28, 2019</p>
<p>Americans are gearing up for the 2020 presidential elections, and Republicans have a choice: Should Donald Trump be their nominee? His detractors see a politically vulnerable candidate caught up in the uncertainty of the Mueller investigation, wounded by the longest government shutdown in history, and defeated by House Democrats who refused his demand for border wall funding. But many are standing behind the president. They argue his passionate and loyal base will deliver yet another political win, particularly if his campaign finally has the full support and guidance of the Republican Party. Can Trump deliver key swing states and another victory for the GOP? Or is he the wrong choice for the American right?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/jkt6eTEM-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/jkt6eTEM-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Jeff Flake</strong><br>The Honorable Jeff Flake is the former U.S. Senator from Arizona, where he served from 2013 to 2019. Before that, he served six terms in the House of Representatives representing Arizona’s 6th Congressional District. Senator Flake is the author of the 2017 New York Times best-seller “Conscience of a Conservative: A Rejection of Destructive Politics and a Return to Principle,” where he takes a stand for civility in an era of hyper-partisanship. He is currently a contributor to CBS News, a guest lecturer at Princeton, and a guest speaker at Yale.</p>
<p><strong>Bret Stephens</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">Bret Stephens is a Pulitzer Prize-winning journalist, an op-ed columnist for </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">The New York Times</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">, and a political contributor at NBC and MSNBC. Prior to joining the </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">Times</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">, he worked at the </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">Wall Street Journal </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">where he was the deputy editorial page editor in charge of international opinion and, for 11 years, the principal foreign-affairs columnist. Before that, he was editor-in-chief of </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">The Jerusalem Post</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">. At </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">The Jerusalem Post</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">, he oversaw the paper’s news, editorial, digital, and international operations, and wrote a weekly column. Stephens is the author of “America in Retreat: The New Isolationism and the Coming Global Disorder,” “The Dying Art of Disagreement,” and “Has Obama Made the World a More Dangerous Place?: The Munk Debate on U.S. Foreign Policy.” He is the recipient of numerous awards and distinctions, including three honorary doctorates, the Ellis Island Medal of Honor, and the 2013 Pulitzer Prize for Commentary in his columns on American foreign policy and domestic politics. He is also the editor-in-chief of SAPIR: A Journal of Jewish Conversations, which is published by the Maimonides Fund. Stephens holds a B.A. from the University of Chicago and an MSc. from the London School of Economics.</span></span><span class="EOP SCXO29872669 BCX0"> </span></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Kris Kobach</strong><br>Kris W. Kobach is the former secretary of state for Kansas and a former professor of constitutional law at the University of Missouri in Kansas City. He is currently an advisory board member of We Build the Wall, Inc., a non-profit group aiming to fund and build a wall along America’s southern border. Kobach served on the Trump transition team and was co-chair, with Vice President Mike Pence, of the Presidential Commission on Election Integrity. He also served as counsel to Attorney General John Ashcroft during the Bush administration.</p>
<p><strong>Liz Peek</strong><br>Liz Peek is a Fox News contributor and a columnist for The Hill and FoxNews. She has written for the bipartisan FiscalTimes, the New York Post, the Wall Street Journal, the New York Sun, and numerous other publications. Prior to becoming a journalist, Peek was a top-ranked research analyst covering oil field companies. She was the first female partner of Wertheim & Company and the first woman to become president of the National Association of Petroleum Investment Analysts.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>The Dump Trump Debate</strong> <small>2019-10-17 20:14:09</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Robert Rosenkranz, a financier and a philanthropist, believes in civility. Since 2006, his foundation has sponsored a series of public debates called Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S., in which two experts argue for a resolution Charter schools are overrated and video games will make us smarter and two argue against it. “The audience votes twice, on their phones, once before the debate and once after it’s over,” Rosenkranz said recently. “The hope is that a significant portion will change their minds, or will come away with a more nuanced understanding of the other side.”</p>
<p>The debate topics are supposed to reflect popular interest. For the past few years, an outsized amount of popular interest has centered on one stable genius and his Twitter account. This puts Rosenkranz in a bind. “Our goal is to raise the level of discourse,” he said. “If you put ‘Donald Trump (https://www.newyorker.com/tag/donald-trump)’ in the title of a debate, it’s hard for anyone to listen with an open mind.”</p>
<p>On a recent Thursday night at Hunter College, however, the elephant in the room was acknowledged. The resolution was “The Republican Party should not re-nominate Donald Trump.” The four debaters, all Republicans, made up what Abraham Lincoln might have called a team of rivals, except for the “team” part. Arguing against the resolution that is, for keeping Trump were Liz Peek, a Fox News contributor, and Kris Kobach, a former secretary of state of Kansas who interviewed, unsuccessfully, to be Trump’s Secretary of Homeland Security. (Last year, he ran, also unsuccessfully, for governor of Kansas.) Arguing for the resolution were Bret Stephens, a Times columnist and a Never Trump conservative, and Jeff Flake (https://www.newyorker.com/tag/jeff-flake), who served as a Republican senator from Arizona until earlier this year. His 2017 book, “Conscience of a Conservative (https://www.amazon.com/dp/0399592911/?tag=thneyo0f-20),” was a long subtweet about how Trump was destroying Flake’s beloved party.</p>
<p>Rosenkranz met the debaters in a greenroom. “Now, this man looks like a Hollywood casting agent’s idea of a U.S. senator!” Rosenkranz said, shaking Flake’s hand. Flake is tall and coiffed; he has a natural non-orange tan and an aw-shucks smile. “Those days are long gone,” he said. He had recently returned to D.C. for the first time as an ex-senator. “I stopped by the cloakroom in the Senate to visit some of my old friends,” he said. The President had just been there for lunch. “I said, ‘There are things I miss, but that is not one of them.’ ”</p>
<p>After a sound check, Flake and Kobach commiserated about the monotony of involuntary early retirement. “What have you been up to?” Kobach asked.</p>
<p>“Not much,” Flake said. “Back in Arizona. We’re moving, so that’s keeping me busy. You?”</p>
<p>“Back in Kansas,” Kobach said. “You know how it is.”</p>
<p>Flake, a pro-immigration conservative, was against Trump’s proposed border wall. Kobach supports it. “I’ve joined the advisory board of We Build the Wall,” Kobach told Flake. “So I’ve actually been traveling to your state a lot, talking to landowners on the border.” He was referring to a nonprofit that aims to build a wall using only crowdfunding and donated land. Flake winced, then forced a diplomatic smile. “Is that right?” he said.</p>
<p>The debaters took the stage, and the audience submitted its pre-debate vote: sixty-one percent in favor of dumping Trump, twenty-one percent opposed, and eighteen percent undecided. Stephens gave his opening statement. “Ladies and gentlemen, good evening,” he began. “Kris, buenas noches.” Kobach, shuffling his notes, smiled gamely. Then Stephens posed a question: Would the G.O.P. continue to be “the party of Abraham Lincoln, Teddy Roosevelt, Ronald Reagan,” or would it become “the party of Pat Buchanan, Steve Bannon, Donald Trump, and Kris Kobach”? Kobach smiled again, less gamely. Stephens snuck in a dig: “Kris just lost his race for governor of Kansas!” This time, Kobach didn’t even pretend to smile.</p>
<p>“I would encourage the debaters to not have to name people on the other side of the table to make their arguments,” the moderator said.</p></div>
<div><strong>Tom Ginsburg Debates Whether Trump Should Be Indicted on Intelligence Squared / Open to Debate Podcast</strong> <small>2023-02-07 23:01:46</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Should Trump Be Indicted?</p>
<p>After a series of prime-time hearings from the January 6th Committee and hundreds of charges against individuals who participated in the events of that day, the Department of Justice faces a complex political and legal question: Should it charge Donald Trump with federal crimes? Those calling on Attorney General Merrick Garland to act argue that no person is above the law and that the Committee's investigations have unearthed more than enough evidence to bring a variety of charges against the former president. But still, others warn that indicting a former president who has signaled interest in returning to the campaign trail in 2024 and who enjoys considerable support in the Republican party will even further fraction the nation's political divisions. Would indicting President Trump set a dangerous precedent and deepen political hostility in the run-up to a major presidential election? Or would failing to indict him prove even worse?</p>
<p>Read more at Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. (http://opentodebate.org)</p></div>
<div><strong>Open to Debate Podcast: Should Trump Be Indicted?</strong> <small>2023-02-07 23:06:48</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>There are many issues in our lives where neutral opinions are replaced with hard-line views. Should the toilet paper roll be over or under when placed on the holder? Should ketchup be used as a condiment for breakfast, or is it strictly for french fries and burgers? Is there a place for a mullet in polite society?</p></div>
<div><strong>The Trump Colorado Case: Right Analysis, Wrong Outcome</strong> <small>2023-12-21 15:59:07</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>I read the dissent of the Colorado Supreme Court’s 4-3 decision, written by the court’s chief justice, Brian Boatright. I agree with Justice Boatright’s opinion.</p>
<p>I agree with the detailed analysis of the majority opinion that there is substantial evidence in the public record that Donald Trump violated Section 3 of the 14th Amendment – i.e., that he participated in an insurrection criminal conspiracy to thwart the lawful election of Joe Biden.</p>
<p>But it is not good for the country, and not good law, for Trump to be barred from running in 2024 without due process of law, which means a trial, the right to cross-examination, and a verdict of guilt by a jury “beyond a reasonable doubt.”</p>
<p>The irony of course is that the ultimate abuser and denier of our U.S. Constitution, the rule of law, and due process is Donald J. Trump. Remember his leading the 2016 cheers to “Lock her up!” This was a reference to Hillary Clinton’s practice of storing her State Department emails on a private server. He did not insist that Hillary Clinton be provided due process before leading that cheer. As we now know, the inspector general of the State Department did not find she had violated any criminal laws and FBI Director James Comey – no Hillary Clinton fan – agreed that not one of the 33,000 emails she transferred to her private server contained recognizable classified markings.</p>
<p>But that example cuts both ways. Yes, it is obviously hypocritical for Trump and his supporters to scream about due process in the Colorado case. But Mrs. Clinton’s example also shows why due process is so important. She was never convicted of anything. And, so far at least, neither has Trump.</p>
<p>Winning a criminal insurrection conspiracy case won’t be a cakewalk for Special Counsel Jack Smith. I say this because on Dec. 14 I participated as playing Smith’s role as “prosecutor” in a mock trial sponsored by the nationally respected nonprofit organization Open to Debate (https://opentodebate.org/debates/). Our mock argument was live-streamed last week, but it can be heard again on Jan. 5, 2024, the day before the anniversary of the Jan. 6 insurrection effort, on an NPR local affiliate; seen and heard on YouTube here (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X2AQxFtqh-4); on opentodebate.org; or on available podcast channels.</p>
<p>During this mock trial, the Trump side was represented by Sara Azari (https://www.azarilaw.com/sara-azari), a Los Angeles-based defense lawyer. Sara argued not only the absence of a smoking gun admission or written evidence by Trump that he knew he had lost the election; she also effectively argued that Trump’s claims, though false, are protected as political speech under the First Amendment.</p>
<p>My response was that the First Amendment does not protect lies that are part of a criminal conspiracy. I pointed out that there will be testimony from several people that Trump admitted he had lost but lied about it. However, I also pointed out that a jury can conclude beyond a reasonable doubt that he knew that the voter fraud did not cost him the election because the highest officials of his government, whom he appointed, all told him he had lost, including the attorney general, senior Justice Department officials, the director of national intelligence, and every single state official in the key battleground states whom he called. Georgia’s secretary of state of told him he had lost after three separate recounts. Still Trump asked him to “find” one vote more than the total Biden was found to have won Georgia – proving he knew he was asking the secretary of state to lie.</p>
<p>I also pointed out that 61 out of 61 state court judges rejected his claim that he had lost these key battleground states because of voter fraud. (Once in Pennsylvania, a court found some voter fraud, but that judge also ruled it wasn’t significant enough to change the outcome in that state).</p>
<p>In any event, there will and must be a test of Donald Trump’s culpability, but that must come in a trial, with due process by a finder of fact that reaches a verdict beyond a reasonable doubt. America cannot accept a verdict barring Trump from running for office based on a court hearing 1,500 miles from Washington, D.C., without a trial, on a civil court standard of “preponderance of the evidence” – meaning anything above 50%.</p>
<p>Those of us who oppose Trump can beat him at the ballot box, especially if and when he is convicted of felonies in one or more of the criminal trials he faces in federal and state courts. Colorado’s chief justice was right in his dissent when he concluded Trump should not be barred by a state court “in the absence of an insurrection-related conviction” – the latter word meaning after a trial and a jury of his peers finds the defendant guilty “beyond a reasonable doubt.”</p>
<p>Lanny Davis is the founder of the Washington, D.C., law firm, Lanny J. Davis & Associates. He is one of the first to use the concept of legal crisis management to solve client problems – operating at the intersection of law, media, and politics. He is a former special counsel to President Bill Clinton in 1996-98 and served on a privacy and civil liberties panel appointed by President George W. Bush. He has been writing his “Purple Nation” column for more than 13 years.</p></div>
<div><strong>Open to Debate: Is the Republican Party’s Refusal to Raise Taxes Fiscally Irresponsible?</strong> <small>2024-02-27 16:49:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Whether to extend four trillion dollars in tax cuts or raise them next year is in question, with 34.1 trillion dollars in federal debt hanging in the balance. Some argue that tax cuts don’t do enough to pay off the debt and not raising taxes imbalances the federal budget. Others argue our debt is caused by government overspending and will be helped by tax cuts that help promote a flourishing economy. Now we debate: Is the Republican Party’s Refusal to Raise Taxes Fiscally Irresponsible?</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>The Republican Party Should Not Re-Nominate Trump</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Polls & Stats</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Historical Precedent</u></p>
<p><u>America’s Economy</u></p>
<p><u>Immigration</u></p>
<p><u>Trump & Women</u></p>
<p><u>Possible Primary Challengers</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> March 28, 2019</p>
<p>Americans are gearing up for the 2020 presidential elections, and Republicans have a choice: Should Donald Trump be their nominee? His detractors see a politically vulnerable candidate caught up in the uncertainty of the Mueller investigation, wounded by the longest government shutdown in history, and defeated by House Democrats who refused his demand for border wall funding. But many are standing behind the president. They argue his passionate and loyal base will deliver yet another political win, particularly if his campaign finally has the full support and guidance of the Republican Party. Can Trump deliver key swing states and another victory for the GOP? Or is he the wrong choice for the American right?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/jkt6eTEM-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/jkt6eTEM-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Jeff Flake</strong><br>The Honorable Jeff Flake is the former U.S. Senator from Arizona, where he served from 2013 to 2019. Before that, he served six terms in the House of Representatives representing Arizona’s 6th Congressional District. Senator Flake is the author of the 2017 New York Times best-seller “Conscience of a Conservative: A Rejection of Destructive Politics and a Return to Principle,” where he takes a stand for civility in an era of hyper-partisanship. He is currently a contributor to CBS News, a guest lecturer at Princeton, and a guest speaker at Yale.</p>
<p><strong>Bret Stephens</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">Bret Stephens is a Pulitzer Prize-winning journalist, an op-ed columnist for </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">The New York Times</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">, and a political contributor at NBC and MSNBC. Prior to joining the </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">Times</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">, he worked at the </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">Wall Street Journal </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">where he was the deputy editorial page editor in charge of international opinion and, for 11 years, the principal foreign-affairs columnist. Before that, he was editor-in-chief of </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">The Jerusalem Post</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">. At </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">The Jerusalem Post</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">, he oversaw the paper’s news, editorial, digital, and international operations, and wrote a weekly column. Stephens is the author of “America in Retreat: The New Isolationism and the Coming Global Disorder,” “The Dying Art of Disagreement,” and “Has Obama Made the World a More Dangerous Place?: The Munk Debate on U.S. Foreign Policy.” He is the recipient of numerous awards and distinctions, including three honorary doctorates, the Ellis Island Medal of Honor, and the 2013 Pulitzer Prize for Commentary in his columns on American foreign policy and domestic politics. He is also the editor-in-chief of SAPIR: A Journal of Jewish Conversations, which is published by the Maimonides Fund. Stephens holds a B.A. from the University of Chicago and an MSc. from the London School of Economics.</span></span><span class="EOP SCXO29872669 BCX0"> </span></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Kris Kobach</strong><br>Kris W. Kobach is the former secretary of state for Kansas and a former professor of constitutional law at the University of Missouri in Kansas City. He is currently an advisory board member of We Build the Wall, Inc., a non-profit group aiming to fund and build a wall along America’s southern border. Kobach served on the Trump transition team and was co-chair, with Vice President Mike Pence, of the Presidential Commission on Election Integrity. He also served as counsel to Attorney General John Ashcroft during the Bush administration.</p>
<p><strong>Liz Peek</strong><br>Liz Peek is a Fox News contributor and a columnist for The Hill and FoxNews. She has written for the bipartisan FiscalTimes, the New York Post, the Wall Street Journal, the New York Sun, and numerous other publications. Prior to becoming a journalist, Peek was a top-ranked research analyst covering oil field companies. She was the first female partner of Wertheim & Company and the first woman to become president of the National Association of Petroleum Investment Analysts.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>The Dump Trump Debate</strong> <small>2019-10-17 20:14:09</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Robert Rosenkranz, a financier and a philanthropist, believes in civility. Since 2006, his foundation has sponsored a series of public debates called Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S., in which two experts argue for a resolution Charter schools are overrated and video games will make us smarter and two argue against it. “The audience votes twice, on their phones, once before the debate and once after it’s over,” Rosenkranz said recently. “The hope is that a significant portion will change their minds, or will come away with a more nuanced understanding of the other side.”</p>
<p>The debate topics are supposed to reflect popular interest. For the past few years, an outsized amount of popular interest has centered on one stable genius and his Twitter account. This puts Rosenkranz in a bind. “Our goal is to raise the level of discourse,” he said. “If you put ‘Donald Trump (https://www.newyorker.com/tag/donald-trump)’ in the title of a debate, it’s hard for anyone to listen with an open mind.”</p>
<p>On a recent Thursday night at Hunter College, however, the elephant in the room was acknowledged. The resolution was “The Republican Party should not re-nominate Donald Trump.” The four debaters, all Republicans, made up what Abraham Lincoln might have called a team of rivals, except for the “team” part. Arguing against the resolution that is, for keeping Trump were Liz Peek, a Fox News contributor, and Kris Kobach, a former secretary of state of Kansas who interviewed, unsuccessfully, to be Trump’s Secretary of Homeland Security. (Last year, he ran, also unsuccessfully, for governor of Kansas.) Arguing for the resolution were Bret Stephens, a Times columnist and a Never Trump conservative, and Jeff Flake (https://www.newyorker.com/tag/jeff-flake), who served as a Republican senator from Arizona until earlier this year. His 2017 book, “Conscience of a Conservative (https://www.amazon.com/dp/0399592911/?tag=thneyo0f-20),” was a long subtweet about how Trump was destroying Flake’s beloved party.</p>
<p>Rosenkranz met the debaters in a greenroom. “Now, this man looks like a Hollywood casting agent’s idea of a U.S. senator!” Rosenkranz said, shaking Flake’s hand. Flake is tall and coiffed; he has a natural non-orange tan and an aw-shucks smile. “Those days are long gone,” he said. He had recently returned to D.C. for the first time as an ex-senator. “I stopped by the cloakroom in the Senate to visit some of my old friends,” he said. The President had just been there for lunch. “I said, ‘There are things I miss, but that is not one of them.’ ”</p>
<p>After a sound check, Flake and Kobach commiserated about the monotony of involuntary early retirement. “What have you been up to?” Kobach asked.</p>
<p>“Not much,” Flake said. “Back in Arizona. We’re moving, so that’s keeping me busy. You?”</p>
<p>“Back in Kansas,” Kobach said. “You know how it is.”</p>
<p>Flake, a pro-immigration conservative, was against Trump’s proposed border wall. Kobach supports it. “I’ve joined the advisory board of We Build the Wall,” Kobach told Flake. “So I’ve actually been traveling to your state a lot, talking to landowners on the border.” He was referring to a nonprofit that aims to build a wall using only crowdfunding and donated land. Flake winced, then forced a diplomatic smile. “Is that right?” he said.</p>
<p>The debaters took the stage, and the audience submitted its pre-debate vote: sixty-one percent in favor of dumping Trump, twenty-one percent opposed, and eighteen percent undecided. Stephens gave his opening statement. “Ladies and gentlemen, good evening,” he began. “Kris, buenas noches.” Kobach, shuffling his notes, smiled gamely. Then Stephens posed a question: Would the G.O.P. continue to be “the party of Abraham Lincoln, Teddy Roosevelt, Ronald Reagan,” or would it become “the party of Pat Buchanan, Steve Bannon, Donald Trump, and Kris Kobach”? Kobach smiled again, less gamely. Stephens snuck in a dig: “Kris just lost his race for governor of Kansas!” This time, Kobach didn’t even pretend to smile.</p>
<p>“I would encourage the debaters to not have to name people on the other side of the table to make their arguments,” the moderator said.</p></div>
<div><strong>Tom Ginsburg Debates Whether Trump Should Be Indicted on Intelligence Squared / Open to Debate Podcast</strong> <small>2023-02-07 23:01:46</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Should Trump Be Indicted?</p>
<p>After a series of prime-time hearings from the January 6th Committee and hundreds of charges against individuals who participated in the events of that day, the Department of Justice faces a complex political and legal question: Should it charge Donald Trump with federal crimes? Those calling on Attorney General Merrick Garland to act argue that no person is above the law and that the Committee's investigations have unearthed more than enough evidence to bring a variety of charges against the former president. But still, others warn that indicting a former president who has signaled interest in returning to the campaign trail in 2024 and who enjoys considerable support in the Republican party will even further fraction the nation's political divisions. Would indicting President Trump set a dangerous precedent and deepen political hostility in the run-up to a major presidential election? Or would failing to indict him prove even worse?</p>
<p>Read more at Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. (http://opentodebate.org)</p></div>
<div><strong>Open to Debate Podcast: Should Trump Be Indicted?</strong> <small>2023-02-07 23:06:48</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>There are many issues in our lives where neutral opinions are replaced with hard-line views. Should the toilet paper roll be over or under when placed on the holder? Should ketchup be used as a condiment for breakfast, or is it strictly for french fries and burgers? Is there a place for a mullet in polite society?</p></div>
<div><strong>The Trump Colorado Case: Right Analysis, Wrong Outcome</strong> <small>2023-12-21 15:59:07</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>I read the dissent of the Colorado Supreme Court’s 4-3 decision, written by the court’s chief justice, Brian Boatright. I agree with Justice Boatright’s opinion.</p>
<p>I agree with the detailed analysis of the majority opinion that there is substantial evidence in the public record that Donald Trump violated Section 3 of the 14th Amendment – i.e., that he participated in an insurrection criminal conspiracy to thwart the lawful election of Joe Biden.</p>
<p>But it is not good for the country, and not good law, for Trump to be barred from running in 2024 without due process of law, which means a trial, the right to cross-examination, and a verdict of guilt by a jury “beyond a reasonable doubt.”</p>
<p>The irony of course is that the ultimate abuser and denier of our U.S. Constitution, the rule of law, and due process is Donald J. Trump. Remember his leading the 2016 cheers to “Lock her up!” This was a reference to Hillary Clinton’s practice of storing her State Department emails on a private server. He did not insist that Hillary Clinton be provided due process before leading that cheer. As we now know, the inspector general of the State Department did not find she had violated any criminal laws and FBI Director James Comey – no Hillary Clinton fan – agreed that not one of the 33,000 emails she transferred to her private server contained recognizable classified markings.</p>
<p>But that example cuts both ways. Yes, it is obviously hypocritical for Trump and his supporters to scream about due process in the Colorado case. But Mrs. Clinton’s example also shows why due process is so important. She was never convicted of anything. And, so far at least, neither has Trump.</p>
<p>Winning a criminal insurrection conspiracy case won’t be a cakewalk for Special Counsel Jack Smith. I say this because on Dec. 14 I participated as playing Smith’s role as “prosecutor” in a mock trial sponsored by the nationally respected nonprofit organization Open to Debate (https://opentodebate.org/debates/). Our mock argument was live-streamed last week, but it can be heard again on Jan. 5, 2024, the day before the anniversary of the Jan. 6 insurrection effort, on an NPR local affiliate; seen and heard on YouTube here (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X2AQxFtqh-4); on opentodebate.org; or on available podcast channels.</p>
<p>During this mock trial, the Trump side was represented by Sara Azari (https://www.azarilaw.com/sara-azari), a Los Angeles-based defense lawyer. Sara argued not only the absence of a smoking gun admission or written evidence by Trump that he knew he had lost the election; she also effectively argued that Trump’s claims, though false, are protected as political speech under the First Amendment.</p>
<p>My response was that the First Amendment does not protect lies that are part of a criminal conspiracy. I pointed out that there will be testimony from several people that Trump admitted he had lost but lied about it. However, I also pointed out that a jury can conclude beyond a reasonable doubt that he knew that the voter fraud did not cost him the election because the highest officials of his government, whom he appointed, all told him he had lost, including the attorney general, senior Justice Department officials, the director of national intelligence, and every single state official in the key battleground states whom he called. Georgia’s secretary of state of told him he had lost after three separate recounts. Still Trump asked him to “find” one vote more than the total Biden was found to have won Georgia – proving he knew he was asking the secretary of state to lie.</p>
<p>I also pointed out that 61 out of 61 state court judges rejected his claim that he had lost these key battleground states because of voter fraud. (Once in Pennsylvania, a court found some voter fraud, but that judge also ruled it wasn’t significant enough to change the outcome in that state).</p>
<p>In any event, there will and must be a test of Donald Trump’s culpability, but that must come in a trial, with due process by a finder of fact that reaches a verdict beyond a reasonable doubt. America cannot accept a verdict barring Trump from running for office based on a court hearing 1,500 miles from Washington, D.C., without a trial, on a civil court standard of “preponderance of the evidence” – meaning anything above 50%.</p>
<p>Those of us who oppose Trump can beat him at the ballot box, especially if and when he is convicted of felonies in one or more of the criminal trials he faces in federal and state courts. Colorado’s chief justice was right in his dissent when he concluded Trump should not be barred by a state court “in the absence of an insurrection-related conviction” – the latter word meaning after a trial and a jury of his peers finds the defendant guilty “beyond a reasonable doubt.”</p>
<p>Lanny Davis is the founder of the Washington, D.C., law firm, Lanny J. Davis & Associates. He is one of the first to use the concept of legal crisis management to solve client problems – operating at the intersection of law, media, and politics. He is a former special counsel to President Bill Clinton in 1996-98 and served on a privacy and civil liberties panel appointed by President George W. Bush. He has been writing his “Purple Nation” column for more than 13 years.</p></div>
<div><strong>Open to Debate: Is the Republican Party’s Refusal to Raise Taxes Fiscally Irresponsible?</strong> <small>2024-02-27 16:49:55</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Whether to extend four trillion dollars in tax cuts or raise them next year is in question, with 34.1 trillion dollars in federal debt hanging in the balance. Some argue that tax cuts don’t do enough to pay off the debt and not raising taxes imbalances the federal budget. Others argue our debt is caused by government overspending and will be helped by tax cuts that help promote a flourishing economy. Now we debate: Is the Republican Party’s Refusal to Raise Taxes Fiscally Irresponsible?</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>The Republican Party Should Not Re-Nominate Trump</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Polls & Stats</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Historical Precedent</u></p>
<p><u>America’s Economy</u></p>
<p><u>Immigration</u></p>
<p><u>Trump & Women</u></p>
<p><u>Possible Primary Challengers</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Constitutional Free Speech Principles Can Save Social Media Companies from Themselves</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/constitutional-free-speech-principles-can-save-social-media-companies-themselves</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10064</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> March 04, 2019</p>
<p>How should the world’s largest social media companies respond to a pernicious online climate, including hate speech and false content posted by users? For some, the answer is clear: take the fake and offensive content down. But for others, censorship – even by a private company – is dangerous in a time when digital platforms have become the new public square and many Americans cite Facebook and Twitter as their primary news sources. Rather than embracing European hate speech laws or developing platform-specific community standards that are sometimes seen as partisan, they argue, social media companies should voluntarily adopt the First Amendment and block content only if it violates American law. Should First Amendment doctrine govern free speech online? Or are new, more internationally focused speech policies better equipped to handle the modern challenges of regulating content and speech in the digital era?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/HZusodQB-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/HZusodQB-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>David French</strong><br>David French is a senior writer for the National Review, a senior fellow at the National Review Institute, an attorney, and a veteran of Operation Iraqi Freedom. He is a New York Times best-selling author, and his next book, "The Great American Divorce," will be published this year. He was previously the president of the Foundation for Individual Rights in Education and has served as senior counsel for the American Center for Law and Justice and the Alliance Defending Freedom.</p>
<p><strong>Corynne McSherry</strong><br>Corynne McSherry is the legal director at the Electronic Frontier Foundation, specializing in intellectual property, open access, and free speech issues. Her policy work includes leading EFF’s effort to fix copyright (including the successful effort to shut down the Stop Online Piracy Act, or SOPA), promote net neutrality, and promote best practices for online expression. McSherry comments regularly on digital rights issues and has been quoted in a variety of outlets, including NPR, CBS News, Fox News, the New York Times, Billboard, the Wall Street Journal, and Rolling Stone. Prior to joining EFF, McSherry was a civil litigator at the law firm of Bingham McCutchen LLP.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Nathaniel Persily</strong><br>Nate Persily is a professor at Stanford Law School and the director of the Stanford Project on Democracy and the Internet. His scholarship and legal practice focus on American election law, which addresses issues such as voting rights, political parties, campaign finance, redistricting, and election administration. Persily’s current work, for which he has been honored as an Andrew Carnegie Fellow and a fellow at the Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, examines the impact of changing technology on political communication, campaigns, and election administration.</p>
<p><strong>Marietje Schaake</strong><br>Marietje Schaake is international policy director and international policy fellow at Stanford’s Cyber Policy Center and Institute for Human-Centered Artificial Intelligence, respectively. She is a former member of the European Parliament from the Netherlands and was a member of D66, part of the Alliance of Liberals and Democrats for Europe political group. She is also the founder of the European Parliament Intergroup on the Digital Agenda for Europe, a member of the European Council on Foreign Relations, and an adviser to the Center for Humane Technology. Schaake was featured by Politico as one of the 28 most influential Europeans in the class of 2017.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Is Elon Musk killing Twitter? How bankruptcy might not be the end</strong> <small>2023-02-02 18:59:19</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>A debate between an investor and a journalist looks into what is happening at the social media company</p>
<p>Last October, Elon Musk completed his move to acquire Twitter (https://interestingengineering.com/culture/elon-musk-completes-twitter-takeover) after a short legal brawl, but the joy of the move was short-lived. Having fired the top brass the same day, Musk moved on to firing more than half of Twitter’s staff, and bad news kept poring out of the San Francisco headquarters quite regularly.</p>
<p>As we enter the New Year, the situation hasn’t changed much, and Twitter continues to be in the news for all the wrong reasons, like not paying rent for its office spaces and employees being forced out of buildings by landlords, The New York Times reported (https://www.nytimes.com/2022/12/13/technology/elon-musk-twitter-shakeup.html?smid=tw-nytimes&smtyp=cur). The question that crosses one’s mind is if Musk is out to kill Twitter once and for all.</p>
<p>Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S.Intelligence Squared (http://opentodebate.org), a platform known for organizing debates, took up this question and set up a debate between Kara Swisher, the editor-at-large at New York Magazine, and Anthony Scaramucci, managing partner at Skybridge capital and former communications director at the White House.</p>
<p>Neither Swisher nor Scaramucci have a personal or professional relationship with Musk, even though they have met and interacted with the now Twitter CEO on multiple occasions.</p>
<p>Here's a look at various aspects of the effects Elon Musk's takeover has had on Twitter.</p>
<p>Active Users
Musk’s actions have allegedly led to a drop in usage among active users, who usually contribute a lot of content to the platform, and is forcing users to give competitors, like Mastodon, a try, Swisher said while stating that Musk's leadership was leading to Twitter's downfall.</p>
<p>Comparing it to a proverbial town square, Scaramucci argued that Twitter, since Musk’s takeover had more active users and was at the center of many important events, whether it was the FIFA World Cup or the FTX debacle.</p>
<p>Journalists could cover nuances of a story thanks to Twitter while people get updates about people they follow from the platform. Twitter Spaces turned out to be an effective medium and preferable over ClubHouse. When Musk himself joined Twitter Space, more than 100,000 people were in attendance listening and asking questions, Scaramucci said while defending that Musk wasn't killing Twitter.</p>
<p>Return of banned accounts
Swisher pointed out Musk-led Twitter has allowed 60,000 accounts previously suspended back on the platform to “improve the conversation”. Worse still, the decision to allow these users back seems to have been made single-handedly by Musk, instead of a council that was supposed to be set up.</p>
<p>Scaramucci argued that by bringing people back, Musk was giving them a platform to voice their opinions rather than shut them off. This way, he was bringing them back into the social contract. He added that when individuals speak, think and speak freely, it creates economic innovation.</p>
<p>Loss of revenue
Swisher strongly argued that Musk was indeed killing Twitter after his arrival blew off $5 billion in advertising revenues for the social media company, which was significant for income in the pre-Musk days. His plans of launching the paid subscription model of revenue generation hurt corporate clients more as users faked companies after paying $8 a month and got verified checks to their fake usernames.</p>
<p>Scaramucci added that large corporations were risk averse and did not want to advertise on Twitter due to what Musk was doing.</p>
<p>Twitter’s valuation drops
Swisher also pointed out a report that the Bank of America and Morgan Stanley who lent Musk money to finance his Twitter deal have now halved the Twitter debt on their books, which means the company’s equity has been wiped out in just two months after Musk has arrived at the helm of the affairs.</p>
<p>Scaramucci ceded that Twitter’s valuations were down but argued that the company was far from dead and could see a revival in the coming months and years. Instead with a more active user base, the company was more vital than ever.</p>
<p>Could Twitter go bankrupt?
Swisher pointed out that Musk first spoke about Twitter's potential bankruptcy (https://interestingengineering.com/culture/twitter-possible-bankruptcy-top-executives-leave). While it is likely that Musk, the world’s richest person, will not let it happen, he had many wealthy friends who could put money into the company if it came to that.</p>
<p>However, she warned that if the loan ended up on Wall Street, it could be bought by someone else, who would want Musk out before he could fix what he had broken at Twitter. She argued that although Twitter got a lot of attention from politicians and the media, it wasn’t a great business when compared to other social media outlets, and with Musk at the helm had turned into a lousy business.</p>
<p>Comparison with Tesla, SpaceX
Scaramucci’s faith in Elon Musk to revive Twitter comes from his other companies, Tesla and SpaceX, staring at bankruptcy in 2008. Back then, it was Musk’s leadership that steered them away to levels that made him one of the richest people in the world (https://interestingengineering.com/culture/elon-musk-just-got-36-billion-richer-in-a-single-day).</p>
<p>He said that Musk may have started on the wrong foot with Twitter trying to give away verified badges for a fee but, having realized his mistake, reversed his decision. In the long run, Scaramucci expects Musk to get things right at Twitter.</p>
<p>Swisher, however, argued that too much faith was being put into Musk’s ability because of his history. Musk was good at making cars and rockets, but that does not mean he will be good at media too.</p>
<p>Twitter being a media company puts him in a very different situation, and his ideas to ‘unlock its potential’ are retreads of what many orders have suggested in the past. In fact, Musk has been unable to execute them properly and has made the site more erratic as of now.</p>
<p>Swisher also referred to Steve Jobs as a true visionary who stayed in his lane and did great things. Musk, on the other hand, does not seem to have a clue about what he is up to.</p>
<p>Musk’s vision for Twitter
Scaramucci, an investor, had access to a Powerpoint presentation for Musk’s vision for Twitter, which said that he wants to broaden the social media base and make it more inclusive. Going forward, Musk wants Twitter to become a ‘super app’ much like WeChat, which is used in China by users for social media, making payments, and personal communication.</p>
<p>Swisher, however, said that ‘super apps’ have not worked in the U.S. before, and even the likes of Apple and Amazon have tried to do it and failed so far. It might be working in China, but the U.S. was a different market, and people would trust Amazon or Apple with their payments but not Twitter.</p>
<p>Moreover, people used different apps for different purposes, like Snapchat for communication and TikTok for entertainment. Like Facebook usage has dropped, Twitter under Musk is heading the same way.</p>
<p>Twitter: Unassailable or Obsolete?
Due to its ability to connect people to events happening globally, Scaramucci said, Twitter had found a niche for itself in the past 15 years of its existence and become an indispensable part of our daily lives. Even if Musk failed in his mission to turn the company around, he would leave, and someone else could steady the ship.</p>
<p>With Musk planning to ring in many changes in how Twitter looks and behaves, users could be worried if the sudden changes would keep the platform usable. Swisher thinks that if the user experience dips and people find it hard to use Twitter, then it is likely that competitors will make something easier to use, shifting the user base away.</p>
<p>Swisher was pessimistic that the company could survive the Elon storm and compared his management style to building a rocket while it was in flight. Worse still, his decisions were taking the rocket on a downward trajectory, and Musk was single-handedly making the decisions. Swisher would not be surprised if Twitter soon became part of the graveyard of internet companies such as AOL, AIM, Yahoo, and MySpace, which were great at one time but have become obsolete over the years.</p>
<p>Impact on Musk
The time Musk spends at Twitter also affects his other ventures, such as Tesla, Swisher argued. The EV-making company had seen a steep decline in its valuation (https://interestingengineering.com/culture/musk-lose-200-billion), with Twitter serving as a larger distraction for Musk, the CEO, than when he was just a prolific user of the platform.</p>
<p>The competition in the EV market has grown, and Tesla is ceding its market share, which took years to build, very rapidly. The mass firing of staff at Twitter is also resulting in class action lawsuits and which are likely to be the biggest ones in Musk’s life.</p>
<p>Scaramucci quoting Warren Buffett that a high-quality business can endure a bad management team or terrible decisions to set the tone of his defense is a strong indicator of what’s happening at Twitter.</p>
<p>The debate was published across various podcast platforms today.</p></div>
<div><strong>Pod-Alization: Libsyn Finds Its “Lore”; Is Musk Killing Twitter; Podcast Interviews</strong> <small>2023-02-07 19:20:15</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Is Musk killing Twitter
This week’s Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S.debate podcast asks: Is Elon Musk Killing Twitter? Journalist Kara Swisher argues Yes. Investor Anthony Scaramucci argues No. Wired’s Steven Levy and Insider’s Monica Melton chime in as well with questions.</p>
<p>The 50-minute debate is now available on all podcast platforms (search “Intelligence Squared U.S.”) and on YouTube.</p>
<p>Of course, you could ask another question. Is Musk at Twitter causing Tesla to implode? Musk’s auto business has missed production targets, seen its stock price plummet, and its cars in self-driving mode have been involved in several accidents.</p></div>
<div><strong>Unsatisfying answers about possibly benign balloons leave congressional critics frustrated</strong> <small>2023-02-16 16:48:58</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Calendar</p>
<p>FRIDAY | FEBRUARY 17</p>
<p>TBA Munich, Germany Munich Security Conference 2023 begins, running through Sunday, Feb. 19 https://securityconference.org (https://securityconference.org/en/news/full/muenchner-sicherheitskonferenz-one-month-to-go/)</p>
<p>2 p.m. Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. virtual live debate recording: Should The U.S. Ban TikTok? with Kori Schake, senior fellow and director of foreign and defense policy studies, American Enterprise Institute, arguing Yes and Milton Mueller, professor, Georgia Institute of Technology School of Public Policy, founder and director, Internet Governance Project, arguing No.Moderated by John Donvan https://www.workcast.com/register (https://www.workcast.com/register?cpak=5204951257857492&mc_cid=c86fb254c9&mc_eid=fb0110d67b)</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Constitutional Free Speech Principles Can Save Social Media Companies from Themselves</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Content Moderation Policies</u></p>
<p><u>Section 230</u></p>
<p><u>German Laws</u></p>
<p><u>European Commission</u></p>
<p><u>High-Profile Incidents</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> March 04, 2019</p>
<p>How should the world’s largest social media companies respond to a pernicious online climate, including hate speech and false content posted by users? For some, the answer is clear: take the fake and offensive content down. But for others, censorship – even by a private company – is dangerous in a time when digital platforms have become the new public square and many Americans cite Facebook and Twitter as their primary news sources. Rather than embracing European hate speech laws or developing platform-specific community standards that are sometimes seen as partisan, they argue, social media companies should voluntarily adopt the First Amendment and block content only if it violates American law. Should First Amendment doctrine govern free speech online? Or are new, more internationally focused speech policies better equipped to handle the modern challenges of regulating content and speech in the digital era?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/HZusodQB-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/HZusodQB-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>David French</strong><br>David French is a senior writer for the National Review, a senior fellow at the National Review Institute, an attorney, and a veteran of Operation Iraqi Freedom. He is a New York Times best-selling author, and his next book, "The Great American Divorce," will be published this year. He was previously the president of the Foundation for Individual Rights in Education and has served as senior counsel for the American Center for Law and Justice and the Alliance Defending Freedom.</p>
<p><strong>Corynne McSherry</strong><br>Corynne McSherry is the legal director at the Electronic Frontier Foundation, specializing in intellectual property, open access, and free speech issues. Her policy work includes leading EFF’s effort to fix copyright (including the successful effort to shut down the Stop Online Piracy Act, or SOPA), promote net neutrality, and promote best practices for online expression. McSherry comments regularly on digital rights issues and has been quoted in a variety of outlets, including NPR, CBS News, Fox News, the New York Times, Billboard, the Wall Street Journal, and Rolling Stone. Prior to joining EFF, McSherry was a civil litigator at the law firm of Bingham McCutchen LLP.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Nathaniel Persily</strong><br>Nate Persily is a professor at Stanford Law School and the director of the Stanford Project on Democracy and the Internet. His scholarship and legal practice focus on American election law, which addresses issues such as voting rights, political parties, campaign finance, redistricting, and election administration. Persily’s current work, for which he has been honored as an Andrew Carnegie Fellow and a fellow at the Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, examines the impact of changing technology on political communication, campaigns, and election administration.</p>
<p><strong>Marietje Schaake</strong><br>Marietje Schaake is international policy director and international policy fellow at Stanford’s Cyber Policy Center and Institute for Human-Centered Artificial Intelligence, respectively. She is a former member of the European Parliament from the Netherlands and was a member of D66, part of the Alliance of Liberals and Democrats for Europe political group. She is also the founder of the European Parliament Intergroup on the Digital Agenda for Europe, a member of the European Council on Foreign Relations, and an adviser to the Center for Humane Technology. Schaake was featured by Politico as one of the 28 most influential Europeans in the class of 2017.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Is Elon Musk killing Twitter? How bankruptcy might not be the end</strong> <small>2023-02-02 18:59:19</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>A debate between an investor and a journalist looks into what is happening at the social media company</p>
<p>Last October, Elon Musk completed his move to acquire Twitter (https://interestingengineering.com/culture/elon-musk-completes-twitter-takeover) after a short legal brawl, but the joy of the move was short-lived. Having fired the top brass the same day, Musk moved on to firing more than half of Twitter’s staff, and bad news kept poring out of the San Francisco headquarters quite regularly.</p>
<p>As we enter the New Year, the situation hasn’t changed much, and Twitter continues to be in the news for all the wrong reasons, like not paying rent for its office spaces and employees being forced out of buildings by landlords, The New York Times reported (https://www.nytimes.com/2022/12/13/technology/elon-musk-twitter-shakeup.html?smid=tw-nytimes&smtyp=cur). The question that crosses one’s mind is if Musk is out to kill Twitter once and for all.</p>
<p>Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S.Intelligence Squared (http://opentodebate.org), a platform known for organizing debates, took up this question and set up a debate between Kara Swisher, the editor-at-large at New York Magazine, and Anthony Scaramucci, managing partner at Skybridge capital and former communications director at the White House.</p>
<p>Neither Swisher nor Scaramucci have a personal or professional relationship with Musk, even though they have met and interacted with the now Twitter CEO on multiple occasions.</p>
<p>Here's a look at various aspects of the effects Elon Musk's takeover has had on Twitter.</p>
<p>Active Users
Musk’s actions have allegedly led to a drop in usage among active users, who usually contribute a lot of content to the platform, and is forcing users to give competitors, like Mastodon, a try, Swisher said while stating that Musk's leadership was leading to Twitter's downfall.</p>
<p>Comparing it to a proverbial town square, Scaramucci argued that Twitter, since Musk’s takeover had more active users and was at the center of many important events, whether it was the FIFA World Cup or the FTX debacle.</p>
<p>Journalists could cover nuances of a story thanks to Twitter while people get updates about people they follow from the platform. Twitter Spaces turned out to be an effective medium and preferable over ClubHouse. When Musk himself joined Twitter Space, more than 100,000 people were in attendance listening and asking questions, Scaramucci said while defending that Musk wasn't killing Twitter.</p>
<p>Return of banned accounts
Swisher pointed out Musk-led Twitter has allowed 60,000 accounts previously suspended back on the platform to “improve the conversation”. Worse still, the decision to allow these users back seems to have been made single-handedly by Musk, instead of a council that was supposed to be set up.</p>
<p>Scaramucci argued that by bringing people back, Musk was giving them a platform to voice their opinions rather than shut them off. This way, he was bringing them back into the social contract. He added that when individuals speak, think and speak freely, it creates economic innovation.</p>
<p>Loss of revenue
Swisher strongly argued that Musk was indeed killing Twitter after his arrival blew off $5 billion in advertising revenues for the social media company, which was significant for income in the pre-Musk days. His plans of launching the paid subscription model of revenue generation hurt corporate clients more as users faked companies after paying $8 a month and got verified checks to their fake usernames.</p>
<p>Scaramucci added that large corporations were risk averse and did not want to advertise on Twitter due to what Musk was doing.</p>
<p>Twitter’s valuation drops
Swisher also pointed out a report that the Bank of America and Morgan Stanley who lent Musk money to finance his Twitter deal have now halved the Twitter debt on their books, which means the company’s equity has been wiped out in just two months after Musk has arrived at the helm of the affairs.</p>
<p>Scaramucci ceded that Twitter’s valuations were down but argued that the company was far from dead and could see a revival in the coming months and years. Instead with a more active user base, the company was more vital than ever.</p>
<p>Could Twitter go bankrupt?
Swisher pointed out that Musk first spoke about Twitter's potential bankruptcy (https://interestingengineering.com/culture/twitter-possible-bankruptcy-top-executives-leave). While it is likely that Musk, the world’s richest person, will not let it happen, he had many wealthy friends who could put money into the company if it came to that.</p>
<p>However, she warned that if the loan ended up on Wall Street, it could be bought by someone else, who would want Musk out before he could fix what he had broken at Twitter. She argued that although Twitter got a lot of attention from politicians and the media, it wasn’t a great business when compared to other social media outlets, and with Musk at the helm had turned into a lousy business.</p>
<p>Comparison with Tesla, SpaceX
Scaramucci’s faith in Elon Musk to revive Twitter comes from his other companies, Tesla and SpaceX, staring at bankruptcy in 2008. Back then, it was Musk’s leadership that steered them away to levels that made him one of the richest people in the world (https://interestingengineering.com/culture/elon-musk-just-got-36-billion-richer-in-a-single-day).</p>
<p>He said that Musk may have started on the wrong foot with Twitter trying to give away verified badges for a fee but, having realized his mistake, reversed his decision. In the long run, Scaramucci expects Musk to get things right at Twitter.</p>
<p>Swisher, however, argued that too much faith was being put into Musk’s ability because of his history. Musk was good at making cars and rockets, but that does not mean he will be good at media too.</p>
<p>Twitter being a media company puts him in a very different situation, and his ideas to ‘unlock its potential’ are retreads of what many orders have suggested in the past. In fact, Musk has been unable to execute them properly and has made the site more erratic as of now.</p>
<p>Swisher also referred to Steve Jobs as a true visionary who stayed in his lane and did great things. Musk, on the other hand, does not seem to have a clue about what he is up to.</p>
<p>Musk’s vision for Twitter
Scaramucci, an investor, had access to a Powerpoint presentation for Musk’s vision for Twitter, which said that he wants to broaden the social media base and make it more inclusive. Going forward, Musk wants Twitter to become a ‘super app’ much like WeChat, which is used in China by users for social media, making payments, and personal communication.</p>
<p>Swisher, however, said that ‘super apps’ have not worked in the U.S. before, and even the likes of Apple and Amazon have tried to do it and failed so far. It might be working in China, but the U.S. was a different market, and people would trust Amazon or Apple with their payments but not Twitter.</p>
<p>Moreover, people used different apps for different purposes, like Snapchat for communication and TikTok for entertainment. Like Facebook usage has dropped, Twitter under Musk is heading the same way.</p>
<p>Twitter: Unassailable or Obsolete?
Due to its ability to connect people to events happening globally, Scaramucci said, Twitter had found a niche for itself in the past 15 years of its existence and become an indispensable part of our daily lives. Even if Musk failed in his mission to turn the company around, he would leave, and someone else could steady the ship.</p>
<p>With Musk planning to ring in many changes in how Twitter looks and behaves, users could be worried if the sudden changes would keep the platform usable. Swisher thinks that if the user experience dips and people find it hard to use Twitter, then it is likely that competitors will make something easier to use, shifting the user base away.</p>
<p>Swisher was pessimistic that the company could survive the Elon storm and compared his management style to building a rocket while it was in flight. Worse still, his decisions were taking the rocket on a downward trajectory, and Musk was single-handedly making the decisions. Swisher would not be surprised if Twitter soon became part of the graveyard of internet companies such as AOL, AIM, Yahoo, and MySpace, which were great at one time but have become obsolete over the years.</p>
<p>Impact on Musk
The time Musk spends at Twitter also affects his other ventures, such as Tesla, Swisher argued. The EV-making company had seen a steep decline in its valuation (https://interestingengineering.com/culture/musk-lose-200-billion), with Twitter serving as a larger distraction for Musk, the CEO, than when he was just a prolific user of the platform.</p>
<p>The competition in the EV market has grown, and Tesla is ceding its market share, which took years to build, very rapidly. The mass firing of staff at Twitter is also resulting in class action lawsuits and which are likely to be the biggest ones in Musk’s life.</p>
<p>Scaramucci quoting Warren Buffett that a high-quality business can endure a bad management team or terrible decisions to set the tone of his defense is a strong indicator of what’s happening at Twitter.</p>
<p>The debate was published across various podcast platforms today.</p></div>
<div><strong>Pod-Alization: Libsyn Finds Its “Lore”; Is Musk Killing Twitter; Podcast Interviews</strong> <small>2023-02-07 19:20:15</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Is Musk killing Twitter
This week’s Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S.debate podcast asks: Is Elon Musk Killing Twitter? Journalist Kara Swisher argues Yes. Investor Anthony Scaramucci argues No. Wired’s Steven Levy and Insider’s Monica Melton chime in as well with questions.</p>
<p>The 50-minute debate is now available on all podcast platforms (search “Intelligence Squared U.S.”) and on YouTube.</p>
<p>Of course, you could ask another question. Is Musk at Twitter causing Tesla to implode? Musk’s auto business has missed production targets, seen its stock price plummet, and its cars in self-driving mode have been involved in several accidents.</p></div>
<div><strong>Unsatisfying answers about possibly benign balloons leave congressional critics frustrated</strong> <small>2023-02-16 16:48:58</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Calendar</p>
<p>FRIDAY | FEBRUARY 17</p>
<p>TBA Munich, Germany Munich Security Conference 2023 begins, running through Sunday, Feb. 19 https://securityconference.org (https://securityconference.org/en/news/full/muenchner-sicherheitskonferenz-one-month-to-go/)</p>
<p>2 p.m. Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. virtual live debate recording: Should The U.S. Ban TikTok? with Kori Schake, senior fellow and director of foreign and defense policy studies, American Enterprise Institute, arguing Yes and Milton Mueller, professor, Georgia Institute of Technology School of Public Policy, founder and director, Internet Governance Project, arguing No.Moderated by John Donvan https://www.workcast.com/register (https://www.workcast.com/register?cpak=5204951257857492&mc_cid=c86fb254c9&mc_eid=fb0110d67b)</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Constitutional Free Speech Principles Can Save Social Media Companies from Themselves</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Content Moderation Policies</u></p>
<p><u>Section 230</u></p>
<p><u>German Laws</u></p>
<p><u>European Commission</u></p>
<p><u>High-Profile Incidents</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Unresolved: The Techonomic Cold War With China</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/unresolved-techonomic-cold-war-china</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10331</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> February 25, 2019</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Politics, U.S., World</p>
<p>President Xi Jinping has made it clear: When it comes to big data, advanced weaponry, and other innovations in tech and AI, China has plans to surpass the United States as the world’s next techonomic superpower. But between the trade war with the U.S., the ambitious Belt and Road Initiative, and an array of domestic challenges, are China’s goals outpacing its capacity? Or is China building and investing in strategic partnerships that will push the country toward global dominance?
Staged in our “Unresolved” format, this debate brings together five foreign policy luminaries to tackle pressing questions, including: Will the next Silicon Valley be in China? Is the Belt and Road Initiative a trillion-dollar blunder? And will the U.S. and China both lose the trade war?</p>
<p><strong>Unresolved Questions:</strong></p>
<p>• A New Cold War?</p>
<p>• The Next Silicon Valley Will Be in China</p>
<p>• The Belt and Road Initiative Is a Trillion-Dollar Blunder</p>
<p>• The U.S. and China Will Both Lose the Trade War</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/43zrYQqA-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/43zrYQqA-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Ian Bremmer</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO102471467 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO102471467 BCX0">Ian Bremmer is the president and founder of Eurasia Group, the leading global political risk research and consulting firm, and president of GZERO Media. He is the foreign affairs columnist and editor-at-large at Time magazine, where he writes about China, U.S. foreign policy, and geopolitics. A prolific writer, he is the author of eleven books, including the New York Times best-seller "Us vs. Them: The Failure of Globalism," which explores the consequences of globalism.</span></span></p>
<p><strong>Michèle Flournoy</strong><br>Michèle Flournoy is the co-founder and managing partner of WestExec, a strategic advisory firm offering unique geopolitical expertise, and the co-founder and former CEO of the Center for a New American Security. Previously, she served as the undersecretary of defense for policy under President Obama. She was a Pentagon policy chief and the principal adviser to the Secretary of Defense in the formulation of national security and defense policy, oversight of military plans and operations, and in National Security Council deliberations. Flournoy serves on the CNAS board of directors.</p>
<p><strong>Yasheng Huang</strong><br>Yasheng Huang is a professor of political economy and international management at MIT, where he holds the International Program Professorship in Chinese Economy and Business in the Sloan School of Management. He is the author of several books in English and Chinese, including "Capitalism with Chinese Characteristics," which was named an Economist book of the year. Huang also holds special professorship appointments at Fudan University and Hunan University and fellowships at Tsinghua University and the World Economic Forum. He has served as a consultant to the World Bank and the OECD.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Parag Khanna</strong><br>Parag Khanna is a leading global strategy adviser and the founder and managing partner of FutureMap, a data- and scenario-based strategic advisory firm. A best-selling author, his most recent book is "The Future is Asian: Commerce, Conflict, and Culture in the 21st Century." Khanna was previously a senior research fellow in the Center on Asia and Globalization at the National University of Singapore. He has been a fellow at the Brookings Institution and New America, an adviser to the U.S. National Intelligence Council’s Global Trends 2030 program, and a senior geopolitical adviser to U.S. Special Operations Forces.</p>
<p><strong>Susan Thornton</strong><br>Susan A. Thornton is a retired senior U.S. diplomat with almost three decades of experience with the U.S. State Department in Eurasia and East Asia. She is currently a Visiting Lecturer in Law and Senior Fellow at the Yale Law School Paul Tsai China Center. She is also the director of the Forum on Asia-Pacific Security at the National Committee on American Foreign Policy and a nonresident senior fellow at the Brookings Institution.
Until July 2018, Thornton was Acting Assistant Secretary for East Asian and Pacific Affairs at the Department of State and led East Asia policymaking amid crises with North Korea, escalating trade tensions with China, and a fast-changing international environment. In previous State Department roles, she worked on U.S. policy toward China, Korea and the former Soviet Union and served in leadership positions at U.S. embassies in Central Asia, Russia, the Caucasus and China.
Thornton received her M.A. in International Relations from the Johns Hopkins University School of Advanced International Studies and her B.A. from Bowdoin College in Economics and Russian. She serves on several nonprofit boards and speaks Mandarin and Russian.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Unresolved: The Techonomic Cold War With China</em></p>
<p><u>A New Cold War?</u></p>
<p><u>The Next Silicon Valley Will Be in China</u></p>
<p><u>The Belt and Road Initiative Is a Trillion-Dollar Blunder</u></p>
<p><u>The U.S. and China Will Both Lose the Trade War</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> February 25, 2019</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Politics, U.S., World</p>
<p>President Xi Jinping has made it clear: When it comes to big data, advanced weaponry, and other innovations in tech and AI, China has plans to surpass the United States as the world’s next techonomic superpower. But between the trade war with the U.S., the ambitious Belt and Road Initiative, and an array of domestic challenges, are China’s goals outpacing its capacity? Or is China building and investing in strategic partnerships that will push the country toward global dominance?
Staged in our “Unresolved” format, this debate brings together five foreign policy luminaries to tackle pressing questions, including: Will the next Silicon Valley be in China? Is the Belt and Road Initiative a trillion-dollar blunder? And will the U.S. and China both lose the trade war?</p>
<p><strong>Unresolved Questions:</strong></p>
<p>• A New Cold War?</p>
<p>• The Next Silicon Valley Will Be in China</p>
<p>• The Belt and Road Initiative Is a Trillion-Dollar Blunder</p>
<p>• The U.S. and China Will Both Lose the Trade War</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/43zrYQqA-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/43zrYQqA-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Ian Bremmer</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO102471467 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO102471467 BCX0">Ian Bremmer is the president and founder of Eurasia Group, the leading global political risk research and consulting firm, and president of GZERO Media. He is the foreign affairs columnist and editor-at-large at Time magazine, where he writes about China, U.S. foreign policy, and geopolitics. A prolific writer, he is the author of eleven books, including the New York Times best-seller "Us vs. Them: The Failure of Globalism," which explores the consequences of globalism.</span></span></p>
<p><strong>Michèle Flournoy</strong><br>Michèle Flournoy is the co-founder and managing partner of WestExec, a strategic advisory firm offering unique geopolitical expertise, and the co-founder and former CEO of the Center for a New American Security. Previously, she served as the undersecretary of defense for policy under President Obama. She was a Pentagon policy chief and the principal adviser to the Secretary of Defense in the formulation of national security and defense policy, oversight of military plans and operations, and in National Security Council deliberations. Flournoy serves on the CNAS board of directors.</p>
<p><strong>Yasheng Huang</strong><br>Yasheng Huang is a professor of political economy and international management at MIT, where he holds the International Program Professorship in Chinese Economy and Business in the Sloan School of Management. He is the author of several books in English and Chinese, including "Capitalism with Chinese Characteristics," which was named an Economist book of the year. Huang also holds special professorship appointments at Fudan University and Hunan University and fellowships at Tsinghua University and the World Economic Forum. He has served as a consultant to the World Bank and the OECD.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Parag Khanna</strong><br>Parag Khanna is a leading global strategy adviser and the founder and managing partner of FutureMap, a data- and scenario-based strategic advisory firm. A best-selling author, his most recent book is "The Future is Asian: Commerce, Conflict, and Culture in the 21st Century." Khanna was previously a senior research fellow in the Center on Asia and Globalization at the National University of Singapore. He has been a fellow at the Brookings Institution and New America, an adviser to the U.S. National Intelligence Council’s Global Trends 2030 program, and a senior geopolitical adviser to U.S. Special Operations Forces.</p>
<p><strong>Susan Thornton</strong><br>Susan A. Thornton is a retired senior U.S. diplomat with almost three decades of experience with the U.S. State Department in Eurasia and East Asia. She is currently a Visiting Lecturer in Law and Senior Fellow at the Yale Law School Paul Tsai China Center. She is also the director of the Forum on Asia-Pacific Security at the National Committee on American Foreign Policy and a nonresident senior fellow at the Brookings Institution.
Until July 2018, Thornton was Acting Assistant Secretary for East Asian and Pacific Affairs at the Department of State and led East Asia policymaking amid crises with North Korea, escalating trade tensions with China, and a fast-changing international environment. In previous State Department roles, she worked on U.S. policy toward China, Korea and the former Soviet Union and served in leadership positions at U.S. embassies in Central Asia, Russia, the Caucasus and China.
Thornton received her M.A. in International Relations from the Johns Hopkins University School of Advanced International Studies and her B.A. from Bowdoin College in Economics and Russian. She serves on several nonprofit boards and speaks Mandarin and Russian.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Unresolved: The Techonomic Cold War With China</em></p>
<p><u>A New Cold War?</u></p>
<p><u>The Next Silicon Valley Will Be in China</u></p>
<p><u>The Belt and Road Initiative Is a Trillion-Dollar Blunder</u></p>
<p><u>The U.S. and China Will Both Lose the Trade War</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>IBM Project Debater</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/ibm-project-debater</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10196</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> February 11, 2019</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Tech</p>
<p>At Open to Debate (formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S.), we’ve debated AI before – the risks, the rewards, and whether it can change the world – but for the first time, we’re debating with AI.
In partnership with IBM, Open to Debate hosted a unique debate between a world-class champion debater and an AI system. IBM Project Debater is the first AI system designed to debate humans on complex topics using a combination of pioneering research developed by IBM researchers, including: data-driven speechwriting and delivery, listening comprehension, and modeling human dilemmas.
First debuted in a small closed-door event in June 2018, Project Debater will now face its toughest opponent yet in front of its largest-ever audience, with our own John Donvan in the moderator’s seat. The topic will not be revealed to Project Debater and the champion human debater until shortly before the debate begins.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/uD3YipZI-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/uD3YipZI-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>IBM Project Debater</strong><br>IBM’s Project Debater is the first-ever AI system designed to meaningfully engage with humans in a debate. First created in 2012 in IBM Research's lab in Haifa, Israel, Project Debater scans billions of sentences to generate a position on any given topic. Project Debater is not connected to the internet and relies on three pioneering capabilities: the first is data-driven speechwriting and delivery, or the ability to generate and deliver a persuasive speech. The second is listening comprehension, or the ability to understand a human’s argument and, in turn, construct a rebuttal. And the third is the ability to form principled arguments based on Project Debater’s unique knowledge graph.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Harish Natarajan</strong><br>Harish Natarajan, a widely recognized debate champion, was a grand finalist at the 2016 World Debating Championships and the winner of the European Debating Championship in 2012. Natarajan sat on the motion-setting committees for the 2014 World Debating Championship in India, the 2016 European Debating Championship in Poland, and other major competitions in over 20 countries. He has also coached the Filipino national school’s debating team, which reached the finals of the Asian Championship and was the third-ranked team at the World Championships. He is the head of economic risk analysis at AKE International and a graduate of the University of Oxford and the University of Cambridge.</p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> February 11, 2019</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Tech</p>
<p>At Open to Debate (formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S.), we’ve debated AI before – the risks, the rewards, and whether it can change the world – but for the first time, we’re debating with AI.
In partnership with IBM, Open to Debate hosted a unique debate between a world-class champion debater and an AI system. IBM Project Debater is the first AI system designed to debate humans on complex topics using a combination of pioneering research developed by IBM researchers, including: data-driven speechwriting and delivery, listening comprehension, and modeling human dilemmas.
First debuted in a small closed-door event in June 2018, Project Debater will now face its toughest opponent yet in front of its largest-ever audience, with our own John Donvan in the moderator’s seat. The topic will not be revealed to Project Debater and the champion human debater until shortly before the debate begins.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/uD3YipZI-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/uD3YipZI-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>IBM Project Debater</strong><br>IBM’s Project Debater is the first-ever AI system designed to meaningfully engage with humans in a debate. First created in 2012 in IBM Research's lab in Haifa, Israel, Project Debater scans billions of sentences to generate a position on any given topic. Project Debater is not connected to the internet and relies on three pioneering capabilities: the first is data-driven speechwriting and delivery, or the ability to generate and deliver a persuasive speech. The second is listening comprehension, or the ability to understand a human’s argument and, in turn, construct a rebuttal. And the third is the ability to form principled arguments based on Project Debater’s unique knowledge graph.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Harish Natarajan</strong><br>Harish Natarajan, a widely recognized debate champion, was a grand finalist at the 2016 World Debating Championships and the winner of the European Debating Championship in 2012. Natarajan sat on the motion-setting committees for the 2014 World Debating Championship in India, the 2016 European Debating Championship in Poland, and other major competitions in over 20 countries. He has also coached the Filipino national school’s debating team, which reached the finals of the Asian Championship and was the third-ranked team at the World Championships. He is the head of economic risk analysis at AKE International and a graduate of the University of Oxford and the University of Cambridge.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Don&#x27;t Bring Extinct Creatures Back to Life</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/dont-bring-extinct-creatures-back-life</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10086</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> January 31, 2019</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Education, Science</p>
<p>De-extinction describes the process of creating an organism which is a member of, or closely resembles, an extinct species. While this process was once a sci-fi fantasy explored in films like “Jurassic Park,” recent biological and technological breakthroughs indicate that reviving extinct creatures, like the passenger pigeon and the woolly mammoth, could become a reality. De-extinction’s proponents argue that the benefits are many, including correcting mistakes of the past by bringing back extinct ecosystems and organisms and helping to curb climate change. They remind us that all scientific breakthroughs are initially met with skepticism and concern, most of which we now take for granted. But others aren’t so sure de-extinction is ethical, or even feasible, since each creature poses its own unique challenge: Recreating a bird is a very different process from recreating a mammal. And beyond that, some say that the resources and funds necessary for de-extinction would compete with current and vital conservation efforts. After all, they argue, with over 16,000 endangered species on Earth, shouldn’t humans focus on saving them from extinction rather than “playing God?”</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/q0htmbpb-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/q0htmbpb-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Ross MacPhee</strong><br>Dr. Ross MacPhee is the former chairman of the Department of Mammalogy at the American Museum of Natural History, where he has been curator since 1988. Known for his paleomammalogical research on island extinctions, he has focused his most recent work on extinctions occurring during the past 50,000 years, or "Near Time." He is the author of the new book "End of the Megafauna: The Fate of the World's Hugest, Fiercest, and Strangest Animals" (Norton, 2019). Dr. MacPhee has also collaborated with geneticists and molecular biologists to develop the new tool of "ancient DNA" for studying the ultimate collapse of Pleistocene mammals.</p>
<p><strong>Lynn J. Rothschild</strong><br>Dr. Lynn Rothschild is an evolutionary biologist and astrobiologist who focuses on the origin and evolution of life on Earth while at the same time pioneering the use of synthetic biology to enable space exploration. She is an adjunct professor of molecular biology, cell biology, and biochemistry at Brown University. Since 2011, Rothschild has been the faculty adviser of the award-winning Stanford-Brown iGEM team, which has pioneered the use of synthetic biology to accomplish NASA’s missions, including the human settlement of Mars.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Stewart Brand</strong><br>Stewart Brand is a futurist, environmentalist, and proponent of de-extinction who promotes the use of science to preserve the planet. He is the co-founder of Revive & Restore, which facilitates extinct species revival, and the Long Now Foundation, of which he is co-chair and president. He was the founder and editor of the award-winning Whole Earth Catalog and is the author of several books, including “Whole Earth Discipline: An Ecopragmatist Manifesto.” In 2013, Brand organized the TEDxDeExtinction conference in partnership with the National Geographic Society.</p>
<p><strong>George Church</strong><br>Dr. George Church is a geneticist and molecular engineer who is working to revive the extinct woolly mammoth. He is the Robert Winthrop professor of genetics at Harvard Medical School and a professor of health sciences and technology at Harvard and MIT. Dr. Church developed the methods used for the first genome sequence and founded the Personal Genome Project. He has earned dozens of awards and honors, including Time’s "100 Most Influential People," and is the author of 490 papers, 130 patent publications, and the book "Regenesis: How Synthetic Biology Will Reinvent Nature and Ourselves."</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Would bringing back extinct animals turn out as badly as it did in ‘Jurassic Park’?</strong> <small>2019-04-01 15:30:52</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>On a frigid January night, a Harvard genetics professor with a billowing white beard stood stage left in a theater on Manhattan's Upper East Side, an icon of the environmentalist movement in a fleece vest beside him. Both men were staring down a toothy problem: How could they convince their counterparts on the stage, along with the 300 people who'd filed into Hunter College's Kaye Playhouse for a debate, that the world should bring back velociraptors or, at the very least, an extinct pigeon?</p>
<p>The theme from the 1993 blockbuster “Jurassic Park” was playing in the background, chiseling away at their argument before the debate even began. In the film, based on the 1990 Michael Crichton bestseller, dinosaurs are brought back from extinction to fill a theme park. “That film took sides. The experiment blows up. People get hurt,” moderator John Donvan told the crowd during introductions. “But not before actor Jeff Goldblum declares, ‘Scientists were so preoccupied with whether or not they could that they didn’t stop to think if they should.’ And then, a dinosaur eats Jeff Goldblum.”</p>
<p>Actually, a dinosaur does not eat Goldblum’s brainy and brawny mathematician character, but chaos certainly reigns in the movie and its myriad sequels because of de-extinction. Those images are what George Church, 64, of the billowing white beard, who helped launch the Human Genome Project, and Stewart Brand, 80, of the fleece vest, who is a founder and editor of the Whole Earth Catalog, would need to overcome to win this evening’s debate</p></div>
<div><strong>Top shows up 7% in August, say Podtrac</strong> <small>2023-02-07 21:08:01</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Podcast analytics company Podtrac’s US podcast publisher data for August was released (http://analytics.podtrac.com/blog/3axz27rzg4ge6he-zxz5j-9gxcg-2j6jy-34ffa-nm6er-3tw7c-emtp2-mdrry-ze339-de2x2-4z3s4?utm_source=podnews.net&utm_medium=web&utm_campaign=podnews.net:2022-09-12). In spite of all the publicity handed to them last month, The Daily Wire, a right-wing podcast network, underperformed, increasing total downloads by just 3% against an average increase of 7%. Ben Shapiro’s show also dropped a place in Podtrac’s top podcast ranking (http://analytics.podtrac.com/blog/f4mshhnby74ls6n-hb7mg-94r4y-m8wfz-nr3bz-kkwdt-jh2w3-xk9wr-rd6c2?utm_source=podnews.net&utm_medium=web&utm_campaign=podnews.net:2022-09-12). iHeart remains #1 for podcasts, with downloads up by 6.8%. The ranker measures participating publishers only.</p>
<p>Podcast News - with Lemonada Media</p>
<p>Founded in 2019 by Jessica Cordova Kramer and Stephanie Wittels Wachs, Lemonada (https://podnews.net/class-click/1609/2022-09-12) is an award-winning, independent, audio-first podcast network, with a mission to make life suck less.</p>
<p>https://podnews.net/podcast/ih8p
Should we search for extraterrestrial life? In Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S., one expert argues yes, and one argues no. Astronomer and SETI Institute co-founder Jill Tarter thinks we should; theoretical cosmologist and Science Channel host Paul Sutter argues that we shouldn’t.</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Don't Bring Extinct Creatures Back to Life</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Definitions & Legal Frameworks</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For (Anti De-extinction)</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against (Pro De-extinction)</u></p>
<p><u>Feasibility</u></p>
<p><u>Creatures</u></p>
<p><u>Conservation</u></p>
<p><u>Ethics & Moral Hazard</u></p>
<p><u>Cloning, CRISPR, & Gene-Editing</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> January 31, 2019</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Education, Science</p>
<p>De-extinction describes the process of creating an organism which is a member of, or closely resembles, an extinct species. While this process was once a sci-fi fantasy explored in films like “Jurassic Park,” recent biological and technological breakthroughs indicate that reviving extinct creatures, like the passenger pigeon and the woolly mammoth, could become a reality. De-extinction’s proponents argue that the benefits are many, including correcting mistakes of the past by bringing back extinct ecosystems and organisms and helping to curb climate change. They remind us that all scientific breakthroughs are initially met with skepticism and concern, most of which we now take for granted. But others aren’t so sure de-extinction is ethical, or even feasible, since each creature poses its own unique challenge: Recreating a bird is a very different process from recreating a mammal. And beyond that, some say that the resources and funds necessary for de-extinction would compete with current and vital conservation efforts. After all, they argue, with over 16,000 endangered species on Earth, shouldn’t humans focus on saving them from extinction rather than “playing God?”</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/q0htmbpb-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/q0htmbpb-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Ross MacPhee</strong><br>Dr. Ross MacPhee is the former chairman of the Department of Mammalogy at the American Museum of Natural History, where he has been curator since 1988. Known for his paleomammalogical research on island extinctions, he has focused his most recent work on extinctions occurring during the past 50,000 years, or "Near Time." He is the author of the new book "End of the Megafauna: The Fate of the World's Hugest, Fiercest, and Strangest Animals" (Norton, 2019). Dr. MacPhee has also collaborated with geneticists and molecular biologists to develop the new tool of "ancient DNA" for studying the ultimate collapse of Pleistocene mammals.</p>
<p><strong>Lynn J. Rothschild</strong><br>Dr. Lynn Rothschild is an evolutionary biologist and astrobiologist who focuses on the origin and evolution of life on Earth while at the same time pioneering the use of synthetic biology to enable space exploration. She is an adjunct professor of molecular biology, cell biology, and biochemistry at Brown University. Since 2011, Rothschild has been the faculty adviser of the award-winning Stanford-Brown iGEM team, which has pioneered the use of synthetic biology to accomplish NASA’s missions, including the human settlement of Mars.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Stewart Brand</strong><br>Stewart Brand is a futurist, environmentalist, and proponent of de-extinction who promotes the use of science to preserve the planet. He is the co-founder of Revive & Restore, which facilitates extinct species revival, and the Long Now Foundation, of which he is co-chair and president. He was the founder and editor of the award-winning Whole Earth Catalog and is the author of several books, including “Whole Earth Discipline: An Ecopragmatist Manifesto.” In 2013, Brand organized the TEDxDeExtinction conference in partnership with the National Geographic Society.</p>
<p><strong>George Church</strong><br>Dr. George Church is a geneticist and molecular engineer who is working to revive the extinct woolly mammoth. He is the Robert Winthrop professor of genetics at Harvard Medical School and a professor of health sciences and technology at Harvard and MIT. Dr. Church developed the methods used for the first genome sequence and founded the Personal Genome Project. He has earned dozens of awards and honors, including Time’s "100 Most Influential People," and is the author of 490 papers, 130 patent publications, and the book "Regenesis: How Synthetic Biology Will Reinvent Nature and Ourselves."</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Would bringing back extinct animals turn out as badly as it did in ‘Jurassic Park’?</strong> <small>2019-04-01 15:30:52</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>On a frigid January night, a Harvard genetics professor with a billowing white beard stood stage left in a theater on Manhattan's Upper East Side, an icon of the environmentalist movement in a fleece vest beside him. Both men were staring down a toothy problem: How could they convince their counterparts on the stage, along with the 300 people who'd filed into Hunter College's Kaye Playhouse for a debate, that the world should bring back velociraptors or, at the very least, an extinct pigeon?</p>
<p>The theme from the 1993 blockbuster “Jurassic Park” was playing in the background, chiseling away at their argument before the debate even began. In the film, based on the 1990 Michael Crichton bestseller, dinosaurs are brought back from extinction to fill a theme park. “That film took sides. The experiment blows up. People get hurt,” moderator John Donvan told the crowd during introductions. “But not before actor Jeff Goldblum declares, ‘Scientists were so preoccupied with whether or not they could that they didn’t stop to think if they should.’ And then, a dinosaur eats Jeff Goldblum.”</p>
<p>Actually, a dinosaur does not eat Goldblum’s brainy and brawny mathematician character, but chaos certainly reigns in the movie and its myriad sequels because of de-extinction. Those images are what George Church, 64, of the billowing white beard, who helped launch the Human Genome Project, and Stewart Brand, 80, of the fleece vest, who is a founder and editor of the Whole Earth Catalog, would need to overcome to win this evening’s debate</p></div>
<div><strong>Top shows up 7% in August, say Podtrac</strong> <small>2023-02-07 21:08:01</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Podcast analytics company Podtrac’s US podcast publisher data for August was released (http://analytics.podtrac.com/blog/3axz27rzg4ge6he-zxz5j-9gxcg-2j6jy-34ffa-nm6er-3tw7c-emtp2-mdrry-ze339-de2x2-4z3s4?utm_source=podnews.net&utm_medium=web&utm_campaign=podnews.net:2022-09-12). In spite of all the publicity handed to them last month, The Daily Wire, a right-wing podcast network, underperformed, increasing total downloads by just 3% against an average increase of 7%. Ben Shapiro’s show also dropped a place in Podtrac’s top podcast ranking (http://analytics.podtrac.com/blog/f4mshhnby74ls6n-hb7mg-94r4y-m8wfz-nr3bz-kkwdt-jh2w3-xk9wr-rd6c2?utm_source=podnews.net&utm_medium=web&utm_campaign=podnews.net:2022-09-12). iHeart remains #1 for podcasts, with downloads up by 6.8%. The ranker measures participating publishers only.</p>
<p>Podcast News - with Lemonada Media</p>
<p>Founded in 2019 by Jessica Cordova Kramer and Stephanie Wittels Wachs, Lemonada (https://podnews.net/class-click/1609/2022-09-12) is an award-winning, independent, audio-first podcast network, with a mission to make life suck less.</p>
<p>https://podnews.net/podcast/ih8p
Should we search for extraterrestrial life? In Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S., one expert argues yes, and one argues no. Astronomer and SETI Institute co-founder Jill Tarter thinks we should; theoretical cosmologist and Science Channel host Paul Sutter argues that we shouldn’t.</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Don't Bring Extinct Creatures Back to Life</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Definitions & Legal Frameworks</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For (Anti De-extinction)</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against (Pro De-extinction)</u></p>
<p><u>Feasibility</u></p>
<p><u>Creatures</u></p>
<p><u>Conservation</u></p>
<p><u>Ethics & Moral Hazard</u></p>
<p><u>Cloning, CRISPR, & Gene-Editing</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Ten Years After the Global Financial Crisis, the System Is Safer</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/gfc</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10175</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> January 16, 2019</p>
<p>More than 10 years ago, Lehman Brothers collapsed, and the world witnessed one of the worst financial crises in global history. In the United States, the stock market plummeted, unemployment soared, and the economy was thrown into a recession. And many other countries faced a similar fate. Has the world learned its lesson? Some argue that the international framework for handling and responding to a future crisis is lacking. Beyond that, they argue, there is reduced market-making activity, less scope for reduced interest rates, and increased government spending and borrowing. But others are more optimistic, arguing that the past decade was one of recovery and reform, with governments passing regulations to deal with failing institutions and creating oversight infrastructure that shored up the banks. And, they say, there are fewer sketchy loans on the books. Is the global financial system more resilient? Or are we ill-prepared for next time?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/HOe0MDNB-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/HOe0MDNB-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Jason Furman</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">Jason Furman is the Aetna Professor of the Practice of Economic Policy jointly at Harvard Kennedy School and the Department of Economics at Harvard University. He is also a nonresident senior fellow at the Peterson Institute for International Economics. Previously he served as a top economic adviser to President Obama, including serving as the 28th Chairman of the Council of Economic Advisers, acting as President Obama’s chief economist and a cabinet member. During this time, Furman played a major role in most of the major economic policies of the Obama Administration. Furman also served under President Clinton. Furman engages in public policy through research, writing, and teaching, focusing on U.S. and international macroeconomics, fiscal policy, labor markets, and competition policy. He is a member of numerous organizations, including the Council on Foreign Relations, the Group of Thirty, and the Economic Strategy Group. He also serves as a Trustee of the Russell Sage Foundation and the advisory boards for the Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, the Bund Summit, the Hamilton Project, and the Washington Center for Equitable Growth. In addition to articles in scholarly journals and periodicals, Furman is a regular contributor to the </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">W</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">all Street Journal</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0"> and </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">Project Syndicate</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0"> and the editor of two books on economic policy.</span></span></p>
<p><strong>Neel Kashkari</strong><br>Neel Kashkari has been president and chief executive officer of the Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis since January 2016. In this role, he serves on the Federal Open Market Committee and was instrumental in establishing the Opportunity and Inclusive Growth Institute to promote greater economic equity. He’s also been outspoken about the need to address the "too big to fail" problem. Previously, he served in several senior positions at the U.S. Department of the Treasury, including overseeing the Troubled Asset Relief Program, or TARP, during the financial crisis.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Kenneth Rogoff</strong><br>Kenneth Rogoff is the Thomas D. Cabot professor of public policy and economics at Harvard University. From 2001 to 2003, he served as chief economist at the International Monetary Fund. His widely cited 2009 book with Carmen Reinhart, "This Time Is Different: Eight Centuries of Financial Folly," shows the remarkable quantitative similarities across time and countries in the run-up and aftermath of severe financial crises. Known for his seminal work on exchange rates and central bank independence, Rogoff is also the author of the 2016 book "The Curse of Cash."</p>
<p><strong>Gillian Tett</strong><br>Gillian Tett is chair of the editorial board and U.S. editor-at-large of the Financial Times, where she oversees global coverage of the financial markets. An award-winning journalist and best-selling author, Tett is also the co-founder of "Moral Money," a twice-weekly newsletter on socially responsible business. Her most recent book, "The Silo Effect," analyzes the financial system through the lens of cultural anthropology. She has been named Columnist of the Year (2014), Journalist of the Year (2009), and Business Journalist of the Year (2008) in the British Press Awards and received three awards from America's Society of Business and Economic Writers Awards. She is a best-selling author and has received the Royal Anthropological Institute Marsh Award and the American Anthropological Association President Medal for her work in social science.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Ten Years After the Global Financial Crisis, the System Is Safer</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Dodd-Frank Act</u></p>
<p><u>Interest Rates</u></p>
<p><u>Risky Loans & Debt</u></p>
<p><u>Yield Curve</u></p>
<p><u>Too Big To Fail</u></p>
<p><u>Around the World</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> January 16, 2019</p>
<p>More than 10 years ago, Lehman Brothers collapsed, and the world witnessed one of the worst financial crises in global history. In the United States, the stock market plummeted, unemployment soared, and the economy was thrown into a recession. And many other countries faced a similar fate. Has the world learned its lesson? Some argue that the international framework for handling and responding to a future crisis is lacking. Beyond that, they argue, there is reduced market-making activity, less scope for reduced interest rates, and increased government spending and borrowing. But others are more optimistic, arguing that the past decade was one of recovery and reform, with governments passing regulations to deal with failing institutions and creating oversight infrastructure that shored up the banks. And, they say, there are fewer sketchy loans on the books. Is the global financial system more resilient? Or are we ill-prepared for next time?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/HOe0MDNB-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/HOe0MDNB-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Jason Furman</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">Jason Furman is the Aetna Professor of the Practice of Economic Policy jointly at Harvard Kennedy School and the Department of Economics at Harvard University. He is also a nonresident senior fellow at the Peterson Institute for International Economics. Previously he served as a top economic adviser to President Obama, including serving as the 28th Chairman of the Council of Economic Advisers, acting as President Obama’s chief economist and a cabinet member. During this time, Furman played a major role in most of the major economic policies of the Obama Administration. Furman also served under President Clinton. Furman engages in public policy through research, writing, and teaching, focusing on U.S. and international macroeconomics, fiscal policy, labor markets, and competition policy. He is a member of numerous organizations, including the Council on Foreign Relations, the Group of Thirty, and the Economic Strategy Group. He also serves as a Trustee of the Russell Sage Foundation and the advisory boards for the Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, the Bund Summit, the Hamilton Project, and the Washington Center for Equitable Growth. In addition to articles in scholarly journals and periodicals, Furman is a regular contributor to the </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">W</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">all Street Journal</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0"> and </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">Project Syndicate</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0"> and the editor of two books on economic policy.</span></span></p>
<p><strong>Neel Kashkari</strong><br>Neel Kashkari has been president and chief executive officer of the Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis since January 2016. In this role, he serves on the Federal Open Market Committee and was instrumental in establishing the Opportunity and Inclusive Growth Institute to promote greater economic equity. He’s also been outspoken about the need to address the "too big to fail" problem. Previously, he served in several senior positions at the U.S. Department of the Treasury, including overseeing the Troubled Asset Relief Program, or TARP, during the financial crisis.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Kenneth Rogoff</strong><br>Kenneth Rogoff is the Thomas D. Cabot professor of public policy and economics at Harvard University. From 2001 to 2003, he served as chief economist at the International Monetary Fund. His widely cited 2009 book with Carmen Reinhart, "This Time Is Different: Eight Centuries of Financial Folly," shows the remarkable quantitative similarities across time and countries in the run-up and aftermath of severe financial crises. Known for his seminal work on exchange rates and central bank independence, Rogoff is also the author of the 2016 book "The Curse of Cash."</p>
<p><strong>Gillian Tett</strong><br>Gillian Tett is chair of the editorial board and U.S. editor-at-large of the Financial Times, where she oversees global coverage of the financial markets. An award-winning journalist and best-selling author, Tett is also the co-founder of "Moral Money," a twice-weekly newsletter on socially responsible business. Her most recent book, "The Silo Effect," analyzes the financial system through the lens of cultural anthropology. She has been named Columnist of the Year (2014), Journalist of the Year (2009), and Business Journalist of the Year (2008) in the British Press Awards and received three awards from America's Society of Business and Economic Writers Awards. She is a best-selling author and has received the Royal Anthropological Institute Marsh Award and the American Anthropological Association President Medal for her work in social science.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Ten Years After the Global Financial Crisis, the System Is Safer</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Dodd-Frank Act</u></p>
<p><u>Interest Rates</u></p>
<p><u>Risky Loans & Debt</u></p>
<p><u>Yield Curve</u></p>
<p><u>Too Big To Fail</u></p>
<p><u>Around the World</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
    
</rss>
