<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">

    <channel>
        <title>Open to Debate – Debates</title>
        <link>https://opentodebate.org</link>
        <description>Debates with related research and news</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 03:03:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
        <item>
            <title>Agree To Disagree: Identity Politics</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/agree-disagree-identity-politics</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:9967</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> December 11, 2020</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Culture, Politics</p>
<p>The public and pundits alike are still processing the most recent election, but this much we know: 2020 marks the most diverse Congress in American history, and President Trump garnered more minority voters in 2020 than in 2016. As Georgia faces two runoff elections, which will determine which party controls the Senate, gubernatorial nominee Stacey Abrams and other voting-rights advocates have focused on identity politics as a way to prevail in the electoral process. Is it a winning strategy? Two experts on race and identity in America sit with Open to Debate host and moderator John Donvan to debate.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/6uVGnzwI-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/6uVGnzwI-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Michael Eric Dyson</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO212281303 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto">Michael Eric Dyson, a globally renowned scholar of race, religion, and contemporary culture, will join Vanderbilt as Centennial Chair and University Distinguished Professor of African American and Diaspora Studies in the College of Arts and Science and University Distinguished Professor of Ethics and Society in the Divinity School on Jan. 1, 2021. Currently a professor of sociology at Georgetown University in Washington, D.C., Dyson is also a prominent commentator across several national media outlets and a contributing opinion writer at The New York Times. In addition, he serves as a contributing editor at The New Republic and <a href="https://andscape.com/">The Undefeated</a>, a website from ESPN.</span></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John McWhorter</strong><br>John H. McWhorter is an associate professor of English and comparative literature at Columbia University. He earned his B.A. from Rutgers, his M.A. from New York University, and his Ph.D. in linguistics from Stanford. Professor McWhorter has taught the American Studies seminar "Language in America," a study of American linguistic history that considered Native American languages, immigrant languages, Creole languages, and Black English—their development, interactions, and preservation. He has also taught the seminar "Language Contact," which focused specifically on the mixture of languages in North America and studied the development of creoles, pidgins, koines, "vehicular" languages, and nonstandard dialects. The seminar considered the perceived legitimacy of languages and the standing of language mixtures in media and education. Professor McWhorter is the author of more than twenty books, including “Losing the Race: Self-Sabotage in Black America,” and “Winning the Race: Beyond the Crisis in Black America.” He has written for many publications, including the New Republic, the Wall Street Journal, the Washington Post, and the New York Times.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>The Trump Colorado Case: Right Analysis, Wrong Outcome</strong> <small>2023-12-21 15:59:07</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>I read the dissent of the Colorado Supreme Court’s 4-3 decision, written by the court’s chief justice, Brian Boatright. I agree with Justice Boatright’s opinion.</p>
<p>I agree with the detailed analysis of the majority opinion that there is substantial evidence in the public record that Donald Trump violated Section 3 of the 14th Amendment – i.e., that he participated in an insurrection criminal conspiracy to thwart the lawful election of Joe Biden.</p>
<p>But it is not good for the country, and not good law, for Trump to be barred from running in 2024 without due process of law, which means a trial, the right to cross-examination, and a verdict of guilt by a jury “beyond a reasonable doubt.”</p>
<p>The irony of course is that the ultimate abuser and denier of our U.S. Constitution, the rule of law, and due process is Donald J. Trump. Remember his leading the 2016 cheers to “Lock her up!” This was a reference to Hillary Clinton’s practice of storing her State Department emails on a private server. He did not insist that Hillary Clinton be provided due process before leading that cheer. As we now know, the inspector general of the State Department did not find she had violated any criminal laws and FBI Director James Comey – no Hillary Clinton fan – agreed that not one of the 33,000 emails she transferred to her private server contained recognizable classified markings.</p>
<p>But that example cuts both ways. Yes, it is obviously hypocritical for Trump and his supporters to scream about due process in the Colorado case. But Mrs. Clinton’s example also shows why due process is so important. She was never convicted of anything. And, so far at least, neither has Trump.</p>
<p>Winning a criminal insurrection conspiracy case won’t be a cakewalk for Special Counsel Jack Smith. I say this because on Dec. 14 I participated as playing Smith’s role as “prosecutor” in a mock trial sponsored by the nationally respected nonprofit organization Open to Debate (https://opentodebate.org/debates/). Our mock argument was live-streamed last week, but it can be heard again on Jan. 5, 2024, the day before the anniversary of the Jan. 6 insurrection effort, on an NPR local affiliate; seen and heard on YouTube here (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X2AQxFtqh-4); on opentodebate.org; or on available podcast channels.</p>
<p>During this mock trial, the Trump side was represented by Sara Azari (https://www.azarilaw.com/sara-azari), a Los Angeles-based defense lawyer. Sara argued not only the absence of a smoking gun admission or written evidence by Trump that he knew he had lost the election; she also effectively argued that Trump’s claims, though false, are protected as political speech under the First Amendment.</p>
<p>My response was that the First Amendment does not protect lies that are part of a criminal conspiracy. I pointed out that there will be testimony from several people that Trump admitted he had lost but lied about it. However, I also pointed out that a jury can conclude beyond a reasonable doubt that he knew that the voter fraud did not cost him the election because the highest officials of his government, whom he appointed, all told him he had lost, including the attorney general, senior Justice Department officials, the director of national intelligence, and every single state official in the key battleground states whom he called. Georgia’s secretary of state of told him he had lost after three separate recounts. Still Trump asked him to “find” one vote more than the total Biden was found to have won Georgia – proving he knew he was asking the secretary of state to lie.</p>
<p>I also pointed out that 61 out of 61 state court judges rejected his claim that he had lost these key battleground states because of voter fraud. (Once in Pennsylvania, a court found some voter fraud, but that judge also ruled it wasn’t significant enough to change the outcome in that state).</p>
<p>In any event, there will and must be a test of Donald Trump’s culpability, but that must come in a trial, with due process by a finder of fact that reaches a verdict beyond a reasonable doubt. America cannot accept a verdict barring Trump from running for office based on a court hearing 1,500 miles from Washington, D.C., without a trial, on a civil court standard of “preponderance of the evidence” – meaning anything above 50%.</p>
<p>Those of us who oppose Trump can beat him at the ballot box, especially if and when he is convicted of felonies in one or more of the criminal trials he faces in federal and state courts. Colorado’s chief justice was right in his dissent when he concluded Trump should not be barred by a state court “in the absence of an insurrection-related conviction” – the latter word meaning after a trial and a jury of his peers finds the defendant guilty “beyond a reasonable doubt.”</p>
<p>Lanny Davis is the founder of the Washington, D.C., law firm, Lanny J. Davis & Associates. He is one of the first to use the concept of legal crisis management to solve client problems – operating at the intersection of law, media, and politics. He is a former special counsel to President Bill Clinton in 1996-98 and served on a privacy and civil liberties panel appointed by President George W. Bush. He has been writing his “Purple Nation” column for more than 13 years.</p></div>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> December 11, 2020</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Culture, Politics</p>
<p>The public and pundits alike are still processing the most recent election, but this much we know: 2020 marks the most diverse Congress in American history, and President Trump garnered more minority voters in 2020 than in 2016. As Georgia faces two runoff elections, which will determine which party controls the Senate, gubernatorial nominee Stacey Abrams and other voting-rights advocates have focused on identity politics as a way to prevail in the electoral process. Is it a winning strategy? Two experts on race and identity in America sit with Open to Debate host and moderator John Donvan to debate.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/6uVGnzwI-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/6uVGnzwI-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Michael Eric Dyson</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO212281303 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto">Michael Eric Dyson, a globally renowned scholar of race, religion, and contemporary culture, will join Vanderbilt as Centennial Chair and University Distinguished Professor of African American and Diaspora Studies in the College of Arts and Science and University Distinguished Professor of Ethics and Society in the Divinity School on Jan. 1, 2021. Currently a professor of sociology at Georgetown University in Washington, D.C., Dyson is also a prominent commentator across several national media outlets and a contributing opinion writer at The New York Times. In addition, he serves as a contributing editor at The New Republic and <a href="https://andscape.com/">The Undefeated</a>, a website from ESPN.</span></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John McWhorter</strong><br>John H. McWhorter is an associate professor of English and comparative literature at Columbia University. He earned his B.A. from Rutgers, his M.A. from New York University, and his Ph.D. in linguistics from Stanford. Professor McWhorter has taught the American Studies seminar "Language in America," a study of American linguistic history that considered Native American languages, immigrant languages, Creole languages, and Black English—their development, interactions, and preservation. He has also taught the seminar "Language Contact," which focused specifically on the mixture of languages in North America and studied the development of creoles, pidgins, koines, "vehicular" languages, and nonstandard dialects. The seminar considered the perceived legitimacy of languages and the standing of language mixtures in media and education. Professor McWhorter is the author of more than twenty books, including “Losing the Race: Self-Sabotage in Black America,” and “Winning the Race: Beyond the Crisis in Black America.” He has written for many publications, including the New Republic, the Wall Street Journal, the Washington Post, and the New York Times.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>The Trump Colorado Case: Right Analysis, Wrong Outcome</strong> <small>2023-12-21 15:59:07</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>I read the dissent of the Colorado Supreme Court’s 4-3 decision, written by the court’s chief justice, Brian Boatright. I agree with Justice Boatright’s opinion.</p>
<p>I agree with the detailed analysis of the majority opinion that there is substantial evidence in the public record that Donald Trump violated Section 3 of the 14th Amendment – i.e., that he participated in an insurrection criminal conspiracy to thwart the lawful election of Joe Biden.</p>
<p>But it is not good for the country, and not good law, for Trump to be barred from running in 2024 without due process of law, which means a trial, the right to cross-examination, and a verdict of guilt by a jury “beyond a reasonable doubt.”</p>
<p>The irony of course is that the ultimate abuser and denier of our U.S. Constitution, the rule of law, and due process is Donald J. Trump. Remember his leading the 2016 cheers to “Lock her up!” This was a reference to Hillary Clinton’s practice of storing her State Department emails on a private server. He did not insist that Hillary Clinton be provided due process before leading that cheer. As we now know, the inspector general of the State Department did not find she had violated any criminal laws and FBI Director James Comey – no Hillary Clinton fan – agreed that not one of the 33,000 emails she transferred to her private server contained recognizable classified markings.</p>
<p>But that example cuts both ways. Yes, it is obviously hypocritical for Trump and his supporters to scream about due process in the Colorado case. But Mrs. Clinton’s example also shows why due process is so important. She was never convicted of anything. And, so far at least, neither has Trump.</p>
<p>Winning a criminal insurrection conspiracy case won’t be a cakewalk for Special Counsel Jack Smith. I say this because on Dec. 14 I participated as playing Smith’s role as “prosecutor” in a mock trial sponsored by the nationally respected nonprofit organization Open to Debate (https://opentodebate.org/debates/). Our mock argument was live-streamed last week, but it can be heard again on Jan. 5, 2024, the day before the anniversary of the Jan. 6 insurrection effort, on an NPR local affiliate; seen and heard on YouTube here (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X2AQxFtqh-4); on opentodebate.org; or on available podcast channels.</p>
<p>During this mock trial, the Trump side was represented by Sara Azari (https://www.azarilaw.com/sara-azari), a Los Angeles-based defense lawyer. Sara argued not only the absence of a smoking gun admission or written evidence by Trump that he knew he had lost the election; she also effectively argued that Trump’s claims, though false, are protected as political speech under the First Amendment.</p>
<p>My response was that the First Amendment does not protect lies that are part of a criminal conspiracy. I pointed out that there will be testimony from several people that Trump admitted he had lost but lied about it. However, I also pointed out that a jury can conclude beyond a reasonable doubt that he knew that the voter fraud did not cost him the election because the highest officials of his government, whom he appointed, all told him he had lost, including the attorney general, senior Justice Department officials, the director of national intelligence, and every single state official in the key battleground states whom he called. Georgia’s secretary of state of told him he had lost after three separate recounts. Still Trump asked him to “find” one vote more than the total Biden was found to have won Georgia – proving he knew he was asking the secretary of state to lie.</p>
<p>I also pointed out that 61 out of 61 state court judges rejected his claim that he had lost these key battleground states because of voter fraud. (Once in Pennsylvania, a court found some voter fraud, but that judge also ruled it wasn’t significant enough to change the outcome in that state).</p>
<p>In any event, there will and must be a test of Donald Trump’s culpability, but that must come in a trial, with due process by a finder of fact that reaches a verdict beyond a reasonable doubt. America cannot accept a verdict barring Trump from running for office based on a court hearing 1,500 miles from Washington, D.C., without a trial, on a civil court standard of “preponderance of the evidence” – meaning anything above 50%.</p>
<p>Those of us who oppose Trump can beat him at the ballot box, especially if and when he is convicted of felonies in one or more of the criminal trials he faces in federal and state courts. Colorado’s chief justice was right in his dissent when he concluded Trump should not be barred by a state court “in the absence of an insurrection-related conviction” – the latter word meaning after a trial and a jury of his peers finds the defendant guilty “beyond a reasonable doubt.”</p>
<p>Lanny Davis is the founder of the Washington, D.C., law firm, Lanny J. Davis & Associates. He is one of the first to use the concept of legal crisis management to solve client problems – operating at the intersection of law, media, and politics. He is a former special counsel to President Bill Clinton in 1996-98 and served on a privacy and civil liberties panel appointed by President George W. Bush. He has been writing his “Purple Nation” column for more than 13 years.</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Stop Worrying About National Deficits</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/stop-worrying-about-national-deficits</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10170</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> December 07, 2020</p>
<p>Governments around the world have spent unprecedented sums — trillions of dollars — to combat the economic impacts of coronavirus. In the United States alone, the national deficit surpassed $3 trillion this year. That’s three times larger than in 2019 and some $2 trillion more than the White House projected back in February. But just what does rising government debt mean for our future? A new crop of economists – adherents to Modern Monetary Theory – have a bold proposition: Don't worry about it. In a modern economy, they argue, deficits are no bogeyman. And they're certainly no excuse to halt state spending on things like education and healthcare. Take Japan, for instance, where the national deficit is a soaring $12 trillion and counting. But others are more wary. They warn that unless political leaders balance the books, soaring federal debt will undermine the nation's economic future and compromise national security and its sovereignty. So, we ask, are rising national deficits cause for concern?
<script src="https://apps.elfsight.com/p/platform.js" defer></script>
<div class="elfsight-app-d3cace7c-13dd-4c8c-973d-65bcb0405037"></div></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/Ni9WHpFk-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/Ni9WHpFk-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>James Galbraith</strong><br>James Galbraith is an economist and professor of public affairs at the University of Texas at Austin. He was executive director of the Joint Economic Committee of the U.S. Congress in the early 1980s and previously chaired the board of Economists for Peace and Security. Galbraith is the author of several books, including "Inequality: What Everyone Needs to Know."</p>
<p><strong>Stephanie Kelton</strong><br>Stephanie Kelton is the bestselling author of "The Deficit Myth" and a leading authority on Modern Monetary Theory, a new approach to economics that has been embraced by leaders like Bernie Sanders and Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez. Kelton served as chief economist on the U.S. Senate Budget Committee and was a senior economic adviser to Sanders' presidential campaigns. She was named one of the 50 people most influencing the policy debate in America by POLITICO and is currently a professor at Stony Brook University.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Todd Buchholz</strong><br>Todd Buchholz is a leading expert on the economy, stock market, and politics. He was director of economic policy under President George H. W. Bush and managing director of the Tiger Management hedge fund. He is the author of "New Ideas from Dead Economists" and "The Price of Prosperity: Why Rich Nations Fail and How to Renew Them."</p>
<p><strong>Otmar Issing</strong><br>Otmar Issing is a former chief economist and member of the board of the European Central Bank. Issing chaired the Advisory Council on a New Financial Order appointed by German Chancellor Angela Merkel (2008-2010) and was as an international adviser to Goldman Sachs (2007-2018). He currently serves as president of the Center for Financial Studies at Goethe University, Frankfurt.</p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> December 07, 2020</p>
<p>Governments around the world have spent unprecedented sums — trillions of dollars — to combat the economic impacts of coronavirus. In the United States alone, the national deficit surpassed $3 trillion this year. That’s three times larger than in 2019 and some $2 trillion more than the White House projected back in February. But just what does rising government debt mean for our future? A new crop of economists – adherents to Modern Monetary Theory – have a bold proposition: Don't worry about it. In a modern economy, they argue, deficits are no bogeyman. And they're certainly no excuse to halt state spending on things like education and healthcare. Take Japan, for instance, where the national deficit is a soaring $12 trillion and counting. But others are more wary. They warn that unless political leaders balance the books, soaring federal debt will undermine the nation's economic future and compromise national security and its sovereignty. So, we ask, are rising national deficits cause for concern?
<script src="https://apps.elfsight.com/p/platform.js" defer></script>
<div class="elfsight-app-d3cace7c-13dd-4c8c-973d-65bcb0405037"></div></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/Ni9WHpFk-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/Ni9WHpFk-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>James Galbraith</strong><br>James Galbraith is an economist and professor of public affairs at the University of Texas at Austin. He was executive director of the Joint Economic Committee of the U.S. Congress in the early 1980s and previously chaired the board of Economists for Peace and Security. Galbraith is the author of several books, including "Inequality: What Everyone Needs to Know."</p>
<p><strong>Stephanie Kelton</strong><br>Stephanie Kelton is the bestselling author of "The Deficit Myth" and a leading authority on Modern Monetary Theory, a new approach to economics that has been embraced by leaders like Bernie Sanders and Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez. Kelton served as chief economist on the U.S. Senate Budget Committee and was a senior economic adviser to Sanders' presidential campaigns. She was named one of the 50 people most influencing the policy debate in America by POLITICO and is currently a professor at Stony Brook University.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Todd Buchholz</strong><br>Todd Buchholz is a leading expert on the economy, stock market, and politics. He was director of economic policy under President George H. W. Bush and managing director of the Tiger Management hedge fund. He is the author of "New Ideas from Dead Economists" and "The Price of Prosperity: Why Rich Nations Fail and How to Renew Them."</p>
<p><strong>Otmar Issing</strong><br>Otmar Issing is a former chief economist and member of the board of the European Central Bank. Issing chaired the Advisory Council on a New Financial Order appointed by German Chancellor Angela Merkel (2008-2010) and was as an international adviser to Goldman Sachs (2007-2018). He currently serves as president of the Center for Financial Studies at Goethe University, Frankfurt.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Agree to Disagree: Election Lawsuits</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/agree-disagree-election-lawsuits</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:9964</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> November 13, 2020</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Law, U.S.</p>
<p>Joe Biden delivered a victory speech. His team is planning to take power. But rather than concede, President Trump has instead turned to the courts, with election lawsuits in states like Pennsylvania, Georgia, and Arizona. It's a historic moment, and for many an unsettling one. But could these lawsuits actually be good for democracy? Two competing legal minds weigh in, with Open to Debate host and moderator John Donvan at the helm.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/LINut8Lf-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/LINut8Lf-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rebecca Roiphe</strong><br>Rebecca Roiphe studies lawyers’ ethics and the history of the legal profession, focusing on the interaction between lawyers’ work and the rhetoric or ideals of professionalism. Prior to joining New York Law School, Professor Roiphe worked as a Manhattan prosecutor. She also served as a law clerk for the Honorable Bruce Selya, U.S. Court of Appeals for the First Circuit. She draws on her professional experiences and her training as a historian in her writing. Her scholarship emphasizes the important, mediating role prosecutors play in American democracy and examines the country’s tradition of prosecutorial independence, particularly with regard to the President’s power to control the Department of Justice. Professor Roiphe’s opinion pieces have appeared in Slate, the New York Review of Books, Politico, U.S. News, and other popular press. She is frequently quoted as an expert on legal ethics and criminal justice in the media, including in The New York Times, The Washington Post, Bloomberg News, Vice News, and the New York Law Journal. Professor Roiphe has appeared on MSNBC and CNN. She is a contributing legal analyst at CBS News, where she appears regularly to discuss national legal issues, particularly those involving Special Counsel Robert Mueller’s probe into Russian influence in the 2016 election and the impeachment trials of President Donald J. Trump.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Ian Bassin</strong><br>Ian Bassin is co-founder and executive director of Protect Democracy. He previously served as Associate White House Counsel, where, in addition to counseling the President and senior White House staff on administrative and constitutional law, his responsibilities included ensuring that White House and executive branch officials complied with the laws, rules, and norms that protect the fundamentally democratic nature of our government. His writing on democracy, authoritarianism, and American law and politics has appeared in The New York Times, The Washington Post, The Los Angeles Times, The Atlantic, Slate, Salon, and other publications. He received his J.D. from Yale Law School and a B.A. from Wesleyan University.</p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> November 13, 2020</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Law, U.S.</p>
<p>Joe Biden delivered a victory speech. His team is planning to take power. But rather than concede, President Trump has instead turned to the courts, with election lawsuits in states like Pennsylvania, Georgia, and Arizona. It's a historic moment, and for many an unsettling one. But could these lawsuits actually be good for democracy? Two competing legal minds weigh in, with Open to Debate host and moderator John Donvan at the helm.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/LINut8Lf-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/LINut8Lf-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rebecca Roiphe</strong><br>Rebecca Roiphe studies lawyers’ ethics and the history of the legal profession, focusing on the interaction between lawyers’ work and the rhetoric or ideals of professionalism. Prior to joining New York Law School, Professor Roiphe worked as a Manhattan prosecutor. She also served as a law clerk for the Honorable Bruce Selya, U.S. Court of Appeals for the First Circuit. She draws on her professional experiences and her training as a historian in her writing. Her scholarship emphasizes the important, mediating role prosecutors play in American democracy and examines the country’s tradition of prosecutorial independence, particularly with regard to the President’s power to control the Department of Justice. Professor Roiphe’s opinion pieces have appeared in Slate, the New York Review of Books, Politico, U.S. News, and other popular press. She is frequently quoted as an expert on legal ethics and criminal justice in the media, including in The New York Times, The Washington Post, Bloomberg News, Vice News, and the New York Law Journal. Professor Roiphe has appeared on MSNBC and CNN. She is a contributing legal analyst at CBS News, where she appears regularly to discuss national legal issues, particularly those involving Special Counsel Robert Mueller’s probe into Russian influence in the 2016 election and the impeachment trials of President Donald J. Trump.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Ian Bassin</strong><br>Ian Bassin is co-founder and executive director of Protect Democracy. He previously served as Associate White House Counsel, where, in addition to counseling the President and senior White House staff on administrative and constitutional law, his responsibilities included ensuring that White House and executive branch officials complied with the laws, rules, and norms that protect the fundamentally democratic nature of our government. His writing on democracy, authoritarianism, and American law and politics has appeared in The New York Times, The Washington Post, The Los Angeles Times, The Atlantic, Slate, Salon, and other publications. He received his J.D. from Yale Law School and a B.A. from Wesleyan University.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>A U.S.-China Space Race Is Good For Humanity</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/us-china-space-race-good-humanity</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:9942</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> November 07, 2020</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Politics, Science, Tech</p>
<p>China is ramping up its national space industry with huge investments in next-generation technologies that promise to transform military, economic, and political realities. Against this backdrop, we ask: Would a new U.S.-China space race be good for humanity? Could it drive innovation, rally public support for science and discovery, and launch humans into the next generation? Or would this competition catalyze an expensive global arms race, militarize space for decades to come, and destroy any hope of international peace and cohesion in the future?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://www.youtube.com/embed/OX1fr_8YmXs' target='_blank'>https://www.youtube.com/embed/OX1fr_8YmXs</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Bidushi Bhattacharya</strong><br>Bidushi Bhattacharya is a rocket scientist and entrepreneur. After two decades with NASA working on projects including the Hubble Space Telescope and the Galileo probe to Jupiter, Bhattacharya founded Astropreneurs HUB, Southeast Asia’s first space technology incubator. She currently serves on the Global Entrepreneurship Network Space Advisory Board and is the CEO of Bhattacharya Space Enterprises, a Singaporean startup dedicated to space-related education and training.</p>
<p><strong>Avi Loeb</strong><br>Abraham (Avi) Loeb is a theoretical physicist, author, and Harvard professor. He was the longest-serving chair of Harvard's astronomy department (for nine years) and is an elected member of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, the American Physical Society, and the International Academy of Astronautics. Loeb is a member of the President's Council of Advisors on Science and Technology at the White House, and in 2012, TIME magazine selected Loeb as one of the 25 most influential people in space.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Michio Kaku</strong><br>Michio Kaku is one of the most widely recognized figures in science. He is a theoretical physicist, an international bestselling author, and the co-founder of String Field Theory. His most recent book, "Future of Humanity," projects the future of the space program centuries into the future. Kaku is a professor at the City University of New York.</p>
<p><strong>Raji Rajagopalan</strong><br><div class="debater-profile">
<div class="speaker-details">
<div class="banner_sub_title"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="depater-bio">Rajeswari Pillai Rajagopalan is a distinguished fellow and head of the Nuclear and Space Policy Initiative at the Observer Research Foundation, one of India’s leading think tanks. Rajagopalan also recently served as a technical advisor to the United Nations Group of Governmental Experts on the Prevention of Arms Races in Outer Space. She is the author of "The Dragon's Fire: Chinese Military Strategy and Its Implications for Asia."</div></p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Up for debate: Would doing less in Ukraine help US prepare for China challenge?</strong> <small>2023-02-23 17:18:59</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>CHINA HAWKS SEEK SHIFT AWAY FROM UKRAINE: Just as Ukraine is facing a critical inflection point in what the Pentagon sees as a small window to break through Russian lines and reclaim the momentum in the yearlong war, there are Republicans in Congress who argue now is the time for the U.S. to scale back its support to Kyiv.</p>
<p>Among those advocating a turn away from Ukraine is Sen. Josh Hawley (R-MO), who is scheduled to deliver an address today at the Heritage Foundation, in which he will advocate a defense policy that prioritizes China as America’s biggest threat and “challenges the consensus on Ukraine.” The speech will focus on “key decisions America must make to deter China – including doing less in Ukraine,” according to a press release from his office.</p>
<p>“I want the Europeans on the continent there to do the heavy lifting when it comes to supporting Ukraine,” Hawley told (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vQNa2lHyAb0&t=78s) St. Louis television station KSDK last week. “Obviously I want to see Russia defeated …There's no doubt about any of that.”</p>
<p>“The question is, what are America's interests in the midst of this? Is our interest in nation-building in Ukraine? And by that I mean writing checks directly to the Ukrainian government,” Hawley said. “That's what we're doing and have been doing for months. What we should be doing is saying to the Europeans, Germany at the front of the list, you need to take the first priority, the lead in defending Ukraine and standing up to Russia. We will prioritize China.”</p>
<p>NATO DISCUSSES MAJOR INCREASE IN DEFENSE SPENDING ACROSS ALLIANCE (https://www.washingtonexaminer.com/restoring-america/patriotism-unity/defense-national-security/nato-major-increase-defense-spending)</p>
<p>THE ‘UKRAINE FATIGUE’ RESOLUTION: Hawley is in the minority in his party, but he’s not alone. Last week, Rep. Matt Gaetz (R-FL) introduced a resolution that would express to the House that it’s time to cut off U.S. assistance to Ukraine’s war effort.</p>
<p>Dubbed the “Ukraine Fatigue Resolution,” the symbolic bill has no chance of enactment, but it did attract 10 hard-right cosponsors: Reps. Andy Biggs (R-AZ), Lauren Boebert (R-CO), Paul Gosar (R-AZ), Marjorie Taylor Greene (R-GA), Anna Paulina Luna (R-FL), Thomas Massie (R-KY), Mary Miller (R-IL), Barry Moore (R-AL), Ralph Norman (R-SC), and Matt Rosendale (R-MT).</p>
<p>The complaints about the high cost of U.S. aid come as a survey (https://apnorc.org/projects/acontinuing-support-for-u-s-involvement-a-year-into-the-war-between-russia-and-ukraine-a/) conducted by the Associated Press-NORC Center for Public Affairs Research shows that while Americans still think the U.S. should play “at least some role in the war,” support for specific interventions like supplying weapons is “waning.”</p>
<p>MCCAUL: ‘THEY JUST WANT TO KNOW WHERE THE MONEY'S GONE’: The new chairman of the House Foreign Affairs Committee says many who are wavering on funding for Ukraine are concerned about how the money is being spent.</p>
<p>“You've got people in the fringe elements on both sides that are just dug in. You have a lot of people in the middle on my side of the aisle who are just being a little bit quiet to see how the winds blow because their big question is, ‘I just want to know where the money's gone,’” Rep. Mike McCaul (R-TX) said in an interview with the Washington Examiner to be published tomorrow.</p>
<p>“If I can explain that to them, and explain the accountability and the audits taking place … and then bring the Trump national security team in to say that this is the right foreign policy. I think those combined would go a long ways,” McCaul said. “What I want to do is basically be able to tell the story of where the money has gone. A third of it's gone into replenishing our stockpile and modernizing our weapon systems, a third is going to our defense contractors to make new weapons, which we really need, and then a third's going into Ukraine.”</p>
<p>“I mean, with less than 3% of our Department of Defense budget, they've annihilated the Russian military, they've humiliated them,” McCaul added. “Without one American soldier, which is key.”</p>
<p>RUSSIA CONTINUES TO POUR ‘ILL-TRAINED’ TROOPS INTO UKRAINE, AUSTIN SAYS (https://www.washingtonexaminer.com/policy/defense-national-security/russia-continues-to-pour-ill-trained-troops-ukraine)</p></div>
<div><strong>John Donvan on debate "The Trump Doctrine A Global Reckoning" at Council on Foreign Relations</strong> <small>2025-05-22 14:39:42</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>John Donvan of Open to Debate discusses debate he served as Moderator in Chief, "The Trump Doctrine A Global Reckoning" at Council on Foreign Relations in New York City on May 6, 2025.</p>
<p>More on https://opentodebate.org/ (https://www.youtube.com/redirect?event=video_description&redir_token=QUFFLUhqbUZoa1VwcXBpWllvNlFuSVRxRG83ZXBFb3RTQXxBQ3Jtc0tuUy1pNTg5Yy1sek5KcDFPV1BmNkRLVDRFaGR5SXRxZkF1QjdRLUtscnVvRWVWMDBxOFlnNm1PX2hzZWtlazQwRWpOSDNRalQxUGVPS2lIZkZoU1hNOHNCZkVrTHBRdXZmRUxpQjROVVNXaVJNekRUWQ&q=https%3A%2F%2Fopentodebate.org%2F&v=2l6qL50iRa0)</p>
<p>More on Council on Foreign Relations at: https://www.cfr.org/ (https://www.youtube.com/redirect?event=video_description&redir_token=QUFFLUhqbFJnelVfcE1FNFBPb2xsN3pmeE5oNkRjNGtOd3xBQ3Jtc0tucGl4aGRvQXlJSERiWEw2NkNSRGp1cEE5a09hLUFoTDM2M3ppQ1ZkRE5GdkJKSldFMkc5M0twRE8yNVptYUFmZlNRODlGdXVLZ1JmWkF5eGRaVVdpV3hRNHFTUk15RGJBV0czdEhCUmlzaTVhRDFwcw&q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.cfr.org%2F&v=2l6qL50iRa0)</p>
<p>Video by Ken Kraetzer for CaMMVetsMedia LLC "Covering Cadets, Midshipmen, the Military and Veterans Proudly Since 2008" More at CaMMVetsMediaLLC.com</p></div>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> November 07, 2020</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Politics, Science, Tech</p>
<p>China is ramping up its national space industry with huge investments in next-generation technologies that promise to transform military, economic, and political realities. Against this backdrop, we ask: Would a new U.S.-China space race be good for humanity? Could it drive innovation, rally public support for science and discovery, and launch humans into the next generation? Or would this competition catalyze an expensive global arms race, militarize space for decades to come, and destroy any hope of international peace and cohesion in the future?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://www.youtube.com/embed/OX1fr_8YmXs' target='_blank'>https://www.youtube.com/embed/OX1fr_8YmXs</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Bidushi Bhattacharya</strong><br>Bidushi Bhattacharya is a rocket scientist and entrepreneur. After two decades with NASA working on projects including the Hubble Space Telescope and the Galileo probe to Jupiter, Bhattacharya founded Astropreneurs HUB, Southeast Asia’s first space technology incubator. She currently serves on the Global Entrepreneurship Network Space Advisory Board and is the CEO of Bhattacharya Space Enterprises, a Singaporean startup dedicated to space-related education and training.</p>
<p><strong>Avi Loeb</strong><br>Abraham (Avi) Loeb is a theoretical physicist, author, and Harvard professor. He was the longest-serving chair of Harvard's astronomy department (for nine years) and is an elected member of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, the American Physical Society, and the International Academy of Astronautics. Loeb is a member of the President's Council of Advisors on Science and Technology at the White House, and in 2012, TIME magazine selected Loeb as one of the 25 most influential people in space.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Michio Kaku</strong><br>Michio Kaku is one of the most widely recognized figures in science. He is a theoretical physicist, an international bestselling author, and the co-founder of String Field Theory. His most recent book, "Future of Humanity," projects the future of the space program centuries into the future. Kaku is a professor at the City University of New York.</p>
<p><strong>Raji Rajagopalan</strong><br><div class="debater-profile">
<div class="speaker-details">
<div class="banner_sub_title"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="depater-bio">Rajeswari Pillai Rajagopalan is a distinguished fellow and head of the Nuclear and Space Policy Initiative at the Observer Research Foundation, one of India’s leading think tanks. Rajagopalan also recently served as a technical advisor to the United Nations Group of Governmental Experts on the Prevention of Arms Races in Outer Space. She is the author of "The Dragon's Fire: Chinese Military Strategy and Its Implications for Asia."</div></p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Up for debate: Would doing less in Ukraine help US prepare for China challenge?</strong> <small>2023-02-23 17:18:59</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>CHINA HAWKS SEEK SHIFT AWAY FROM UKRAINE: Just as Ukraine is facing a critical inflection point in what the Pentagon sees as a small window to break through Russian lines and reclaim the momentum in the yearlong war, there are Republicans in Congress who argue now is the time for the U.S. to scale back its support to Kyiv.</p>
<p>Among those advocating a turn away from Ukraine is Sen. Josh Hawley (R-MO), who is scheduled to deliver an address today at the Heritage Foundation, in which he will advocate a defense policy that prioritizes China as America’s biggest threat and “challenges the consensus on Ukraine.” The speech will focus on “key decisions America must make to deter China – including doing less in Ukraine,” according to a press release from his office.</p>
<p>“I want the Europeans on the continent there to do the heavy lifting when it comes to supporting Ukraine,” Hawley told (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vQNa2lHyAb0&t=78s) St. Louis television station KSDK last week. “Obviously I want to see Russia defeated …There's no doubt about any of that.”</p>
<p>“The question is, what are America's interests in the midst of this? Is our interest in nation-building in Ukraine? And by that I mean writing checks directly to the Ukrainian government,” Hawley said. “That's what we're doing and have been doing for months. What we should be doing is saying to the Europeans, Germany at the front of the list, you need to take the first priority, the lead in defending Ukraine and standing up to Russia. We will prioritize China.”</p>
<p>NATO DISCUSSES MAJOR INCREASE IN DEFENSE SPENDING ACROSS ALLIANCE (https://www.washingtonexaminer.com/restoring-america/patriotism-unity/defense-national-security/nato-major-increase-defense-spending)</p>
<p>THE ‘UKRAINE FATIGUE’ RESOLUTION: Hawley is in the minority in his party, but he’s not alone. Last week, Rep. Matt Gaetz (R-FL) introduced a resolution that would express to the House that it’s time to cut off U.S. assistance to Ukraine’s war effort.</p>
<p>Dubbed the “Ukraine Fatigue Resolution,” the symbolic bill has no chance of enactment, but it did attract 10 hard-right cosponsors: Reps. Andy Biggs (R-AZ), Lauren Boebert (R-CO), Paul Gosar (R-AZ), Marjorie Taylor Greene (R-GA), Anna Paulina Luna (R-FL), Thomas Massie (R-KY), Mary Miller (R-IL), Barry Moore (R-AL), Ralph Norman (R-SC), and Matt Rosendale (R-MT).</p>
<p>The complaints about the high cost of U.S. aid come as a survey (https://apnorc.org/projects/acontinuing-support-for-u-s-involvement-a-year-into-the-war-between-russia-and-ukraine-a/) conducted by the Associated Press-NORC Center for Public Affairs Research shows that while Americans still think the U.S. should play “at least some role in the war,” support for specific interventions like supplying weapons is “waning.”</p>
<p>MCCAUL: ‘THEY JUST WANT TO KNOW WHERE THE MONEY'S GONE’: The new chairman of the House Foreign Affairs Committee says many who are wavering on funding for Ukraine are concerned about how the money is being spent.</p>
<p>“You've got people in the fringe elements on both sides that are just dug in. You have a lot of people in the middle on my side of the aisle who are just being a little bit quiet to see how the winds blow because their big question is, ‘I just want to know where the money's gone,’” Rep. Mike McCaul (R-TX) said in an interview with the Washington Examiner to be published tomorrow.</p>
<p>“If I can explain that to them, and explain the accountability and the audits taking place … and then bring the Trump national security team in to say that this is the right foreign policy. I think those combined would go a long ways,” McCaul said. “What I want to do is basically be able to tell the story of where the money has gone. A third of it's gone into replenishing our stockpile and modernizing our weapon systems, a third is going to our defense contractors to make new weapons, which we really need, and then a third's going into Ukraine.”</p>
<p>“I mean, with less than 3% of our Department of Defense budget, they've annihilated the Russian military, they've humiliated them,” McCaul added. “Without one American soldier, which is key.”</p>
<p>RUSSIA CONTINUES TO POUR ‘ILL-TRAINED’ TROOPS INTO UKRAINE, AUSTIN SAYS (https://www.washingtonexaminer.com/policy/defense-national-security/russia-continues-to-pour-ill-trained-troops-ukraine)</p></div>
<div><strong>John Donvan on debate "The Trump Doctrine A Global Reckoning" at Council on Foreign Relations</strong> <small>2025-05-22 14:39:42</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>John Donvan of Open to Debate discusses debate he served as Moderator in Chief, "The Trump Doctrine A Global Reckoning" at Council on Foreign Relations in New York City on May 6, 2025.</p>
<p>More on https://opentodebate.org/ (https://www.youtube.com/redirect?event=video_description&redir_token=QUFFLUhqbUZoa1VwcXBpWllvNlFuSVRxRG83ZXBFb3RTQXxBQ3Jtc0tuUy1pNTg5Yy1sek5KcDFPV1BmNkRLVDRFaGR5SXRxZkF1QjdRLUtscnVvRWVWMDBxOFlnNm1PX2hzZWtlazQwRWpOSDNRalQxUGVPS2lIZkZoU1hNOHNCZkVrTHBRdXZmRUxpQjROVVNXaVJNekRUWQ&q=https%3A%2F%2Fopentodebate.org%2F&v=2l6qL50iRa0)</p>
<p>More on Council on Foreign Relations at: https://www.cfr.org/ (https://www.youtube.com/redirect?event=video_description&redir_token=QUFFLUhqbFJnelVfcE1FNFBPb2xsN3pmeE5oNkRjNGtOd3xBQ3Jtc0tucGl4aGRvQXlJSERiWEw2NkNSRGp1cEE5a09hLUFoTDM2M3ppQ1ZkRE5GdkJKSldFMkc5M0twRE8yNVptYUFmZlNRODlGdXVLZ1JmWkF5eGRaVVdpV3hRNHFTUk15RGJBV0czdEhCUmlzaTVhRDFwcw&q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.cfr.org%2F&v=2l6qL50iRa0)</p>
<p>Video by Ken Kraetzer for CaMMVetsMedia LLC "Covering Cadets, Midshipmen, the Military and Veterans Proudly Since 2008" More at CaMMVetsMediaLLC.com</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Unresolved: American Policing</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/unresolved-american-policing</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10364</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> September 30, 2020</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Law, Politics, U.S.</p>
<p>Historic protests calling for police reform have erupted across the nation. But just what could these reforms mean? And how should we see the criminal justice system today? Staged in our “Unresolved” format, this debate brings together five experts to tackle pressing questions on the history and future of policing in the U.S. including: Should we defund the police? Do police unions do more harm than good? And has policing become too militarized?
<div class="elfsight-app-eb31570a-6392-470a-93d1-f46144da2771"></div></p>
<p><strong>Unresolved Questions:</strong></p>
<p>• Motion: We Should Defund the Police</p>
<p>• Motion: The Police Have Become Too Militarized</p>
<p>• Motion: Police Unions Do More Harm Than Good</p>
<p>• Motion: Washington - Not Local Leaders - Should Set Law Enforcement Standards</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://www.youtube.com/embed/rbBPR2pOWWE' target='_blank'>https://www.youtube.com/embed/rbBPR2pOWWE</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Paul Butler</strong><br><span class="TextRun BCX0 SCXO159012287" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun BCX0 SCXO159012287">Paul Butler is the Albert Brick Professor in Law at Georgetown University Law Center and a legal analyst on MSNBC. Previously, Butler served as a federal prosecutor with the U.S. Department of Justice, where his specialty was public corruption. His prosecutions included a United States Senator, three FBI agents, and several other law enforcement officials. He lectures regularly for the American Bar Association and the NAACP, and at colleges, law schools, and community organizations throughout the US. He also serves on the District of Columbia Code Revision Commission as an appointee of the D.C. City Council and was elected to the American Law Institute in 2003. He was also the Bennett Boskey Visiting Professor at Harvard Law School during the 2017-2018 school year. Butler is the author of “Let’s Get Free: A Hip-Hop Theory of Justice”, which received the Harry Chapin Media award, and “Chokehold: Policing Black Men”, which was named one of the best non-fiction books of 2017 by major news outlets and a finalist for the 2018 NAACP Image Award for best non-fiction. He holds an honorary Doctor of Law Degree from the City University of New York and is a graduate of Yale University and Harvard Law School.</span></span></p>
<p><strong>Jason Johnson</strong><br>Jason Johnson is president of the Law Enforcement Legal Defense Fund, a national police advocacy organization. Johnson served as deputy commissioner of the Baltimore Police Department between 2016 and 2018.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rafael Mangual</strong><br>Rafael Mangual is a senior fellow and deputy director of legal policy at the Manhattan Institute and a contributing editor of the City Journal. An expert on urban crime, policing, and incarceration, he was recently appointed to serve a four-year term as a member of the New York State Advisory Committee of the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights.</p>
<p><strong>Sue Rahr</strong><br>Sue Rahr is executive director of the Washington State Criminal Justice Training Commission, overseeing the training of all city and county law enforcement and corrections officers in the state. Rahr served on President Obama’s Task Force on 21st Century Policing. She was King County Sheriff between 2005 and 2012.</p>
<p><strong>Vikrant Reddy</strong><br>Vikrant Reddy is a senior fellow at the Charles Koch Institute, specializing in the area of criminal justice reform. Reddy previously served as a senior policy analyst at the Texas Public Policy Foundation and is also an appointee to the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights Texas State Advisory Committee.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Short Circuit: A Roundup of Recent Federal Court Decisions</strong> <small>2023-02-07 20:40:25</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Wanted posters, vague and threatening letters, and dragging a 75-pound dummy.</p>
<p>Please enjoy the latest edition of Short Circuit (http://ij.org/about-us/shortcircuit/), a weekly feature written by a bunch of people at the Institute for Justice.</p>
<p>Last summer Alexandria, La. police pulled over Mario Rosales for failing to use his turn signal and detained him for 20 minutes, probing for evidence of other, more serious lawbreaking, cutting him loose when they didn't find any. But wait! The officers' dashcam shows that Mario did signal. Those sneaky dogs! Click here (https://ij.org/case/louisiana-traffic-stop/) to learn more about IJ's latest case, a challenge to pretextual, picayune harassment that passes for police work.</p>
<p>Over at Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S., IJ Attorney Anya Bidwell debates the Heritage Foundation's John Malcom on the merits of qualified immunity, explaining why it is really and truly okay if officers who make good-faith mistakes in life-and-death situations are not shielded from suit. With an appearance by The New York Times's Adam Liptak.</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Unresolved: American Policing</em></p>
<p><u>Motion: We Should Defund the Police</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.vox.com/2020/6/26/21303849/what-defund-the-police-really-means' target='_blank'>What "defund the police" really means</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.usatoday.com/story/money/2020/06/26/how-much-money-goes-to-police-departments-in-americas-largest-cities/112004904/' target='_blank'>Here's how much money goes to police departments in largest cities across the U.S.</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.cnn.com/2020/06/06/us/what-is-defund-police-trnd/index.html' target='_blank'>There's a growing call to defund the police. Here's what it means</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.bbc.com/news/election-us-2020-53997196' target='_blank'>US 2020 Election: Does Joe Biden support defunding the police?</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/defund-the-police' target='_blank'>We should still defund the police</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.usatoday.com/story/opinion/voices/2020/06/11/defunding-police-could-backfire-black-former-detective-column/5331008002/' target='_blank'>Black ex-cop: I understand the anger but don't defund police. It could make things worse</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.themarshallproject.org/2020/06/09/support-for-defunding-the-police-department-is-growing-here-s-why-it-s-not-a-silver-bullet' target='_blank'>Support for defunding the police department is growing. Here's why it's not a silver bullet</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://thehill.com/opinion/criminal-justice/501901-defund-the-police-is-not-a-serious-or-a-safe-solution/' target='_blank'>Defund the police is not a serious or a safe solution</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.bostonherald.com/2020/07/10/seattle-experiment-shows-that-we-need-police/' target='_blank'>Seattle experiment shows that we need police</a></p>
<p><u>Motion: The Police Have Become Too Militarized</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.wsj.com/articles/SB10001424127887323848804578608040780519904' target='_blank'>Rise of the warrior cop</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.marketplace.org/2020/06/12/police-departments-1033-military-equipment-weapons/' target='_blank'>How police departments got billions of dollars of tactical military equipment</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/01/us/politics/police-military-gear.html' target='_blank'>Lawmakers begin bipartisan push to cut off police access to military-style gear</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.latimes.com/politics/la-na-pol-military-gear-20170828-story.html' target='_blank'>Trump is endin grestrictions that limit the military from giving surplus gear to police</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2020/06/overlooked-role-guns-police-reform-debate/613258/' target='_blank'>The overlooked rold of guns in the police-reform debate</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.wbur.org/hereandnow/2020/06/23/do-police-need-guns' target='_blank'>Do police need guns?</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/21/us/politics/senate-police-military-equipment.html' target='_blank'>Senate kills broad curbs on military gear for police, thwarting push to demilitarize</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://journalistsresource.org/politics-and-government/militarization-police-reduce-crime-research/' target='_blank'>The militarization of America's police may reduce crime: new study</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.usatoday.com/story/opinion/2017/08/31/police-need-military-equipment-combat-rising-crime-rates-and-police-deaths-alfred-regnery-column/613471001/' target='_blank'>Police need military equipment to combat rising crime rates and police deaths</a></p>
<p><u>Motion: Police Unions Do More Harm Than Good</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/06/us/police-unions-minneapolis-kroll.html' target='_blank'>How police unions became such powerful opponents to reform efforts</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://news.bloomberglaw.com/daily-labor-report/police-union-membership-rising-as-positions-sit-vacant' target='_blank'>Police union membership rising as positions sit vacant</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/politics-news/national-labor-groups-mostly-close-ranks-defend-police-unions-n1231573' target='_blank'>National Labor groups mostly close ranks to defend police unions</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/21290981/police-union-contracts-minneapolis-reform' target='_blank'>How police unions became so powerful - and how they can be tamed</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-problem-with-police-unions-11591830984' target='_blank'>The problem with police unions</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.washingtonpost.com/history/2020/08/29/police-bill-of-rights-officers-discipline-maryland/' target='_blank'>There's a reason it's hard to discipline police, it starts with a bill of rights 47 years ago</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.motherjones.com/crime-justice/2020/08/police-unions-minneapolis/' target='_blank'>The infuriating history of why police unions have so much power</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2020/06/police-unions-reform-conservative-george-floyd-protest-black-lives-matter.html' target='_blank'>Why conservatives and liberals might join to fight back against police unions</a></p>
<p>• <a href='http://nycpba.org/news-items/daily-news/2020/police-unions-protect-us-all/' target='_blank'>Police unions protect us all</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.washingtonpost.com/outlook/2020/06/11/attacking-police-unions-will-hurt-whole-labor-movement/' target='_blank'>Attacking police unions will hurt the whole labor movement</a></p>
<p><u>Motion: Washington - Not Local Leaders - Should Set Law Enforcement Standards</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://wjla.com/news/nation-world/america-has-18000-police-agencies-no-national-standards-experts-say-thats-a-problem' target='_blank'>America has 18,000 police agencies, no national standards; experts say that's a problem</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://thehill.com/homenews/house/501412-top-progressive-lawmaker-unveils-bill-requiring-national-police-training/' target='_blank'>Top progressive lawmaker unveils bill requiring national police training standards</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.washingtonpost.com/outlook/2020/07/07/police-reform-wont-work-unless-it-involves-federal-state-governments/' target='_blank'>Police reform won't work unless it involves federal and state governments</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.vox.com/2020/6/16/21292816/trump-police-reform-executive-order-explained' target='_blank'>Trump's executive order on police reform, explained</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://sgp.fas.org/crs/misc/IF10572.pdf' target='_blank'>What role might the federal government play in law enforcement reform?</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://thehill.com/opinion/criminal-justice/507847-what-current-police-reform-efforts-lack-a-call-to-federalize/' target='_blank'>What current police reform efforts lack: A call to federalize</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.usatoday.com/story/opinion/policing/2020/05/29/prevent-another-death-police-train-and-adopt-national-standards-george-floyd/5282895002/' target='_blank'>Adopt minimum national police use of force standards and train cops for interaction</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.washingtonpost.com/posteverything/wp/2014/11/25/we-should-get-rid-of-local-policing-ferguson-shows-why-the-system-just-doesnt-work/' target='_blank'>We should get rid of local policing. Ferguson shows why the system just doesnt work</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://fedsoc.org/commentary/publications/federalism-in-law-enforcement' target='_blank'>Federalism in law enforcement</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/the-trump-administration-abandoned-obama-era-police-reform-efforts-now-critics-want-them-restored/2020/06/01/4615bc1c-a413-11ea-b473-04905b1af82b_story.html' target='_blank'>The Trump administration abandoned Obama-era police reformefforts. Now critics want them restored</a></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> September 30, 2020</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Law, Politics, U.S.</p>
<p>Historic protests calling for police reform have erupted across the nation. But just what could these reforms mean? And how should we see the criminal justice system today? Staged in our “Unresolved” format, this debate brings together five experts to tackle pressing questions on the history and future of policing in the U.S. including: Should we defund the police? Do police unions do more harm than good? And has policing become too militarized?
<div class="elfsight-app-eb31570a-6392-470a-93d1-f46144da2771"></div></p>
<p><strong>Unresolved Questions:</strong></p>
<p>• Motion: We Should Defund the Police</p>
<p>• Motion: The Police Have Become Too Militarized</p>
<p>• Motion: Police Unions Do More Harm Than Good</p>
<p>• Motion: Washington - Not Local Leaders - Should Set Law Enforcement Standards</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://www.youtube.com/embed/rbBPR2pOWWE' target='_blank'>https://www.youtube.com/embed/rbBPR2pOWWE</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Paul Butler</strong><br><span class="TextRun BCX0 SCXO159012287" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun BCX0 SCXO159012287">Paul Butler is the Albert Brick Professor in Law at Georgetown University Law Center and a legal analyst on MSNBC. Previously, Butler served as a federal prosecutor with the U.S. Department of Justice, where his specialty was public corruption. His prosecutions included a United States Senator, three FBI agents, and several other law enforcement officials. He lectures regularly for the American Bar Association and the NAACP, and at colleges, law schools, and community organizations throughout the US. He also serves on the District of Columbia Code Revision Commission as an appointee of the D.C. City Council and was elected to the American Law Institute in 2003. He was also the Bennett Boskey Visiting Professor at Harvard Law School during the 2017-2018 school year. Butler is the author of “Let’s Get Free: A Hip-Hop Theory of Justice”, which received the Harry Chapin Media award, and “Chokehold: Policing Black Men”, which was named one of the best non-fiction books of 2017 by major news outlets and a finalist for the 2018 NAACP Image Award for best non-fiction. He holds an honorary Doctor of Law Degree from the City University of New York and is a graduate of Yale University and Harvard Law School.</span></span></p>
<p><strong>Jason Johnson</strong><br>Jason Johnson is president of the Law Enforcement Legal Defense Fund, a national police advocacy organization. Johnson served as deputy commissioner of the Baltimore Police Department between 2016 and 2018.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rafael Mangual</strong><br>Rafael Mangual is a senior fellow and deputy director of legal policy at the Manhattan Institute and a contributing editor of the City Journal. An expert on urban crime, policing, and incarceration, he was recently appointed to serve a four-year term as a member of the New York State Advisory Committee of the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights.</p>
<p><strong>Sue Rahr</strong><br>Sue Rahr is executive director of the Washington State Criminal Justice Training Commission, overseeing the training of all city and county law enforcement and corrections officers in the state. Rahr served on President Obama’s Task Force on 21st Century Policing. She was King County Sheriff between 2005 and 2012.</p>
<p><strong>Vikrant Reddy</strong><br>Vikrant Reddy is a senior fellow at the Charles Koch Institute, specializing in the area of criminal justice reform. Reddy previously served as a senior policy analyst at the Texas Public Policy Foundation and is also an appointee to the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights Texas State Advisory Committee.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Short Circuit: A Roundup of Recent Federal Court Decisions</strong> <small>2023-02-07 20:40:25</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Wanted posters, vague and threatening letters, and dragging a 75-pound dummy.</p>
<p>Please enjoy the latest edition of Short Circuit (http://ij.org/about-us/shortcircuit/), a weekly feature written by a bunch of people at the Institute for Justice.</p>
<p>Last summer Alexandria, La. police pulled over Mario Rosales for failing to use his turn signal and detained him for 20 minutes, probing for evidence of other, more serious lawbreaking, cutting him loose when they didn't find any. But wait! The officers' dashcam shows that Mario did signal. Those sneaky dogs! Click here (https://ij.org/case/louisiana-traffic-stop/) to learn more about IJ's latest case, a challenge to pretextual, picayune harassment that passes for police work.</p>
<p>Over at Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S., IJ Attorney Anya Bidwell debates the Heritage Foundation's John Malcom on the merits of qualified immunity, explaining why it is really and truly okay if officers who make good-faith mistakes in life-and-death situations are not shielded from suit. With an appearance by The New York Times's Adam Liptak.</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Unresolved: American Policing</em></p>
<p><u>Motion: We Should Defund the Police</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.vox.com/2020/6/26/21303849/what-defund-the-police-really-means' target='_blank'>What "defund the police" really means</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.usatoday.com/story/money/2020/06/26/how-much-money-goes-to-police-departments-in-americas-largest-cities/112004904/' target='_blank'>Here's how much money goes to police departments in largest cities across the U.S.</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.cnn.com/2020/06/06/us/what-is-defund-police-trnd/index.html' target='_blank'>There's a growing call to defund the police. Here's what it means</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.bbc.com/news/election-us-2020-53997196' target='_blank'>US 2020 Election: Does Joe Biden support defunding the police?</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/defund-the-police' target='_blank'>We should still defund the police</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.usatoday.com/story/opinion/voices/2020/06/11/defunding-police-could-backfire-black-former-detective-column/5331008002/' target='_blank'>Black ex-cop: I understand the anger but don't defund police. It could make things worse</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.themarshallproject.org/2020/06/09/support-for-defunding-the-police-department-is-growing-here-s-why-it-s-not-a-silver-bullet' target='_blank'>Support for defunding the police department is growing. Here's why it's not a silver bullet</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://thehill.com/opinion/criminal-justice/501901-defund-the-police-is-not-a-serious-or-a-safe-solution/' target='_blank'>Defund the police is not a serious or a safe solution</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.bostonherald.com/2020/07/10/seattle-experiment-shows-that-we-need-police/' target='_blank'>Seattle experiment shows that we need police</a></p>
<p><u>Motion: The Police Have Become Too Militarized</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.wsj.com/articles/SB10001424127887323848804578608040780519904' target='_blank'>Rise of the warrior cop</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.marketplace.org/2020/06/12/police-departments-1033-military-equipment-weapons/' target='_blank'>How police departments got billions of dollars of tactical military equipment</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/01/us/politics/police-military-gear.html' target='_blank'>Lawmakers begin bipartisan push to cut off police access to military-style gear</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.latimes.com/politics/la-na-pol-military-gear-20170828-story.html' target='_blank'>Trump is endin grestrictions that limit the military from giving surplus gear to police</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2020/06/overlooked-role-guns-police-reform-debate/613258/' target='_blank'>The overlooked rold of guns in the police-reform debate</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.wbur.org/hereandnow/2020/06/23/do-police-need-guns' target='_blank'>Do police need guns?</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/21/us/politics/senate-police-military-equipment.html' target='_blank'>Senate kills broad curbs on military gear for police, thwarting push to demilitarize</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://journalistsresource.org/politics-and-government/militarization-police-reduce-crime-research/' target='_blank'>The militarization of America's police may reduce crime: new study</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.usatoday.com/story/opinion/2017/08/31/police-need-military-equipment-combat-rising-crime-rates-and-police-deaths-alfred-regnery-column/613471001/' target='_blank'>Police need military equipment to combat rising crime rates and police deaths</a></p>
<p><u>Motion: Police Unions Do More Harm Than Good</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/06/us/police-unions-minneapolis-kroll.html' target='_blank'>How police unions became such powerful opponents to reform efforts</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://news.bloomberglaw.com/daily-labor-report/police-union-membership-rising-as-positions-sit-vacant' target='_blank'>Police union membership rising as positions sit vacant</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/politics-news/national-labor-groups-mostly-close-ranks-defend-police-unions-n1231573' target='_blank'>National Labor groups mostly close ranks to defend police unions</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/21290981/police-union-contracts-minneapolis-reform' target='_blank'>How police unions became so powerful - and how they can be tamed</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-problem-with-police-unions-11591830984' target='_blank'>The problem with police unions</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.washingtonpost.com/history/2020/08/29/police-bill-of-rights-officers-discipline-maryland/' target='_blank'>There's a reason it's hard to discipline police, it starts with a bill of rights 47 years ago</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.motherjones.com/crime-justice/2020/08/police-unions-minneapolis/' target='_blank'>The infuriating history of why police unions have so much power</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2020/06/police-unions-reform-conservative-george-floyd-protest-black-lives-matter.html' target='_blank'>Why conservatives and liberals might join to fight back against police unions</a></p>
<p>• <a href='http://nycpba.org/news-items/daily-news/2020/police-unions-protect-us-all/' target='_blank'>Police unions protect us all</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.washingtonpost.com/outlook/2020/06/11/attacking-police-unions-will-hurt-whole-labor-movement/' target='_blank'>Attacking police unions will hurt the whole labor movement</a></p>
<p><u>Motion: Washington - Not Local Leaders - Should Set Law Enforcement Standards</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://wjla.com/news/nation-world/america-has-18000-police-agencies-no-national-standards-experts-say-thats-a-problem' target='_blank'>America has 18,000 police agencies, no national standards; experts say that's a problem</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://thehill.com/homenews/house/501412-top-progressive-lawmaker-unveils-bill-requiring-national-police-training/' target='_blank'>Top progressive lawmaker unveils bill requiring national police training standards</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.washingtonpost.com/outlook/2020/07/07/police-reform-wont-work-unless-it-involves-federal-state-governments/' target='_blank'>Police reform won't work unless it involves federal and state governments</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.vox.com/2020/6/16/21292816/trump-police-reform-executive-order-explained' target='_blank'>Trump's executive order on police reform, explained</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://sgp.fas.org/crs/misc/IF10572.pdf' target='_blank'>What role might the federal government play in law enforcement reform?</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://thehill.com/opinion/criminal-justice/507847-what-current-police-reform-efforts-lack-a-call-to-federalize/' target='_blank'>What current police reform efforts lack: A call to federalize</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.usatoday.com/story/opinion/policing/2020/05/29/prevent-another-death-police-train-and-adopt-national-standards-george-floyd/5282895002/' target='_blank'>Adopt minimum national police use of force standards and train cops for interaction</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.washingtonpost.com/posteverything/wp/2014/11/25/we-should-get-rid-of-local-policing-ferguson-shows-why-the-system-just-doesnt-work/' target='_blank'>We should get rid of local policing. Ferguson shows why the system just doesnt work</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://fedsoc.org/commentary/publications/federalism-in-law-enforcement' target='_blank'>Federalism in law enforcement</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/the-trump-administration-abandoned-obama-era-police-reform-efforts-now-critics-want-them-restored/2020/06/01/4615bc1c-a413-11ea-b473-04905b1af82b_story.html' target='_blank'>The Trump administration abandoned Obama-era police reformefforts. Now critics want them restored</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Is it Time to Redistribute the Wealth?</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/its-time-redistribute-wealth</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10224</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> September 24, 2020</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Finance, Politics</p>
<p>Economic inequality has become a linchpin of modern politics. As nations around the world face a reckoning on racial and social justice and work to combat the economic impacts of the pandemic, we ask: Is it time to redistribute the wealth? Should we address growing inequality by overhauling our tax system, expanding our social safety nets, and investing more in public initiatives like universal health care, education, and infrastructure? Or would a wealth transfer unduly punish the economic elite, destroy the promise of a meritocracy, and inevitably lead to excessive government intervention in our social and economic lives?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://www.youtube.com/embed/UpGwfuErpeo' target='_blank'>https://www.youtube.com/embed/UpGwfuErpeo</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Robert Reich</strong><br>Robert Reich is a professor of public policy at the University of California at Berkeley and a senior fellow at the Blum Center. A former secretary of labor in the Clinton administration and cofounder of Inequality Media, he is also the author of 18 books, including his latest, "The System: Who Rigged It, How to Fix It."</p>
<p><strong>Yanis Varoufakis</strong><br>Yanis Varoufakis, a former finance minister of Greece, is secretary-general of the MeRA25 party and professor of economics at the University of Athens. He is the author of many books, including "Another Now: Dispatches from an Alternative Past," which considers how to create a more fair and equal society.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Allison Schrager</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0">Allison Schrager is an American economist, author, and senior fellow at the Manhattan Institute, where she studies tax and monetary policy. Schrager is a regular contributor to The Economist, Reuters, and Bloomberg Businessweek, and her work has been published in </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0">Wired</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0">, </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0">National Review, Playboy</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0">, and </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0">Foreign Affairs</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0">. She is also the author of “An Economist Walks into a Brothel.” In addition to her writing, she has consulted for organizations such as the Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development and the International Monetary Fund and is co-founder of a risk advisory firm, </span><span class="SpellingError SCXO90971512 BCX0">LifeCycle</span><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0"> Finance Partners, LLC. She holds a Ph.D. in economics from Columbia University.</span></span></p>
<p><strong>Lawrence Summers</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO9503502 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO9503502 BCX0">Lawrence Summers has held several senior policy positions, including Secretary of the Treasury under the Clinton administration and the Director of the National Economic Council for the Obama administration. He has also served as vice president of development economics and chief economist of the World Bank. Summers is a </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO9503502 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO9503502 BCX0">Charles W. Eliot University P</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO9503502 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO9503502 BCX0">rofessor and the president emeritus of Harvard University.</span></span></p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Is it Time To Redistribute The Wealth?</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Coronavirus</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Inequality Vs. Opportunity</u></p>
<p><u>Wealth Tax</u></p>
<p><u>Billionaire</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> September 24, 2020</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Finance, Politics</p>
<p>Economic inequality has become a linchpin of modern politics. As nations around the world face a reckoning on racial and social justice and work to combat the economic impacts of the pandemic, we ask: Is it time to redistribute the wealth? Should we address growing inequality by overhauling our tax system, expanding our social safety nets, and investing more in public initiatives like universal health care, education, and infrastructure? Or would a wealth transfer unduly punish the economic elite, destroy the promise of a meritocracy, and inevitably lead to excessive government intervention in our social and economic lives?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://www.youtube.com/embed/UpGwfuErpeo' target='_blank'>https://www.youtube.com/embed/UpGwfuErpeo</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Robert Reich</strong><br>Robert Reich is a professor of public policy at the University of California at Berkeley and a senior fellow at the Blum Center. A former secretary of labor in the Clinton administration and cofounder of Inequality Media, he is also the author of 18 books, including his latest, "The System: Who Rigged It, How to Fix It."</p>
<p><strong>Yanis Varoufakis</strong><br>Yanis Varoufakis, a former finance minister of Greece, is secretary-general of the MeRA25 party and professor of economics at the University of Athens. He is the author of many books, including "Another Now: Dispatches from an Alternative Past," which considers how to create a more fair and equal society.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Allison Schrager</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0">Allison Schrager is an American economist, author, and senior fellow at the Manhattan Institute, where she studies tax and monetary policy. Schrager is a regular contributor to The Economist, Reuters, and Bloomberg Businessweek, and her work has been published in </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0">Wired</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0">, </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0">National Review, Playboy</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0">, and </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0">Foreign Affairs</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0">. She is also the author of “An Economist Walks into a Brothel.” In addition to her writing, she has consulted for organizations such as the Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development and the International Monetary Fund and is co-founder of a risk advisory firm, </span><span class="SpellingError SCXO90971512 BCX0">LifeCycle</span><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO90971512 BCX0"> Finance Partners, LLC. She holds a Ph.D. in economics from Columbia University.</span></span></p>
<p><strong>Lawrence Summers</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO9503502 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO9503502 BCX0">Lawrence Summers has held several senior policy positions, including Secretary of the Treasury under the Clinton administration and the Director of the National Economic Council for the Obama administration. He has also served as vice president of development economics and chief economist of the World Bank. Summers is a </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO9503502 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO9503502 BCX0">Charles W. Eliot University P</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO9503502 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO9503502 BCX0">rofessor and the president emeritus of Harvard University.</span></span></p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Is it Time To Redistribute The Wealth?</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Coronavirus</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Inequality Vs. Opportunity</u></p>
<p><u>Wealth Tax</u></p>
<p><u>Billionaire</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Agree to Disagree: Should Washington Break Up Big Tech?</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/agree-disagree-should-washington-break-big-tech</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:9978</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> August 07, 2020</p>
<p>After a 13-month investigation that yielded millions of documents and hundreds of hours of interviews, Congress called the chief executives from Amazon, Apple, Facebook, and Google to testify. And they did. In the historic hearing, the tech titans defended their companies against claims that they’re running afoul of antitrust law and using their market power to crush competition, amass data, and drive their own profits. As the internet giants face more probes from the FCC, DOJ, and a host of state attorneys general, some are calling this big tech’s “big tobacco moment.” But are these companies really too large? In this episode of “Agree to Disagree,” we bring two experts in antitrust and digital technologies to discuss whether Washington should break up big tech.
<p class="rtecenter"><iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/24hwcBwba09ErXaw9eiLCv?utm_source=generator" width="100%" height="232" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe><iframe style="width: 100%; max-width: 660px; overflow: hidden; background: transparent;" src="https://embed.podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/agree-to-disagree-should-washington-break-up-big-tech/id216713308?i=1000487398588" height="175" frameborder="0" sandbox="allow-forms allow-popups allow-same-origin allow-scripts allow-storage-access-by-user-activation allow-top-navigation-by-user-activation"></iframe></p></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Zephyr Teachout</strong><br>Zephyr Teachout is an associate law professor at Fordham Law School. She writes about political law, with a focus on corruption; her book "Corruption in America" (Harvard University Press) is coming out in fall 2014. She is also known for her innovative work as director of online organizing for Howard Dean's 2004 presidential campaign, where she led the first technical team developing social media tools for supporters, many of which were used in Obama's 2008 online campaign. As the first national director of the Sunlight Foundation, she led several crowd-sourced investigative journalism projects, including a national campaign to expose the political connections behind earmarks. She was also a fellow at the New America Foundation's Markets, Enterprise, and Resiliency Initiative, where she worked on developing frameworks to understand the role of monopolistic companies in the American political ecosystem.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Andrew McAfee</strong><br>Andrew McAfee is the co-director of the IDE and a principal research scientist at the MIT Sloan School of Management. His research investigates how information technology changes the way companies perform, organize themselves, and compete. At a higher level, his work also focuses on how computerization affects competition, society, the economy, and the workforce. In addition to having numerous papers published, McAfee also writes a widely read blog, which is at times one of the 10,000 most popular in the world. He is the author or co-author of more than 100 articles, case studies, and other materials for students and teachers of technology. Prior to joining MIT Sloan, McAfee was a professor at Harvard Business School. He has also served as a fellow at the Berkman Center for Internet and Society at Harvard Law School. McAfee received his doctorate from Harvard Business School and completed two Master of Science and two Bachelor of Science degrees at MIT. He speaks frequently to both academic and industry audiences and has taught in executive education programs around the world.</p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> August 07, 2020</p>
<p>After a 13-month investigation that yielded millions of documents and hundreds of hours of interviews, Congress called the chief executives from Amazon, Apple, Facebook, and Google to testify. And they did. In the historic hearing, the tech titans defended their companies against claims that they’re running afoul of antitrust law and using their market power to crush competition, amass data, and drive their own profits. As the internet giants face more probes from the FCC, DOJ, and a host of state attorneys general, some are calling this big tech’s “big tobacco moment.” But are these companies really too large? In this episode of “Agree to Disagree,” we bring two experts in antitrust and digital technologies to discuss whether Washington should break up big tech.
<p class="rtecenter"><iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/24hwcBwba09ErXaw9eiLCv?utm_source=generator" width="100%" height="232" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe><iframe style="width: 100%; max-width: 660px; overflow: hidden; background: transparent;" src="https://embed.podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/agree-to-disagree-should-washington-break-up-big-tech/id216713308?i=1000487398588" height="175" frameborder="0" sandbox="allow-forms allow-popups allow-same-origin allow-scripts allow-storage-access-by-user-activation allow-top-navigation-by-user-activation"></iframe></p></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Zephyr Teachout</strong><br>Zephyr Teachout is an associate law professor at Fordham Law School. She writes about political law, with a focus on corruption; her book "Corruption in America" (Harvard University Press) is coming out in fall 2014. She is also known for her innovative work as director of online organizing for Howard Dean's 2004 presidential campaign, where she led the first technical team developing social media tools for supporters, many of which were used in Obama's 2008 online campaign. As the first national director of the Sunlight Foundation, she led several crowd-sourced investigative journalism projects, including a national campaign to expose the political connections behind earmarks. She was also a fellow at the New America Foundation's Markets, Enterprise, and Resiliency Initiative, where she worked on developing frameworks to understand the role of monopolistic companies in the American political ecosystem.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Andrew McAfee</strong><br>Andrew McAfee is the co-director of the IDE and a principal research scientist at the MIT Sloan School of Management. His research investigates how information technology changes the way companies perform, organize themselves, and compete. At a higher level, his work also focuses on how computerization affects competition, society, the economy, and the workforce. In addition to having numerous papers published, McAfee also writes a widely read blog, which is at times one of the 10,000 most popular in the world. He is the author or co-author of more than 100 articles, case studies, and other materials for students and teachers of technology. Prior to joining MIT Sloan, McAfee was a professor at Harvard Business School. He has also served as a fellow at the Berkman Center for Internet and Society at Harvard Law School. McAfee received his doctorate from Harvard Business School and completed two Master of Science and two Bachelor of Science degrees at MIT. He speaks frequently to both academic and industry audiences and has taught in executive education programs around the world.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Agree to Disagree: Broadband for All?</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/agree-disagree-broadband-all</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:9960</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> July 25, 2020</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Tech, U.S.</p>
<p>From virtual classes to digital happy hours with friends, the pandemic is transforming the way we live, work, and study. But as Americans become increasingly reliant on the internet, we ask: Just who should ensure you have the connection you need? And how might communities go about bridging the increasingly talked-about digital divide? In this episode of our new series "Agree to Disagree," we bring two of the nation's leading communications law experts together to discuss what broadband looks like in the United States, if the internet should be treated as a public utility, and whether government or the free market is better suited to keep us connected.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/CCmPtnUB-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/CCmPtnUB-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Gigi Sohn</strong><br>Gigi Sohn is a leading public advocate for open, affordable, and democratic communications networks. She served as counselor to former Federal Communications Commission Chairman Tom Wheeler and, before that, was the CEO of Public Knowledge, a leading telecommunications, media, and technology policy advocacy organization. Sohn is now a distinguished fellow at the Georgetown Law Institute for Technology Law and Policy.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Christopher Yoo</strong><br>Christopher Yoo is one of the nation's top authorities on law and technology. His research focuses on exploring how the principles of network engineering and the economics of imperfect competition can provide insights into the regulation of the internet and other forms of electronic communications. Yoo has been a leading voice in the "network neutrality" debate and is a professor at the University of Pennsylvania Law School.</p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> July 25, 2020</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Tech, U.S.</p>
<p>From virtual classes to digital happy hours with friends, the pandemic is transforming the way we live, work, and study. But as Americans become increasingly reliant on the internet, we ask: Just who should ensure you have the connection you need? And how might communities go about bridging the increasingly talked-about digital divide? In this episode of our new series "Agree to Disagree," we bring two of the nation's leading communications law experts together to discuss what broadband looks like in the United States, if the internet should be treated as a public utility, and whether government or the free market is better suited to keep us connected.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/CCmPtnUB-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/CCmPtnUB-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Gigi Sohn</strong><br>Gigi Sohn is a leading public advocate for open, affordable, and democratic communications networks. She served as counselor to former Federal Communications Commission Chairman Tom Wheeler and, before that, was the CEO of Public Knowledge, a leading telecommunications, media, and technology policy advocacy organization. Sohn is now a distinguished fellow at the Georgetown Law Institute for Technology Law and Policy.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Christopher Yoo</strong><br>Christopher Yoo is one of the nation's top authorities on law and technology. His research focuses on exploring how the principles of network engineering and the economics of imperfect competition can provide insights into the regulation of the internet and other forms of electronic communications. Yoo has been a leading voice in the "network neutrality" debate and is a professor at the University of Pennsylvania Law School.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Is Nationalism a Force for Good?</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/nationalism-force-good</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10304</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> June 26, 2020</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Politics, U.S., World</p>
<p>From Brexit to “America First,” Modi in India, Erdoğan in Turkey, and Bolsonaro in Brazil, nationalism – or allegiance to a nation-state over other group affiliations – has been on the rise. Now, borders around the world are closed and the coronavirus pandemic is sparking staunch debate about the future of global governance and political identity. The nation-state has been praised for securing the needs of its citizens and serving as the most efficient form of political organization, while also criticized for being insular and inciting anti-immigration policies. Nationalism has been credited for both uniting disparate communities under a common culture and identity, as well as promoting violence based on race and ethnicity. As global problems continue to mount, does the 21st century require international leadership, or is nationalism a force for good?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://www.youtube.com/embed/LYra0iKYTtg' target='_blank'>https://www.youtube.com/embed/LYra0iKYTtg</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Colin Dueck</strong><br>Colin Dueck is a professor of policy and government at George Mason University and a visiting scholar at the American Enterprise Institute. His latest book is “Age of Iron: On Conservative Nationalism.” Dueck has consulted for the Department of State, the Department of Defense, and the National Security Council.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://schar.gmu.edu/about/faculty-directory/colin-dueck">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Andrew Keen</strong><br>Named one of the "100 most connected men" by GQ magazine, Andrew Keen is one of the world’s best-known broadcasters and commentators on democracy. He is the host of, "How to Fix Democracy", the long-running internet show that includes Margaret Atwood and Madeleine Albright among its many illustrious guests. In 2023 and 2024, the show will focus on the 100-year history of American democracy between 1924 and 2024. Andrew wrote and produced the 2020, "How to Fix Democracy", movie, a documentary about democracy shot in Greece, Germany, the United Kingdom, and the United States. He also presents, "Keen on Democracy", a popular podcast show that gets several million downloads and views a year. He is the author of four acclaimed books on the relationship between technology and democracy, including the best-selling "Cult of the Amateur" and "The Internet Is Not the Answer." Andrew studied contemporary history and politics at the Universities of London and Berkeley. He is currently working on a book about democracy in America.</p>
<p><strong>Elif Shafak</strong><br>Elif Shafak is a novelist and the most widely read female author in Turkey. Her latest novel, "10 Minutes, 38 Seconds in this Strange World," was shortlisted for the Booker Prize. In 2006, Shafak was prosecuted for "insulting Turkishness." She writes about global politics, populism, and nationalism.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.elifsafak.com.tr/biography/">here</a></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> June 26, 2020</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Politics, U.S., World</p>
<p>From Brexit to “America First,” Modi in India, Erdoğan in Turkey, and Bolsonaro in Brazil, nationalism – or allegiance to a nation-state over other group affiliations – has been on the rise. Now, borders around the world are closed and the coronavirus pandemic is sparking staunch debate about the future of global governance and political identity. The nation-state has been praised for securing the needs of its citizens and serving as the most efficient form of political organization, while also criticized for being insular and inciting anti-immigration policies. Nationalism has been credited for both uniting disparate communities under a common culture and identity, as well as promoting violence based on race and ethnicity. As global problems continue to mount, does the 21st century require international leadership, or is nationalism a force for good?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://www.youtube.com/embed/LYra0iKYTtg' target='_blank'>https://www.youtube.com/embed/LYra0iKYTtg</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Colin Dueck</strong><br>Colin Dueck is a professor of policy and government at George Mason University and a visiting scholar at the American Enterprise Institute. His latest book is “Age of Iron: On Conservative Nationalism.” Dueck has consulted for the Department of State, the Department of Defense, and the National Security Council.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://schar.gmu.edu/about/faculty-directory/colin-dueck">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Andrew Keen</strong><br>Named one of the "100 most connected men" by GQ magazine, Andrew Keen is one of the world’s best-known broadcasters and commentators on democracy. He is the host of, "How to Fix Democracy", the long-running internet show that includes Margaret Atwood and Madeleine Albright among its many illustrious guests. In 2023 and 2024, the show will focus on the 100-year history of American democracy between 1924 and 2024. Andrew wrote and produced the 2020, "How to Fix Democracy", movie, a documentary about democracy shot in Greece, Germany, the United Kingdom, and the United States. He also presents, "Keen on Democracy", a popular podcast show that gets several million downloads and views a year. He is the author of four acclaimed books on the relationship between technology and democracy, including the best-selling "Cult of the Amateur" and "The Internet Is Not the Answer." Andrew studied contemporary history and politics at the Universities of London and Berkeley. He is currently working on a book about democracy in America.</p>
<p><strong>Elif Shafak</strong><br>Elif Shafak is a novelist and the most widely read female author in Turkey. Her latest novel, "10 Minutes, 38 Seconds in this Strange World," was shortlisted for the Booker Prize. In 2006, Shafak was prosecuted for "insulting Turkishness." She writes about global politics, populism, and nationalism.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.elifsafak.com.tr/biography/">here</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Coronavirus Will Reshape the World Order in China&#x27;s Favor</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/coronavirus-will-reshape-world-order-chinas-favor</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10069</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> June 03, 2020</p>
<p>How might coronavirus reshape geopolitics? For some, the answer is clear: China is on the rise. While Washington embraces “America First” and abdicates its global leadership role, they argue, Beijing is stepping up to fill the void. By providing material assistance to struggling nations, organizing world leaders, and trumpeting its own virus response, China is vying for power and influence. But others see a global future where Beijing’s standing is diminished, not bolstered. They argue the Chinese Communist Party’s mismanagement and lack of transparency around the virus will spark lasting mistrust and condemnation from friends and foes alike. Meanwhile, they say, an economic slowdown coupled with domestic unrest around lockdown policies will challenge Xi Jinping’s authority at home and abroad.
<script src="https://apps.elfsight.com/p/platform.js" defer></script>
<div class="elfsight-app-be402d07-7512-40ae-880b-18f52c50573a"></div></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://www.youtube.com/embed/DRdyg1CttUk' target='_blank'>https://www.youtube.com/embed/DRdyg1CttUk</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Kurt M. Campbell</strong><br>Kurt M. Campbell is the CEO of The Asia Group and the former Assistant Secretary of State for East Asian and Pacific Affairs. Widely credited as an architect of the Obama administration’s “pivot to Asia,” Campbell is the co-founder of the Center for a New American Security and former director of the Aspen Strategy Group.</p>
<p><strong>Kishore Mahbubani</strong><br>Kishore Mahbubani is an academic and former Singaporean diplomat. He previously served as president of the United Nations Security Council and is a distinguished fellow at the National University of Singapore's Asia Research Institute. His latest book, released in March, is titled "Has China Won? The Chinese Challenge to American Primacy."
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://mahbubani.net/">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Minxin Pei</strong><br>Minxin Pei is an expert on U.S.-Asia relations and the author of “China’s Crony Capitalism: The Dynamics of Regime Delay.” He is currently a professor of government at Claremont McKenna College and a senior fellow at the German Marshall Fund.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.gmfus.org/profiles/minxin-pei">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Susan Thornton</strong><br>Susan A. Thornton is a retired senior U.S. diplomat with almost three decades of experience with the U.S. State Department in Eurasia and East Asia. She is currently a Visiting Lecturer in Law and Senior Fellow at the Yale Law School Paul Tsai China Center. She is also the director of the Forum on Asia-Pacific Security at the National Committee on American Foreign Policy and a nonresident senior fellow at the Brookings Institution.
Until July 2018, Thornton was Acting Assistant Secretary for East Asian and Pacific Affairs at the Department of State and led East Asia policymaking amid crises with North Korea, escalating trade tensions with China, and a fast-changing international environment. In previous State Department roles, she worked on U.S. policy toward China, Korea and the former Soviet Union and served in leadership positions at U.S. embassies in Central Asia, Russia, the Caucasus and China.
Thornton received her M.A. in International Relations from the Johns Hopkins University School of Advanced International Studies and her B.A. from Bowdoin College in Economics and Russian. She serves on several nonprofit boards and speaks Mandarin and Russian.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>COUNTDOWN TO WAR China ‘learning from Putin’s Ukraine disaster’ as regime prepares for all-out Taiwan blitz to ‘cut island off from US’</strong> <small>2023-02-02 16:31:20</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>CHINA is preparing for an all-out blitz of Taiwan, a former US Department of Defence official has warned.</p>
<p>Michael Beckley said Xi Jinping (https://www.the-sun.com/who/xi-jinping/) will have learned from Putin's (https://www.the-sun.com/who/vladimir-putin/) disastrous mistakes in Ukraine (https://www.the-sun.com/where/ukraine/) and will aim to "hit Taiwan (https://www.the-sun.com/where/taiwan/) hard from the start" and "sever them from the outside world".</p>
<p>On Tuesday, NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg also said China is "learning lessons" from Putin's invasion and warned: "What is happening in Europe today could happen in East Asia tomorrow."</p>
<p>China regards the self-governing island as part of its territory and has vowed to reunite it with the mainland (https://www.the-sun.com/news/6628504/xi-orders-china-prepare-for-war/) - by force if necessary.</p>
<p>Tensions between the two nations have hit boiling point (https://www.the-sun.com/news/6506796/china-us-worst-war-in-modern-history/) in recent months, with Beijing continuing to flex its military muscles (https://www.the-sun.com/news/5573864/chinas-live-fire-drills-taiwan-drones/) by launching jets into Taiwan's airspace (https://www.the-sun.com/news/5943706/taiwan-fighter-jets-china-invasion/) and firing missiles in haunting drills (https://www.the-sun.com/news/5958186/china-military-drills-taiwan/).</p>
<p>In November last year, the Chinese dictator ordered his troops to prepare for war (https://www.the-sun.com/news/6628504/xi-orders-china-prepare-for-war/) - and some are predicting Beijing is "all but guaranteed" to attack Taiwan (https://www.the-sun.com/news/5946480/four-ways-china-take-taiwan-lightning-invasion/).</p>
<p>In a chilling warning, Michael, who advises US intelligence agencies, said China's aggressive show of force is "not just for fun and games".</p>
<p>Speaking on the Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. podcast, the Associate Professor of Political Science at Tufts University said: "It's easy to say there won't be a war when we're sitting in New York. "If we were in Taipei, I would be a lot more nervous. "Peaceful unification options are disappearing very quickly for Beijing. Most Chinese scholars say Chinese leaders have been determined to snuff out Taiwan one way or another." We do have to be concerned that what China has been doing with the largest and most aggressive show of force is not just for fun and games. "This is actual preparation for a conflict... I don't think it's super likely, but I worry we're too dismissive. These are nationalists who see it as making China whole again. "Xi Jinping has said the Taiwan issue cannot be passed down generation to generation. "A failed Chinese invasion of Taiwan will still kill a lot of people. "Can they win overall? Probably not. But can they deal the US a devastating blow from the outset? Yes."</p>
<p>Michael said it's possible Xi "might have commanders telling him it will be easy" to invade Taiwan. The defence expert said the Chinese army will have learned lessons from Putin's shambolic war in Ukraine. And like Putin, Michael said he "would expect Xi Jinping to rattle the nuclear sabre". "You just have to worry if pull comes to shove, Xi Jinping might just pull the trigger," he said. "With a dictator, you never know... there are factors that could bring this to a head very quickly. "It might not be a full-scale invasion - it might be economic meddling, political coercion."</p>
<p>"What China has been doing with the largest and most aggressive show of force is not just for fun and games"</p>
<p>– Michael BeckleyFormer US Department Of Defence Official</p>
<p>Taiwan is feared to be a major flashpoint between the Washington and Beijing (https://www.the-sun.com/news/3949232/us-secretly-training-taiwan-spy-missions-china/)- with a potential invasion forcing the US to either abandon the island or face full scale war with China (https://www.the-sun.com/news/5319135/china-invade-taiwan-new-aircraft-carrier/).</p>
<p>On Sunday, Republican Mike McCaul said the odds of conflict with China over Taiwan are "very high". He said if China failed to take control of Taiwan bloodlessly then "they are going to look at a military invasion in my judgement". It came after General Mike Minihan, head of the US Air Mobility Command, wrote in a memo: "My gut tells me we will fight in 2025."</p>
<p>Michael said the US and Taiwan have been slow to respond to China's vast military expansion. "They are coming off a decade of really ramping up their military capabilities - and the US and Taiwan have been slow to respond," he said. "As someone who works closely with the US government, I would like to have seen faster responses from Taiwan and Japan."</p>
<p>President and founder of Eurasia Group, Ian Bremmer, said a war with Taiwan is "not very likely to happen in the next few years". But the author didn't rule out the scenario.</p>
<p>"China is going to be checked militarily by many countries in the region, and the US," Ian said. "The Chinese is aware of that, and they don't want to get in a direct fight militarily. "The Chinese aren't being stupid about trying to engage in a military confrontation with the US and their allies."</p>
<p>"Putin is a leader making massive misjudgements on the global stage - I don't see Xi doing that"</p>
<p>– Ian BremmerEurasia Group</p>
<p>He added: "Their ability to get Taiwanese business people to change their orientation politically or else they will be cut down is a lever the Chinese have. "Putin is a leader making massive misjudgements on the global stage - I don't see Xi doing that. "I don't see the Chinese government itching for a global fight - with the exception of the reunification of Taiwan." While Beijing may be preparing for a lightning war (https://www.the-sun.com/news/5946480/four-ways-china-take-taiwan-lightning-invasion/) to storm across the Taiwan Strait and capture the island, experts have said the war could be anything but quick. With tough beaches, rocky terrain, well-drilled defenders, and unforgiving seas, China could face the same brutal grinding warfare that Russia is facing in Ukraine. Taking Taiwan could even require Beijing to muster a force of two million troops (https://www.the-sun.com/news/5947970/china-two-million-soldiers-taiwan-russia/), it's been claimed.</p>
<p>Last year, new photos revealed for the first time (https://www.the-sun.com/news/6583901/heavy-military-operations-south-china-sea/) just how far China's militarisation has escalated in the South China Sea.</p>
<p>Chilling images showed the massive sprawl of Chinese military operations on the man-made islands - which are armed to the teeth with deadly hardware including missile aircraft, flight hangars, and spy planes. The largest of the islands in the archipelago, Taiping Island, is currently controlled by Taiwan - which is at the centre of invasion plans being drawn up by Beijing.</p>
<p>The full debate between Michael Beckley and Ian Bremmer will be released on theIntelligence Squared US (https://opentodebate.org/) podcast on February 17.</p></div>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> June 03, 2020</p>
<p>How might coronavirus reshape geopolitics? For some, the answer is clear: China is on the rise. While Washington embraces “America First” and abdicates its global leadership role, they argue, Beijing is stepping up to fill the void. By providing material assistance to struggling nations, organizing world leaders, and trumpeting its own virus response, China is vying for power and influence. But others see a global future where Beijing’s standing is diminished, not bolstered. They argue the Chinese Communist Party’s mismanagement and lack of transparency around the virus will spark lasting mistrust and condemnation from friends and foes alike. Meanwhile, they say, an economic slowdown coupled with domestic unrest around lockdown policies will challenge Xi Jinping’s authority at home and abroad.
<script src="https://apps.elfsight.com/p/platform.js" defer></script>
<div class="elfsight-app-be402d07-7512-40ae-880b-18f52c50573a"></div></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://www.youtube.com/embed/DRdyg1CttUk' target='_blank'>https://www.youtube.com/embed/DRdyg1CttUk</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Kurt M. Campbell</strong><br>Kurt M. Campbell is the CEO of The Asia Group and the former Assistant Secretary of State for East Asian and Pacific Affairs. Widely credited as an architect of the Obama administration’s “pivot to Asia,” Campbell is the co-founder of the Center for a New American Security and former director of the Aspen Strategy Group.</p>
<p><strong>Kishore Mahbubani</strong><br>Kishore Mahbubani is an academic and former Singaporean diplomat. He previously served as president of the United Nations Security Council and is a distinguished fellow at the National University of Singapore's Asia Research Institute. His latest book, released in March, is titled "Has China Won? The Chinese Challenge to American Primacy."
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://mahbubani.net/">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Minxin Pei</strong><br>Minxin Pei is an expert on U.S.-Asia relations and the author of “China’s Crony Capitalism: The Dynamics of Regime Delay.” He is currently a professor of government at Claremont McKenna College and a senior fellow at the German Marshall Fund.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.gmfus.org/profiles/minxin-pei">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Susan Thornton</strong><br>Susan A. Thornton is a retired senior U.S. diplomat with almost three decades of experience with the U.S. State Department in Eurasia and East Asia. She is currently a Visiting Lecturer in Law and Senior Fellow at the Yale Law School Paul Tsai China Center. She is also the director of the Forum on Asia-Pacific Security at the National Committee on American Foreign Policy and a nonresident senior fellow at the Brookings Institution.
Until July 2018, Thornton was Acting Assistant Secretary for East Asian and Pacific Affairs at the Department of State and led East Asia policymaking amid crises with North Korea, escalating trade tensions with China, and a fast-changing international environment. In previous State Department roles, she worked on U.S. policy toward China, Korea and the former Soviet Union and served in leadership positions at U.S. embassies in Central Asia, Russia, the Caucasus and China.
Thornton received her M.A. in International Relations from the Johns Hopkins University School of Advanced International Studies and her B.A. from Bowdoin College in Economics and Russian. She serves on several nonprofit boards and speaks Mandarin and Russian.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>COUNTDOWN TO WAR China ‘learning from Putin’s Ukraine disaster’ as regime prepares for all-out Taiwan blitz to ‘cut island off from US’</strong> <small>2023-02-02 16:31:20</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>CHINA is preparing for an all-out blitz of Taiwan, a former US Department of Defence official has warned.</p>
<p>Michael Beckley said Xi Jinping (https://www.the-sun.com/who/xi-jinping/) will have learned from Putin's (https://www.the-sun.com/who/vladimir-putin/) disastrous mistakes in Ukraine (https://www.the-sun.com/where/ukraine/) and will aim to "hit Taiwan (https://www.the-sun.com/where/taiwan/) hard from the start" and "sever them from the outside world".</p>
<p>On Tuesday, NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg also said China is "learning lessons" from Putin's invasion and warned: "What is happening in Europe today could happen in East Asia tomorrow."</p>
<p>China regards the self-governing island as part of its territory and has vowed to reunite it with the mainland (https://www.the-sun.com/news/6628504/xi-orders-china-prepare-for-war/) - by force if necessary.</p>
<p>Tensions between the two nations have hit boiling point (https://www.the-sun.com/news/6506796/china-us-worst-war-in-modern-history/) in recent months, with Beijing continuing to flex its military muscles (https://www.the-sun.com/news/5573864/chinas-live-fire-drills-taiwan-drones/) by launching jets into Taiwan's airspace (https://www.the-sun.com/news/5943706/taiwan-fighter-jets-china-invasion/) and firing missiles in haunting drills (https://www.the-sun.com/news/5958186/china-military-drills-taiwan/).</p>
<p>In November last year, the Chinese dictator ordered his troops to prepare for war (https://www.the-sun.com/news/6628504/xi-orders-china-prepare-for-war/) - and some are predicting Beijing is "all but guaranteed" to attack Taiwan (https://www.the-sun.com/news/5946480/four-ways-china-take-taiwan-lightning-invasion/).</p>
<p>In a chilling warning, Michael, who advises US intelligence agencies, said China's aggressive show of force is "not just for fun and games".</p>
<p>Speaking on the Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. podcast, the Associate Professor of Political Science at Tufts University said: "It's easy to say there won't be a war when we're sitting in New York. "If we were in Taipei, I would be a lot more nervous. "Peaceful unification options are disappearing very quickly for Beijing. Most Chinese scholars say Chinese leaders have been determined to snuff out Taiwan one way or another." We do have to be concerned that what China has been doing with the largest and most aggressive show of force is not just for fun and games. "This is actual preparation for a conflict... I don't think it's super likely, but I worry we're too dismissive. These are nationalists who see it as making China whole again. "Xi Jinping has said the Taiwan issue cannot be passed down generation to generation. "A failed Chinese invasion of Taiwan will still kill a lot of people. "Can they win overall? Probably not. But can they deal the US a devastating blow from the outset? Yes."</p>
<p>Michael said it's possible Xi "might have commanders telling him it will be easy" to invade Taiwan. The defence expert said the Chinese army will have learned lessons from Putin's shambolic war in Ukraine. And like Putin, Michael said he "would expect Xi Jinping to rattle the nuclear sabre". "You just have to worry if pull comes to shove, Xi Jinping might just pull the trigger," he said. "With a dictator, you never know... there are factors that could bring this to a head very quickly. "It might not be a full-scale invasion - it might be economic meddling, political coercion."</p>
<p>"What China has been doing with the largest and most aggressive show of force is not just for fun and games"</p>
<p>– Michael BeckleyFormer US Department Of Defence Official</p>
<p>Taiwan is feared to be a major flashpoint between the Washington and Beijing (https://www.the-sun.com/news/3949232/us-secretly-training-taiwan-spy-missions-china/)- with a potential invasion forcing the US to either abandon the island or face full scale war with China (https://www.the-sun.com/news/5319135/china-invade-taiwan-new-aircraft-carrier/).</p>
<p>On Sunday, Republican Mike McCaul said the odds of conflict with China over Taiwan are "very high". He said if China failed to take control of Taiwan bloodlessly then "they are going to look at a military invasion in my judgement". It came after General Mike Minihan, head of the US Air Mobility Command, wrote in a memo: "My gut tells me we will fight in 2025."</p>
<p>Michael said the US and Taiwan have been slow to respond to China's vast military expansion. "They are coming off a decade of really ramping up their military capabilities - and the US and Taiwan have been slow to respond," he said. "As someone who works closely with the US government, I would like to have seen faster responses from Taiwan and Japan."</p>
<p>President and founder of Eurasia Group, Ian Bremmer, said a war with Taiwan is "not very likely to happen in the next few years". But the author didn't rule out the scenario.</p>
<p>"China is going to be checked militarily by many countries in the region, and the US," Ian said. "The Chinese is aware of that, and they don't want to get in a direct fight militarily. "The Chinese aren't being stupid about trying to engage in a military confrontation with the US and their allies."</p>
<p>"Putin is a leader making massive misjudgements on the global stage - I don't see Xi doing that"</p>
<p>– Ian BremmerEurasia Group</p>
<p>He added: "Their ability to get Taiwanese business people to change their orientation politically or else they will be cut down is a lever the Chinese have. "Putin is a leader making massive misjudgements on the global stage - I don't see Xi doing that. "I don't see the Chinese government itching for a global fight - with the exception of the reunification of Taiwan." While Beijing may be preparing for a lightning war (https://www.the-sun.com/news/5946480/four-ways-china-take-taiwan-lightning-invasion/) to storm across the Taiwan Strait and capture the island, experts have said the war could be anything but quick. With tough beaches, rocky terrain, well-drilled defenders, and unforgiving seas, China could face the same brutal grinding warfare that Russia is facing in Ukraine. Taking Taiwan could even require Beijing to muster a force of two million troops (https://www.the-sun.com/news/5947970/china-two-million-soldiers-taiwan-russia/), it's been claimed.</p>
<p>Last year, new photos revealed for the first time (https://www.the-sun.com/news/6583901/heavy-military-operations-south-china-sea/) just how far China's militarisation has escalated in the South China Sea.</p>
<p>Chilling images showed the massive sprawl of Chinese military operations on the man-made islands - which are armed to the teeth with deadly hardware including missile aircraft, flight hangars, and spy planes. The largest of the islands in the archipelago, Taiping Island, is currently controlled by Taiwan - which is at the centre of invasion plans being drawn up by Beijing.</p>
<p>The full debate between Michael Beckley and Ian Bremmer will be released on theIntelligence Squared US (https://opentodebate.org/) podcast on February 17.</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Has the Electoral College Outlived Its Usefulness?</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/electoral-college-has-outlived-its-usefulness</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10185</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> May 20, 2020</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Law, Politics, U.S.</p>
<p><div>
<p xml:lang="EN-US">Five American presidents — two in the last 20 years — have assumed office without winning the popular vote. The most recent example, President Trump’s election in 2016, renewed vigorous debate about the Electoral College’s role in American politics. Supporters argue that the Founders wisely established the college to safeguard the republic against mob rule and ensure voters in less populous states have a voice in presidential elections. But opponents claim the college was created to protect the institution of slavery and that, in the modern era, it subverts the will of people and unfairly prioritizes voters in rural and swing states. As the nation looks to another Electoral College decision in 2020 and the Supreme Court prepares to rule on the landmark “faithless elector” case, we ask: Has the Electoral College Outlived Its Usefulness?</p>
</div>
<div>
<p xml:lang="EN-US">This debate is presented in partnership with the Northwestern Pritzker School of Law as part of the Newt and Jo Minow Debate Series.</p>
</div>
<div class="elfsight-app-2f080b9a-3319-4ba3-a385-37700215f236"></div></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/xCuMXVLI-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/xCuMXVLI-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Jamelle Bouie</strong><br><span class="TextRun BCX0 SCXO140673631" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun BCX0 SCXO140673631">Jamelle Bouie is a columnist for the New York Times and a political analyst for CBS News, where he covers history and politics and has reported on campaigns, elections, national affairs, and culture. Prior to working at the Times, Jamelle was the chief political correspondent for Slate magazine and a staff writer at The Daily Beast. He has held fellowships at The American Prospect and The Nation magazine and was recognized in Forbes’ 30 Under 30 – Media list in 2015. He graduated from the University of Virginia with a degree in political and social thought and government.</span></span></p>
<p><strong>Kate Shaw</strong><br>Kate Shaw is a law professor at the Cardozo School of Law and the co-director of the Floersheimer Center for Constitutional Democracy. She is a Supreme Court contributor for ABC News and co-host of the "Strict Scrutiny" podcast. Shaw is a graduate of the Northwestern Pritzker School of Law and served as an associate counsel in the Obama White House.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://cardozo.yu.edu/directory/kate-shaw">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Tara Ross</strong><br>Tara Ross is nationally recognized for her expertise on the Electoral College. She is the author of several books on the Electoral College, including "Why We Need the Electoral College," "The Indispensable Electoral College," and "We Elect a President." A retired lawyer, Ross served as editor-in-chief of the Texas Review of Law and Politics.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.taraross.com/about">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Bradley A. Smith</strong><br>Bradley A. Smith is one of the nation’s leading authorities on election law and campaign finance. Under President George W. Bush, he served as commissioner, vice chairman, and chairman of the Federal Election Commission. He is a professor at Capital University Law School and co-author of “Voting Rights and Election Law,” a leading casebook in the field.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://law.capital.edu/Faculty/Bios/bsmith.asp">here</a></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> May 20, 2020</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Law, Politics, U.S.</p>
<p><div>
<p xml:lang="EN-US">Five American presidents — two in the last 20 years — have assumed office without winning the popular vote. The most recent example, President Trump’s election in 2016, renewed vigorous debate about the Electoral College’s role in American politics. Supporters argue that the Founders wisely established the college to safeguard the republic against mob rule and ensure voters in less populous states have a voice in presidential elections. But opponents claim the college was created to protect the institution of slavery and that, in the modern era, it subverts the will of people and unfairly prioritizes voters in rural and swing states. As the nation looks to another Electoral College decision in 2020 and the Supreme Court prepares to rule on the landmark “faithless elector” case, we ask: Has the Electoral College Outlived Its Usefulness?</p>
</div>
<div>
<p xml:lang="EN-US">This debate is presented in partnership with the Northwestern Pritzker School of Law as part of the Newt and Jo Minow Debate Series.</p>
</div>
<div class="elfsight-app-2f080b9a-3319-4ba3-a385-37700215f236"></div></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/xCuMXVLI-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/xCuMXVLI-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Jamelle Bouie</strong><br><span class="TextRun BCX0 SCXO140673631" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun BCX0 SCXO140673631">Jamelle Bouie is a columnist for the New York Times and a political analyst for CBS News, where he covers history and politics and has reported on campaigns, elections, national affairs, and culture. Prior to working at the Times, Jamelle was the chief political correspondent for Slate magazine and a staff writer at The Daily Beast. He has held fellowships at The American Prospect and The Nation magazine and was recognized in Forbes’ 30 Under 30 – Media list in 2015. He graduated from the University of Virginia with a degree in political and social thought and government.</span></span></p>
<p><strong>Kate Shaw</strong><br>Kate Shaw is a law professor at the Cardozo School of Law and the co-director of the Floersheimer Center for Constitutional Democracy. She is a Supreme Court contributor for ABC News and co-host of the "Strict Scrutiny" podcast. Shaw is a graduate of the Northwestern Pritzker School of Law and served as an associate counsel in the Obama White House.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://cardozo.yu.edu/directory/kate-shaw">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Tara Ross</strong><br>Tara Ross is nationally recognized for her expertise on the Electoral College. She is the author of several books on the Electoral College, including "Why We Need the Electoral College," "The Indispensable Electoral College," and "We Elect a President." A retired lawyer, Ross served as editor-in-chief of the Texas Review of Law and Politics.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.taraross.com/about">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Bradley A. Smith</strong><br>Bradley A. Smith is one of the nation’s leading authorities on election law and campaign finance. Under President George W. Bush, he served as commissioner, vice chairman, and chairman of the Federal Election Commission. He is a professor at Capital University Law School and co-author of “Voting Rights and Election Law,” a leading casebook in the field.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://law.capital.edu/Faculty/Bios/bsmith.asp">here</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Global Financial System Was Better Prepared for the Pandemic Than 2008</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/global-financial-system-was-better-prepared-pandemic-2008</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10198</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> May 12, 2020</p>
<p>More than a decade ago, Lehman Brothers collapsed, and the world witnessed one of the worst financial crises in global history. In January 2019, Intelligence Squared U.S. hosted a debate on the motion “Ten Years After the Global Financial Crisis, the System Is Safer,” to assess how resilient markets would be in the future. With the emergence of a global pandemic, this has put the debater’s arguments to the ultimate test – whose claims have been vindicated by this unprecedented event? John Donvan is joined by two IQ2 alumni – a top Obama administration economic advisor, Jason Furman, and chair of the editorial board and editor-at-large (U.S.) of the Financial Times, Gillian Tett – to debate whether the global financial system was better prepared for this pandemic after the 2008 financial crash.
<script src="https://apps.elfsight.com/p/platform.js" defer></script>
<div class="elfsight-app-a6cb8e82-0a06-4d13-b9c5-33321afea097"></div></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://www.youtube.com/embed/McqJeP3YAeM' target='_blank'>https://www.youtube.com/embed/McqJeP3YAeM</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Jason Furman</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">Jason Furman is the Aetna Professor of the Practice of Economic Policy jointly at Harvard Kennedy School and the Department of Economics at Harvard University. He is also a nonresident senior fellow at the Peterson Institute for International Economics. Previously he served as a top economic adviser to President Obama, including serving as the 28th Chairman of the Council of Economic Advisers, acting as President Obama’s chief economist and a cabinet member. During this time, Furman played a major role in most of the major economic policies of the Obama Administration. Furman also served under President Clinton. Furman engages in public policy through research, writing, and teaching, focusing on U.S. and international macroeconomics, fiscal policy, labor markets, and competition policy. He is a member of numerous organizations, including the Council on Foreign Relations, the Group of Thirty, and the Economic Strategy Group. He also serves as a Trustee of the Russell Sage Foundation and the advisory boards for the Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, the Bund Summit, the Hamilton Project, and the Washington Center for Equitable Growth. In addition to articles in scholarly journals and periodicals, Furman is a regular contributor to the </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">W</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">all Street Journal</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0"> and </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">Project Syndicate</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0"> and the editor of two books on economic policy.</span></span></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Gillian Tett</strong><br>Gillian Tett is chair of the editorial board and U.S. editor-at-large of the Financial Times, where she oversees global coverage of the financial markets. An award-winning journalist and best-selling author, Tett is also the co-founder of "Moral Money," a twice-weekly newsletter on socially responsible business. Her most recent book, "The Silo Effect," analyzes the financial system through the lens of cultural anthropology. She has been named Columnist of the Year (2014), Journalist of the Year (2009), and Business Journalist of the Year (2008) in the British Press Awards and received three awards from America's Society of Business and Economic Writers Awards. She is a best-selling author and has received the Royal Anthropological Institute Marsh Award and the American Anthropological Association President Medal for her work in social science.</p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> May 12, 2020</p>
<p>More than a decade ago, Lehman Brothers collapsed, and the world witnessed one of the worst financial crises in global history. In January 2019, Intelligence Squared U.S. hosted a debate on the motion “Ten Years After the Global Financial Crisis, the System Is Safer,” to assess how resilient markets would be in the future. With the emergence of a global pandemic, this has put the debater’s arguments to the ultimate test – whose claims have been vindicated by this unprecedented event? John Donvan is joined by two IQ2 alumni – a top Obama administration economic advisor, Jason Furman, and chair of the editorial board and editor-at-large (U.S.) of the Financial Times, Gillian Tett – to debate whether the global financial system was better prepared for this pandemic after the 2008 financial crash.
<script src="https://apps.elfsight.com/p/platform.js" defer></script>
<div class="elfsight-app-a6cb8e82-0a06-4d13-b9c5-33321afea097"></div></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://www.youtube.com/embed/McqJeP3YAeM' target='_blank'>https://www.youtube.com/embed/McqJeP3YAeM</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Jason Furman</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">Jason Furman is the Aetna Professor of the Practice of Economic Policy jointly at Harvard Kennedy School and the Department of Economics at Harvard University. He is also a nonresident senior fellow at the Peterson Institute for International Economics. Previously he served as a top economic adviser to President Obama, including serving as the 28th Chairman of the Council of Economic Advisers, acting as President Obama’s chief economist and a cabinet member. During this time, Furman played a major role in most of the major economic policies of the Obama Administration. Furman also served under President Clinton. Furman engages in public policy through research, writing, and teaching, focusing on U.S. and international macroeconomics, fiscal policy, labor markets, and competition policy. He is a member of numerous organizations, including the Council on Foreign Relations, the Group of Thirty, and the Economic Strategy Group. He also serves as a Trustee of the Russell Sage Foundation and the advisory boards for the Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, the Bund Summit, the Hamilton Project, and the Washington Center for Equitable Growth. In addition to articles in scholarly journals and periodicals, Furman is a regular contributor to the </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">W</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">all Street Journal</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0"> and </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0">Project Syndicate</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO2259304 BCX0"> and the editor of two books on economic policy.</span></span></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Gillian Tett</strong><br>Gillian Tett is chair of the editorial board and U.S. editor-at-large of the Financial Times, where she oversees global coverage of the financial markets. An award-winning journalist and best-selling author, Tett is also the co-founder of "Moral Money," a twice-weekly newsletter on socially responsible business. Her most recent book, "The Silo Effect," analyzes the financial system through the lens of cultural anthropology. She has been named Columnist of the Year (2014), Journalist of the Year (2009), and Business Journalist of the Year (2008) in the British Press Awards and received three awards from America's Society of Business and Economic Writers Awards. She is a best-selling author and has received the Royal Anthropological Institute Marsh Award and the American Anthropological Association President Medal for her work in social science.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Defense Production Act Is Being Underutilized</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/defense-production-act-being-underutilized</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10183</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> April 24, 2020</p>
<p>As health professionals and leaders around the nation rush to procure the supplies Americans need to combat coronavirus, we ask: Is the Defense Production Act being underutilized?  This little-known law, which dates back to the Korean War, gives the president vast authority to compel private companies to act in the interest of national defense. While President Trump has invoked the act in recent weeks, many are calling on his administration to use its powers much more broadly. They argue that the federal government must intervene in private industry to ensure life-saving supplies – like personal protective equipment and ventilators – are produced and distributed effectively. But others say that companies like GM and Ford will meet America’s needs without unnecessary and inefficient government overreach.
<script src="https://apps.elfsight.com/p/platform.js" defer></script>
<div class="elfsight-app-52e72d33-60b7-47ff-a35f-2fbfdef10ed0"></div></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Margaret O’Mara</strong><br>Margaret O'Mara is a historian of modern America who writes and teaches about the history of the technology industry, American politics, and the connections between the two. She is a history professor at the University of Washington and writes often for major publications, including The New York Times, The Washington Post, and The Los Angeles Times. In 2005, she published the book "Cities of Knowledge", in 2015 “Pivitol Tuesdays: Four Elections That Shaped the Twentieth Century, and most recently authored "The Code: Silicon Valley and the Remaking of America." Since the pandemic, she has studied the impact of technology on major metropolitan areas.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Thomas Spoehr</strong><br>Thomas Spoehr is director of the Heritage Foundation's Center for National Defense. Prior to joining Heritage, Spoehr served for over 36 years in the U.S. Army, attaining the rank of Lieutenant General. An expert on national defense policy, he is one of the foremost uniformed experts in weapons of mass destruction, which include chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear weapons.</p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> April 24, 2020</p>
<p>As health professionals and leaders around the nation rush to procure the supplies Americans need to combat coronavirus, we ask: Is the Defense Production Act being underutilized?  This little-known law, which dates back to the Korean War, gives the president vast authority to compel private companies to act in the interest of national defense. While President Trump has invoked the act in recent weeks, many are calling on his administration to use its powers much more broadly. They argue that the federal government must intervene in private industry to ensure life-saving supplies – like personal protective equipment and ventilators – are produced and distributed effectively. But others say that companies like GM and Ford will meet America’s needs without unnecessary and inefficient government overreach.
<script src="https://apps.elfsight.com/p/platform.js" defer></script>
<div class="elfsight-app-52e72d33-60b7-47ff-a35f-2fbfdef10ed0"></div></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Margaret O’Mara</strong><br>Margaret O'Mara is a historian of modern America who writes and teaches about the history of the technology industry, American politics, and the connections between the two. She is a history professor at the University of Washington and writes often for major publications, including The New York Times, The Washington Post, and The Los Angeles Times. In 2005, she published the book "Cities of Knowledge", in 2015 “Pivitol Tuesdays: Four Elections That Shaped the Twentieth Century, and most recently authored "The Code: Silicon Valley and the Remaking of America." Since the pandemic, she has studied the impact of technology on major metropolitan areas.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Thomas Spoehr</strong><br>Thomas Spoehr is director of the Heritage Foundation's Center for National Defense. Prior to joining Heritage, Spoehr served for over 36 years in the U.S. Army, attaining the rank of Lieutenant General. An expert on national defense policy, he is one of the foremost uniformed experts in weapons of mass destruction, which include chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear weapons.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Maximum Pressure Campaign Against Iran Is Working</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/maximum-pressure-campaign-against-iran-working</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10213</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> March 04, 2020</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Politics, World</p>
<p>The targeted killing of General Qassim Suleimani, one of Iran’s most prominent military leaders, sent shockwaves around the world. The strike came more than a year after the United States unilaterally withdrew from the JCPOA and launched a series of punishing economic sanctions that have drastically reduced Iran's oil exports and crippled its economy. The administration’s defenders argue that this "maximum pressure" campaign is necessary to protect American interests, quell Tehran’s human rights abuses, and halt Iran's support of terrorist networks across the region. But opponents see maximum pressure as dangerously misguided. They contend that abandoning the JCPOA – a historic diplomatic achievement – increases the risk of war and undermines key allies. Further, critics say, economic sanctions target civilians and fuel anti-American sentiment in Iran and beyond. Is the maximum pressure campaign against Iran working?
Foreign Affairs is our media partner.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://www.youtube.com/embed/7bJKvyukAoI' target='_blank'>https://www.youtube.com/embed/7bJKvyukAoI</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Victor Davis Hanson</strong><br>Victor Davis Hanson is a leading scholar of classics and military history. He has written or edited more than 20 books, including “The Case for Trump.” Hanson is the host of the National Review’s “The Victor Davis Hanson Podcast” and is the Martin and Illie Anderson Senior Fellow at the Hoover Institution.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.hoover.org/profiles/victor-davis-hanson">here</a></p>
<p><strong>H. R. McMaster</strong><br>H. R. McMaster was the National Security Advisor under President Donald Trump and served as a commissioned officer in the Army for 34 years before retiring as a Lieutenant General in 2018. McMaster is now the Fouad and Michelle Ajami Senior Fellow at the Hoover Institution.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.hoover.org/profiles/h-r-mcmaster">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Martha Crenshaw</strong><br>Martha Crenshaw is a pioneer in terrorism studies. Her recent books include “Explaining Terrorism” and “Countering Terrorism.” Crenshaw is a senior fellow at the Center for International Security and Cooperation and the Freeman Spogli Institute for International Studies at Stanford University and a professor emerita of political science.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://cisac.fsi.stanford.edu/people/martha_crenshaw?combine=book">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Abbas Milani</strong><br>Abbas Milani is a widely published and cited scholar with expertise in U.S.-Iran relations and Iranian cultural, political, and security issues. He is the author of several books, including “The Myth of the Great Satan: A New Look at America's Relations with Iran.” Milani is a research fellow and co-director of the Iran Democracy Project at the Hoover Institution.
<br>Full bio is avaliable <a href="https://www.hoover.org/profiles/abbas-milani">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>The Maximum Pressure Campaign Against Iran Is Working</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>General Suleimani Strike</u></p>
<p><u>Economic Sanctions</u></p>
<p><u>JCPOA</u></p>
<p><u>Domestic Unrest in Iran</u></p>
<p><u>Iranian Funding of Terror</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> March 04, 2020</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Politics, World</p>
<p>The targeted killing of General Qassim Suleimani, one of Iran’s most prominent military leaders, sent shockwaves around the world. The strike came more than a year after the United States unilaterally withdrew from the JCPOA and launched a series of punishing economic sanctions that have drastically reduced Iran's oil exports and crippled its economy. The administration’s defenders argue that this "maximum pressure" campaign is necessary to protect American interests, quell Tehran’s human rights abuses, and halt Iran's support of terrorist networks across the region. But opponents see maximum pressure as dangerously misguided. They contend that abandoning the JCPOA – a historic diplomatic achievement – increases the risk of war and undermines key allies. Further, critics say, economic sanctions target civilians and fuel anti-American sentiment in Iran and beyond. Is the maximum pressure campaign against Iran working?
Foreign Affairs is our media partner.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://www.youtube.com/embed/7bJKvyukAoI' target='_blank'>https://www.youtube.com/embed/7bJKvyukAoI</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Victor Davis Hanson</strong><br>Victor Davis Hanson is a leading scholar of classics and military history. He has written or edited more than 20 books, including “The Case for Trump.” Hanson is the host of the National Review’s “The Victor Davis Hanson Podcast” and is the Martin and Illie Anderson Senior Fellow at the Hoover Institution.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.hoover.org/profiles/victor-davis-hanson">here</a></p>
<p><strong>H. R. McMaster</strong><br>H. R. McMaster was the National Security Advisor under President Donald Trump and served as a commissioned officer in the Army for 34 years before retiring as a Lieutenant General in 2018. McMaster is now the Fouad and Michelle Ajami Senior Fellow at the Hoover Institution.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.hoover.org/profiles/h-r-mcmaster">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Martha Crenshaw</strong><br>Martha Crenshaw is a pioneer in terrorism studies. Her recent books include “Explaining Terrorism” and “Countering Terrorism.” Crenshaw is a senior fellow at the Center for International Security and Cooperation and the Freeman Spogli Institute for International Studies at Stanford University and a professor emerita of political science.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://cisac.fsi.stanford.edu/people/martha_crenshaw?combine=book">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Abbas Milani</strong><br>Abbas Milani is a widely published and cited scholar with expertise in U.S.-Iran relations and Iranian cultural, political, and security issues. He is the author of several books, including “The Myth of the Great Satan: A New Look at America's Relations with Iran.” Milani is a research fellow and co-director of the Iran Democracy Project at the Hoover Institution.
<br>Full bio is avaliable <a href="https://www.hoover.org/profiles/abbas-milani">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>The Maximum Pressure Campaign Against Iran Is Working</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>General Suleimani Strike</u></p>
<p><u>Economic Sanctions</u></p>
<p><u>JCPOA</u></p>
<p><u>Domestic Unrest in Iran</u></p>
<p><u>Iranian Funding of Terror</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Is Anti-Zionism the New Anti-Semitism?</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/anti-zionism-new-anti-semitism</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10007</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> February 27, 2020</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Culture, Religion, World</p>
<p>Zionism — the belief that the Jewish people have a right to statehood in Israel — has been debated for decades. But recently, the Trump administration has publicly championed the Zionist cause and defended the U.S.-Israel special relationship. Simultaneously, the progressive left has become increasingly vocal in condemning Israel's actions. Zionism’s modern-day opponents argue that their concerns about Israel — particularly regarding Palestinian rights and sovereignty — are legitimate. But Zionism's proponents argue that Jews have a political claim to self-determination within their ancestral borders, and that, against the backdrop of increased anti-Semitic violence around the world, anti-Zionism is thinly veiled anti-Semitism. Is anti-Zionism the new anti-Semitism?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/kzHUefGU-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/kzHUefGU-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Bret Stephens</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">Bret Stephens is a Pulitzer Prize-winning journalist, an op-ed columnist for </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">The New York Times</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">, and a political contributor at NBC and MSNBC. Prior to joining the </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">Times</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">, he worked at the </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">Wall Street Journal </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">where he was the deputy editorial page editor in charge of international opinion and, for 11 years, the principal foreign-affairs columnist. Before that, he was editor-in-chief of </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">The Jerusalem Post</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">. At </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">The Jerusalem Post</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">, he oversaw the paper’s news, editorial, digital, and international operations, and wrote a weekly column. Stephens is the author of “America in Retreat: The New Isolationism and the Coming Global Disorder,” “The Dying Art of Disagreement,” and “Has Obama Made the World a More Dangerous Place?: The Munk Debate on U.S. Foreign Policy.” He is the recipient of numerous awards and distinctions, including three honorary doctorates, the Ellis Island Medal of Honor, and the 2013 Pulitzer Prize for Commentary in his columns on American foreign policy and domestic politics. He is also the editor-in-chief of SAPIR: A Journal of Jewish Conversations, which is published by the Maimonides Fund. Stephens holds a B.A. from the University of Chicago and an MSc. from the London School of Economics.</span></span><span class="EOP SCXO29872669 BCX0"> </span></p>
<p><strong>Einat Wilf</strong><br><span data-contrast="auto">Dr. Einat Wilf is a leading thinker on Israel, Zionism, foreign policy and education. She was a member of the Israeli Parliament (Knesset) from 2010 to 2013, where she served as Chair of the Education Committee and Member of the influential Foreign Affairs and Defense Committee.</span>
<span data-contrast="auto">Born and raised in Israel, Dr. Wilf served as an Intelligence Officer in the Israel Defense Forces, Foreign Policy Advisor to Vice Prime Minister Shimon Peres, and a strategic consultant with McKinsey & Company.</span>
<span data-contrast="auto">Dr. Wilf has a B.A. from Harvard, an MBA from INSEAD in France, and a Ph.D. in Political Science from the University of Cambridge. She was the Goldman Visiting Professor at Georgetown University.</span>
<span data-contrast="auto">Dr. Wilf is the author of seven books that explore key issues in Israeli society. "We Should All Be Zionists," published in 2022, brings together her essays from the past four years on Israel, Zionism and the path to peace; the co-authored “The War of Return: How Western Indulgence of the Palestinian Dream Has Obstructed the Path to Peace,” was published in 2020.</span></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Peter Beinart</strong><br>Peter Beinart is a columnist, professor of journalism and political science at the City University of New York, and the author of three books, including “The Crisis of Zionism.” An editor-at-large of the Jewish Currents, Beinart has written for Time, The New York Times, and The New York Review of Books, among other periodicals. He is currently a contributor to The Atlantic, a political commentator for CNN, and a senior fellow at the Foundation for Middle East Peace.
<br>Full bio is avaliable <a href="https://peterbeinart.net/biography/">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Yousef Munayyer</strong><br>Yousef Munayyer is a political analyst, writer, and executive director of the US Campaign for Palestinian Rights (USCPR). Prior to joining USCPR, he was the executive director of the Jerusalem Fund and Palestine Center and served as a policy analyst for the American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee.
<br>Full bio is avaliable <a href="https://uscpr.org/staff">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Open to Debate / Intelligence Squared U.S. Podcast Asks: Is Affirmative Action Unfair To Asian Americans?</strong> <small>2023-02-07 20:13:12</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Affirmative action is one of those issues that nags at people, irrespective of their view on its efficacy. For some, affirmative action offends their sense of fairness and raises their emotional thermostat because someone’s cutting in line. For others, affirmative action is a remedy for a long-standing societal illness — discrimination against a group or multiple groups. Finally, other people view a college campus as a “Cobb salad,” where many different ingredients are tossed into one bowl and one delicious food item results. To them, a college campus of, say, only one kind of cheese is just wrong.</p>
<p>It should never be said that the people at the Open to Debate formerly, Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. have shied away from a debate on a contentious issue. In fact, they know that it’s these issues that make for the most lively and edifying debates.</p>
<p>For some listeners, the concept of a debate may be an alien concept. Why? Because most media outlets, such as Fox News, allow one point of view, making their channel a “safe space” for the “one true political viewpoint.” When a contrary voice is invited on the network, they are often yelled at and talked over until they give up or the network goes to a commercial when that guest begins to score some debate points.</p>
<p>In real debates, people don’t yell or scream or call each other names. For millions, it will be an alien concept.</p>
<p>But listening to a true debate is a cleansing process. It’s like your intellect gets a good deep scrubbing. Lies are washed away. Alternative facts are not allowed. Insults have no place. Suddenly, your entire belief system is hosed down and then rebooted back to its factory default.</p>
<p>With that preface, the new episode of nonpartisan debate podcast Intelligence Squared U.S. asks a provocative question: “Is Affirmative Action Unfair to Asian Americans?”</p>
<p>The Supreme Court is likely to issue a ruling related to this topic in the coming months, having recently heard arguments in the case Students for Fair Admissions, Inc. v. President and Fellows of Harvard College.</p>
<p>Ahead of that, Intelligence Squared presents arguments on both sides of the issue.</p>
<p>“Arguments on both sides of the issue.” A novel concept these days, but, oh, so refreshing.</p>
<p>Arguing for the motion is Lee Cheng, Co-founder of the Asian American Coalition for Education who also worked in the Harvard College admissions process as an alumni interviewer for nearly 25 years. Arguing against is John Yang, President of Asian Americans Advancing Justice who has worked with the White House and Senate in securing the nomination and confirmation of over 20 Asian American and Pacific Islander federal judges.</p>
<p>Listen to the podcast on Apple (https://draft.blogger.com/#), Spotify (https://draft.blogger.com/#), YouTube (https://draft.blogger.com/#), or wherever you get podcasts. Find more info and debater bios at intelligencesquaredus.org (https://draft.blogger.com/#).</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Anti-Zionism Is the New Anti-Semitism</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>The BDS Movement</u></p>
<p><u>Polls and Public Opinion</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> February 27, 2020</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Culture, Religion, World</p>
<p>Zionism — the belief that the Jewish people have a right to statehood in Israel — has been debated for decades. But recently, the Trump administration has publicly championed the Zionist cause and defended the U.S.-Israel special relationship. Simultaneously, the progressive left has become increasingly vocal in condemning Israel's actions. Zionism’s modern-day opponents argue that their concerns about Israel — particularly regarding Palestinian rights and sovereignty — are legitimate. But Zionism's proponents argue that Jews have a political claim to self-determination within their ancestral borders, and that, against the backdrop of increased anti-Semitic violence around the world, anti-Zionism is thinly veiled anti-Semitism. Is anti-Zionism the new anti-Semitism?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/kzHUefGU-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/kzHUefGU-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Bret Stephens</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">Bret Stephens is a Pulitzer Prize-winning journalist, an op-ed columnist for </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">The New York Times</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">, and a political contributor at NBC and MSNBC. Prior to joining the </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">Times</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">, he worked at the </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">Wall Street Journal </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">where he was the deputy editorial page editor in charge of international opinion and, for 11 years, the principal foreign-affairs columnist. Before that, he was editor-in-chief of </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">The Jerusalem Post</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">. At </span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">The Jerusalem Post</span></span><span class="TextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO29872669 BCX0">, he oversaw the paper’s news, editorial, digital, and international operations, and wrote a weekly column. Stephens is the author of “America in Retreat: The New Isolationism and the Coming Global Disorder,” “The Dying Art of Disagreement,” and “Has Obama Made the World a More Dangerous Place?: The Munk Debate on U.S. Foreign Policy.” He is the recipient of numerous awards and distinctions, including three honorary doctorates, the Ellis Island Medal of Honor, and the 2013 Pulitzer Prize for Commentary in his columns on American foreign policy and domestic politics. He is also the editor-in-chief of SAPIR: A Journal of Jewish Conversations, which is published by the Maimonides Fund. Stephens holds a B.A. from the University of Chicago and an MSc. from the London School of Economics.</span></span><span class="EOP SCXO29872669 BCX0"> </span></p>
<p><strong>Einat Wilf</strong><br><span data-contrast="auto">Dr. Einat Wilf is a leading thinker on Israel, Zionism, foreign policy and education. She was a member of the Israeli Parliament (Knesset) from 2010 to 2013, where she served as Chair of the Education Committee and Member of the influential Foreign Affairs and Defense Committee.</span>
<span data-contrast="auto">Born and raised in Israel, Dr. Wilf served as an Intelligence Officer in the Israel Defense Forces, Foreign Policy Advisor to Vice Prime Minister Shimon Peres, and a strategic consultant with McKinsey & Company.</span>
<span data-contrast="auto">Dr. Wilf has a B.A. from Harvard, an MBA from INSEAD in France, and a Ph.D. in Political Science from the University of Cambridge. She was the Goldman Visiting Professor at Georgetown University.</span>
<span data-contrast="auto">Dr. Wilf is the author of seven books that explore key issues in Israeli society. "We Should All Be Zionists," published in 2022, brings together her essays from the past four years on Israel, Zionism and the path to peace; the co-authored “The War of Return: How Western Indulgence of the Palestinian Dream Has Obstructed the Path to Peace,” was published in 2020.</span></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Peter Beinart</strong><br>Peter Beinart is a columnist, professor of journalism and political science at the City University of New York, and the author of three books, including “The Crisis of Zionism.” An editor-at-large of the Jewish Currents, Beinart has written for Time, The New York Times, and The New York Review of Books, among other periodicals. He is currently a contributor to The Atlantic, a political commentator for CNN, and a senior fellow at the Foundation for Middle East Peace.
<br>Full bio is avaliable <a href="https://peterbeinart.net/biography/">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Yousef Munayyer</strong><br>Yousef Munayyer is a political analyst, writer, and executive director of the US Campaign for Palestinian Rights (USCPR). Prior to joining USCPR, he was the executive director of the Jerusalem Fund and Palestine Center and served as a policy analyst for the American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee.
<br>Full bio is avaliable <a href="https://uscpr.org/staff">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Open to Debate / Intelligence Squared U.S. Podcast Asks: Is Affirmative Action Unfair To Asian Americans?</strong> <small>2023-02-07 20:13:12</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>Affirmative action is one of those issues that nags at people, irrespective of their view on its efficacy. For some, affirmative action offends their sense of fairness and raises their emotional thermostat because someone’s cutting in line. For others, affirmative action is a remedy for a long-standing societal illness — discrimination against a group or multiple groups. Finally, other people view a college campus as a “Cobb salad,” where many different ingredients are tossed into one bowl and one delicious food item results. To them, a college campus of, say, only one kind of cheese is just wrong.</p>
<p>It should never be said that the people at the Open to Debate formerly, Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. have shied away from a debate on a contentious issue. In fact, they know that it’s these issues that make for the most lively and edifying debates.</p>
<p>For some listeners, the concept of a debate may be an alien concept. Why? Because most media outlets, such as Fox News, allow one point of view, making their channel a “safe space” for the “one true political viewpoint.” When a contrary voice is invited on the network, they are often yelled at and talked over until they give up or the network goes to a commercial when that guest begins to score some debate points.</p>
<p>In real debates, people don’t yell or scream or call each other names. For millions, it will be an alien concept.</p>
<p>But listening to a true debate is a cleansing process. It’s like your intellect gets a good deep scrubbing. Lies are washed away. Alternative facts are not allowed. Insults have no place. Suddenly, your entire belief system is hosed down and then rebooted back to its factory default.</p>
<p>With that preface, the new episode of nonpartisan debate podcast Intelligence Squared U.S. asks a provocative question: “Is Affirmative Action Unfair to Asian Americans?”</p>
<p>The Supreme Court is likely to issue a ruling related to this topic in the coming months, having recently heard arguments in the case Students for Fair Admissions, Inc. v. President and Fellows of Harvard College.</p>
<p>Ahead of that, Intelligence Squared presents arguments on both sides of the issue.</p>
<p>“Arguments on both sides of the issue.” A novel concept these days, but, oh, so refreshing.</p>
<p>Arguing for the motion is Lee Cheng, Co-founder of the Asian American Coalition for Education who also worked in the Harvard College admissions process as an alumni interviewer for nearly 25 years. Arguing against is John Yang, President of Asian Americans Advancing Justice who has worked with the White House and Senate in securing the nomination and confirmation of over 20 Asian American and Pacific Islander federal judges.</p>
<p>Listen to the podcast on Apple (https://draft.blogger.com/#), Spotify (https://draft.blogger.com/#), YouTube (https://draft.blogger.com/#), or wherever you get podcasts. Find more info and debater bios at intelligencesquaredus.org (https://draft.blogger.com/#).</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Anti-Zionism Is the New Anti-Semitism</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>The BDS Movement</u></p>
<p><u>Polls and Public Opinion</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Two Cheers for Two Parties</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/two-cheers-two-parties</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10372</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> February 13, 2020</p>
<p>Facing extreme partisanship and polarization, America's two-party system has come under fire. Critics argue that the two-party system runs contrary to the founders' intent and has created a political system that fails to represent the electorate, concentrates power for the elites, and makes compromise impossible. They say it's time for real structural change. But others are more cautious. They argue that the two-party system is necessary to rein in extremes on both sides and promote the democratic institutions that are necessary to the nation's political and social stability. Further, they argue that multi-party democracies around the world -- including Israel, the UK, and Italy -- are now struggling to maintain stability and should serve as a warning to Americans seeking reform at home. As the nation gears up for the 2020 presidential election, we ask: Is the two-party system good for democracy?
This debate is presented with generous support from the Dolby Family in partnership with Hirsch Philanthropy Partners.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/1Ccpd8jF-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/1Ccpd8jF-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Yascha Mounk</strong><br>Yascha Mounk is an associate professor of practice in international affairs at Johns Hopkins University and a postdoctoral fellow at the German Marshall Fund. A columnist at Slate and the host of "The Good Fight" podcast, he is an expert on the rise of populism and the crisis of liberal democracy. He is also the author of "The People vs. Democracy: Why Our Freedom Is in Danger and How to Save It."
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.yaschamounk.com/about">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Norman Ornstein</strong><br>Norman Ornstein is a resident scholar at the American Enterprise Institute (AEI), where he studies politics, elections, and the U.S. Congress. A longtime observer and analyst of American politics, he is a co-host of AEI’s Election Watch series, a contributing editor and columnist for National Journal and The Atlantic, a BBC News election analyst, and the chairman of the Campaign Legal Center.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.aei.org/profile/norman-j-ornstein/">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Lee Drutman</strong><br>Lee Drutman is a political scientist and author focused on political parties and democracy. His recent book, "Breaking the Two-Party Doom Loop," makes the case for a multi-party system in the United States. He is a senior fellow in the Political Reform program at New America, co-host of the Politics in Question podcast, and writes for the New York Times, Vox, and FiveThirtyEight, among other outlets.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.newamerica.org/our-people/lee-drutman/">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Katherine Gehl</strong><br>Katherine Gehl is a business leader, political innovation activist, author, and speaker. Gehl leads Venn Innovations, a national, nonpartisan political innovation group, and is the co-author of the forthcoming book, "The Politics Industry," from Harvard Business Publishing. Gehl is co-chair of the National Association of Nonpartisan Reformers and co-founder and co-chair of Democracy Found. Gehl was president and CEO of Gehl Foods, a $250 million high-tech food manufacturing company in Wisconsin.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://katherinegehl.com/">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Two Cheers for Two Parties</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>History of the Two-Party System and Polarization in the United States</u></p>
<p><u>Third Parties</u></p>
<p><u>Parliamentary Governments</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> February 13, 2020</p>
<p>Facing extreme partisanship and polarization, America's two-party system has come under fire. Critics argue that the two-party system runs contrary to the founders' intent and has created a political system that fails to represent the electorate, concentrates power for the elites, and makes compromise impossible. They say it's time for real structural change. But others are more cautious. They argue that the two-party system is necessary to rein in extremes on both sides and promote the democratic institutions that are necessary to the nation's political and social stability. Further, they argue that multi-party democracies around the world -- including Israel, the UK, and Italy -- are now struggling to maintain stability and should serve as a warning to Americans seeking reform at home. As the nation gears up for the 2020 presidential election, we ask: Is the two-party system good for democracy?
This debate is presented with generous support from the Dolby Family in partnership with Hirsch Philanthropy Partners.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/1Ccpd8jF-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/1Ccpd8jF-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Yascha Mounk</strong><br>Yascha Mounk is an associate professor of practice in international affairs at Johns Hopkins University and a postdoctoral fellow at the German Marshall Fund. A columnist at Slate and the host of "The Good Fight" podcast, he is an expert on the rise of populism and the crisis of liberal democracy. He is also the author of "The People vs. Democracy: Why Our Freedom Is in Danger and How to Save It."
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.yaschamounk.com/about">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Norman Ornstein</strong><br>Norman Ornstein is a resident scholar at the American Enterprise Institute (AEI), where he studies politics, elections, and the U.S. Congress. A longtime observer and analyst of American politics, he is a co-host of AEI’s Election Watch series, a contributing editor and columnist for National Journal and The Atlantic, a BBC News election analyst, and the chairman of the Campaign Legal Center.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.aei.org/profile/norman-j-ornstein/">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Lee Drutman</strong><br>Lee Drutman is a political scientist and author focused on political parties and democracy. His recent book, "Breaking the Two-Party Doom Loop," makes the case for a multi-party system in the United States. He is a senior fellow in the Political Reform program at New America, co-host of the Politics in Question podcast, and writes for the New York Times, Vox, and FiveThirtyEight, among other outlets.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.newamerica.org/our-people/lee-drutman/">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Katherine Gehl</strong><br>Katherine Gehl is a business leader, political innovation activist, author, and speaker. Gehl leads Venn Innovations, a national, nonpartisan political innovation group, and is the co-author of the forthcoming book, "The Politics Industry," from Harvard Business Publishing. Gehl is co-chair of the National Association of Nonpartisan Reformers and co-founder and co-chair of Democracy Found. Gehl was president and CEO of Gehl Foods, a $250 million high-tech food manufacturing company in Wisconsin.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://katherinegehl.com/">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Two Cheers for Two Parties</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>History of the Two-Party System and Polarization in the United States</u></p>
<p><u>Third Parties</u></p>
<p><u>Parliamentary Governments</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>It’s Time to Expand Nuclear Power</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/its-time-expand-nuclear-power</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10228</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> January 23, 2020</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Energy, Environment</p>
<p>For decades, the development of nuclear power has sparked staunch debate among scientists, politicians, and activists alike. For its proponents, the promise of nuclear energy is clear: It's the most effective means of reducing greenhouse gases and combating climate change while still meeting the world's growing demand for energy. And to date, nuclear energy produces approximately 10% of the world's power and rakes in billions in revenue in the United States alone. But its critics argue that expanding nuclear energy is dangerous and ill-advised. They cite the high costs of building powerplants, the potential consequences of a meltdown, and the challenge of managing waste. Rather, they argue, we should look to wind and solar to meet our energy demands. Should nuclear energy fuel our future?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://www.youtube.com/embed/2hLOwm9Ei5s' target='_blank'>https://www.youtube.com/embed/2hLOwm9Ei5s</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Kirsty Gogan</strong><br>Kirsty Gogan is the co-founder and executive director of Energy for Humanity (EFH), an NGO focused on decarbonization and energy access. EFH led a delegation of climate scientists to defend nuclear energy at the Paris Climate Conference. A founding director of CleanTech Catalyst, Gogan has advised the UK government on nuclear power and evaluated the national response to Fukushima.</p>
<p><strong>Daniel Poneman</strong><br>Daniel Poneman is a former government official and nuclear energy executive. Under President Obama, he was the Deputy Secretary of Energy and also served as the COO of the Department of Energy. He is now the president and CEO of Centrus Energy, a global energy company that supplies low-enriched uranium for commercial nuclear power plants. He is a senior fellow at the Belfer Center for Science and International Affairs and the author of the recent book "Double Jeopardy: Combating Nuclear Terror and Climate Change."
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.centrusenergy.com/who-we-are/leadership/bio/daniel-poneman/">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Gregory B. Jaczko</strong><br>Gregory Jaczko is the former chairman of the U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC), where he handled the American government’s response to the Fukushima meltdown. After leaving the NRC, he wrote “Confessions of a Rogue Nuclear Regulator” and founded the wind energy company Wind Future LLC.</p>
<p><strong>Arjun Makhijani</strong><br>Arjun Makhijani is the president of the Institute for Energy and Environmental Research and the author of "Carbon-Free and Nuclear-Free: A Roadmap for US Energy Policy." He has spent decades studying nuclear disarmament and energy efficiency. Makhijani has a Ph.D. from the University of California at Berkeley, where he specialized in nuclear fusion.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://ieer.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/Short-Biography-of-Arjun-Makhijani.pdf">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Open to Debate Presents: It’s Time to Expand Nuclear Power with Bill Nye</strong> <small>2023-02-08 18:52:41</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>On Thursday, January 23, Bill Nye takes the Open to Debate stage to kick off the veteran debate series’ spring season. Nye, a longtime fan who publicly changed his mind about GMOs after attending the 2014 Open to Debate on the subject, will offer a nuclear power explainer to introduce the nonprofit’s live debate on the motion “It’s Time to Expand Nuclear Power.”</p>
<p>Proponents claim that nuclear energy is the most effective way to combat climate change while still meeting the world’s growing demand for energy. But critics argue that expanding nuclear energy is dangerous, costly, and ill-advised. Should nuclear energy fuel our future? Arguing yes will be Daniel Poneman, Deputy Secretary of Energy under President Obama, and the co-founder of Energy for Humanity, Kirsty Gogan. Arguing against them will be former chairman of the US Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Gregory B. Jaczko, and the president of the Institute for Energy and Environmental Research, Arjun Makhijani.</p>
<p>The “It’s Time to Expand Nuclear Power” debate will mark Open to Debate debut at their new NYC home, the Florence Gould Hall, then air soon after as part of the syndicated public radio show, podcast, and video series “Open to Debate”</p>
<p>KEYNOTE SPEAKER</p>
<p>* Bill Nye: Scientist and CEO of the Planetary Society
Bill Nye, scientist, engineer, comedian, author, and inventor, is a man with a mission: to help foster a scientifically literate society and to help people everywhere understand and appreciate the science that makes our world work. After Nye attended a 2014 Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. debate on GMOs, he spent time with panelist Dr. Robert Fraley and publicly changed his mind on the topic. He is CEO of the Planetary Society, a space-interest group, and hosts the “Science Rules!” podcast. Nye is best known for hosting the children’s science show “Bill Nye the Science Guy,” “Bill Nye Saves the World,” and is the author of multiple bestselling books.</p>
<p>For the Motion</p>
<p>* Kirsty Gogan: Co-founder and Executive Director of Energy for Humanity
Kirsty Gogan is the co-founder and executive director of Energy for Humanity (EFH), an NGO focused on decarbonization and energy access. EFH led a delegation of climate scientists to defend nuclear energy at the Paris Climate Conference. A founding director of CleanTech Catalyst, Gogan has advised the UK government on nuclear power and evaluated the national response to Fukushima.</p>
<p>* Daniel Poneman: President and CEO of Centrus Energy
Daniel Poneman is a former government official and nuclear energy executive. Under President Obama, he was the Deputy Secretary of Energy and also served as a COO of the Department of Energy. He is now the president and CEO of Centrus Energy, a global energy company that supplies low enriched uranium for commercial nuclear power plants. He is a senior fellow at the Belfer Center for Science and International Affairs and author of the recent book “Double Jeopardy: Combating Nuclear Terror and Climate Change.”</p>
<p>Arguing Against the Motion</p>
<p>* Gregory B. Jaczko: Former Chairman of the US Nuclear Regulatory Commission
Gregory B. Jaczko is the former chairman of the US Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC), where he handled the American government’s response to the Fukushima meltdown. After leaving the NRC, he wrote “Confessions of A Nuclear Regulator” and founded the wind energy company Wind Future LLC.</p>
<p>* Arjun Makhijani: President of the Institute for Energy and Environmental Research
Arjun Makhijani is the president of the Institute for Energy and Environmental Research and the author of “Carbon-Free and Nuclear Free: A Roadmap for US Energy Policy.” He has spent decades studying nuclear disarmament and energy efficiency. Makhijani has a Ph.D. from University of California at Berkeley, where he specialized in nuclear fusion.</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>It's Time to Expand Nuclear Power</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Costs & Investments</u></p>
<p><u>Waste & Risk</u></p>
<p><u>Global Response</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> January 23, 2020</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Energy, Environment</p>
<p>For decades, the development of nuclear power has sparked staunch debate among scientists, politicians, and activists alike. For its proponents, the promise of nuclear energy is clear: It's the most effective means of reducing greenhouse gases and combating climate change while still meeting the world's growing demand for energy. And to date, nuclear energy produces approximately 10% of the world's power and rakes in billions in revenue in the United States alone. But its critics argue that expanding nuclear energy is dangerous and ill-advised. They cite the high costs of building powerplants, the potential consequences of a meltdown, and the challenge of managing waste. Rather, they argue, we should look to wind and solar to meet our energy demands. Should nuclear energy fuel our future?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://www.youtube.com/embed/2hLOwm9Ei5s' target='_blank'>https://www.youtube.com/embed/2hLOwm9Ei5s</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Kirsty Gogan</strong><br>Kirsty Gogan is the co-founder and executive director of Energy for Humanity (EFH), an NGO focused on decarbonization and energy access. EFH led a delegation of climate scientists to defend nuclear energy at the Paris Climate Conference. A founding director of CleanTech Catalyst, Gogan has advised the UK government on nuclear power and evaluated the national response to Fukushima.</p>
<p><strong>Daniel Poneman</strong><br>Daniel Poneman is a former government official and nuclear energy executive. Under President Obama, he was the Deputy Secretary of Energy and also served as the COO of the Department of Energy. He is now the president and CEO of Centrus Energy, a global energy company that supplies low-enriched uranium for commercial nuclear power plants. He is a senior fellow at the Belfer Center for Science and International Affairs and the author of the recent book "Double Jeopardy: Combating Nuclear Terror and Climate Change."
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.centrusenergy.com/who-we-are/leadership/bio/daniel-poneman/">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Gregory B. Jaczko</strong><br>Gregory Jaczko is the former chairman of the U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC), where he handled the American government’s response to the Fukushima meltdown. After leaving the NRC, he wrote “Confessions of a Rogue Nuclear Regulator” and founded the wind energy company Wind Future LLC.</p>
<p><strong>Arjun Makhijani</strong><br>Arjun Makhijani is the president of the Institute for Energy and Environmental Research and the author of "Carbon-Free and Nuclear-Free: A Roadmap for US Energy Policy." He has spent decades studying nuclear disarmament and energy efficiency. Makhijani has a Ph.D. from the University of California at Berkeley, where he specialized in nuclear fusion.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://ieer.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/Short-Biography-of-Arjun-Makhijani.pdf">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Open to Debate Presents: It’s Time to Expand Nuclear Power with Bill Nye</strong> <small>2023-02-08 18:52:41</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>On Thursday, January 23, Bill Nye takes the Open to Debate stage to kick off the veteran debate series’ spring season. Nye, a longtime fan who publicly changed his mind about GMOs after attending the 2014 Open to Debate on the subject, will offer a nuclear power explainer to introduce the nonprofit’s live debate on the motion “It’s Time to Expand Nuclear Power.”</p>
<p>Proponents claim that nuclear energy is the most effective way to combat climate change while still meeting the world’s growing demand for energy. But critics argue that expanding nuclear energy is dangerous, costly, and ill-advised. Should nuclear energy fuel our future? Arguing yes will be Daniel Poneman, Deputy Secretary of Energy under President Obama, and the co-founder of Energy for Humanity, Kirsty Gogan. Arguing against them will be former chairman of the US Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Gregory B. Jaczko, and the president of the Institute for Energy and Environmental Research, Arjun Makhijani.</p>
<p>The “It’s Time to Expand Nuclear Power” debate will mark Open to Debate debut at their new NYC home, the Florence Gould Hall, then air soon after as part of the syndicated public radio show, podcast, and video series “Open to Debate”</p>
<p>KEYNOTE SPEAKER</p>
<p>* Bill Nye: Scientist and CEO of the Planetary Society
Bill Nye, scientist, engineer, comedian, author, and inventor, is a man with a mission: to help foster a scientifically literate society and to help people everywhere understand and appreciate the science that makes our world work. After Nye attended a 2014 Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. debate on GMOs, he spent time with panelist Dr. Robert Fraley and publicly changed his mind on the topic. He is CEO of the Planetary Society, a space-interest group, and hosts the “Science Rules!” podcast. Nye is best known for hosting the children’s science show “Bill Nye the Science Guy,” “Bill Nye Saves the World,” and is the author of multiple bestselling books.</p>
<p>For the Motion</p>
<p>* Kirsty Gogan: Co-founder and Executive Director of Energy for Humanity
Kirsty Gogan is the co-founder and executive director of Energy for Humanity (EFH), an NGO focused on decarbonization and energy access. EFH led a delegation of climate scientists to defend nuclear energy at the Paris Climate Conference. A founding director of CleanTech Catalyst, Gogan has advised the UK government on nuclear power and evaluated the national response to Fukushima.</p>
<p>* Daniel Poneman: President and CEO of Centrus Energy
Daniel Poneman is a former government official and nuclear energy executive. Under President Obama, he was the Deputy Secretary of Energy and also served as a COO of the Department of Energy. He is now the president and CEO of Centrus Energy, a global energy company that supplies low enriched uranium for commercial nuclear power plants. He is a senior fellow at the Belfer Center for Science and International Affairs and author of the recent book “Double Jeopardy: Combating Nuclear Terror and Climate Change.”</p>
<p>Arguing Against the Motion</p>
<p>* Gregory B. Jaczko: Former Chairman of the US Nuclear Regulatory Commission
Gregory B. Jaczko is the former chairman of the US Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC), where he handled the American government’s response to the Fukushima meltdown. After leaving the NRC, he wrote “Confessions of A Nuclear Regulator” and founded the wind energy company Wind Future LLC.</p>
<p>* Arjun Makhijani: President of the Institute for Energy and Environmental Research
Arjun Makhijani is the president of the Institute for Energy and Environmental Research and the author of “Carbon-Free and Nuclear Free: A Roadmap for US Energy Policy.” He has spent decades studying nuclear disarmament and energy efficiency. Makhijani has a Ph.D. from University of California at Berkeley, where he specialized in nuclear fusion.</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>It's Time to Expand Nuclear Power</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Costs & Investments</u></p>
<p><u>Waste & Risk</u></p>
<p><u>Global Response</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
    
</rss>
