<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">

    <channel>
        <title>Open to Debate – Debates</title>
        <link>https://opentodebate.org</link>
        <description>Debates with related research and news</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 03:03:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Pandemic: Year-In-Review</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/pandemic-year-review</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10258</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> December 22, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Health</p>
<p>Two years ago in January, the Covid-19 virus made its way to American shores. (Or at least that is when the CDC confirmed the first U.S. case) In many ways, the world was a different place back then. President Trump was still in office. The word “pandemic” hadn’t quite assumed the gravity it would. And phrases like “flatten the curve,” “doomscrolling,” and “you’re on mute” hadn’t yet become so utterly ubiquitous. But in the midst of the resulting panic, Open to Debate made a commitment to keep debate alive – particularly the kinds of competing ideas that would remain outside the ensuing onslaught of misinformation. We brought in expert interviewees and those who could bring a historical perspective to the unfolding melee. And as the first vaccines surfaced, we debated mandates, pharmaceutical patents, and which groups should receive priority. Through these platforms, and through a closer examination of different perspectives, we hoped to bring some clarity and nuance to what has often been a highly confusing situation.
And so … as we wrap up 2021, we thought we’d bring you an amalgam of our best Covid content. Our host John Donvan will walk you through the ups and downs of this pandemic, guiding you through the depths of what remain highly contentious policies and decisions that continue to affect virtually all of us. And so … from all of us at Open to Debate, we hope you enjoy it. Happy holidays.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/y0EXcU8A-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/y0EXcU8A-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Thomas Cueni</strong><br>Thomas Cueni is Director General of IFPMA, the global association of pharmaceutical research companies, based in Geneva, and Secretary of the Global Biopharmaceutical CEO Roundtable (BCR). In this capacity, Thomas Cueni was instrumental in creating the AMR Action Fund, a collective venture launched in July 2020 to bridge the current gap in funding for the development of new antibiotics. Thomas Cueni represents the innovative biopharmaceutical industry on the ACT Accelerator, the Access to COVID-19 Tools (ACT) Accelerator, a unique global collaboration to accelerate development, production, and equitable access to COVID-19 tests, treatments, and vaccines. Thomas Cueni is Chair of the Business Committee at the OECD Health Committee and also serves on the Board of Directors of the City Cancer Challenge (CCan), an initiative aiming to improve cancer care in major cities in low- and middle-income countries. Cueni also serves as industry co-chair of the APEC Biopharmaceutical WG on Ethics. Furthermore, he is Chair of the Board of the cross-sectoral AMR Industry Alliance, a group committed to tackling the threat of antimicrobial resistance that includes more than 100 companies and associations representing Rx pharma, generics, biotech, and diagnostics. Prior to joining IFPMA, he was Secretary General of Interpharma, the association of pharmaceutical research companies in Switzerland, and for many years was a member of the Board and Chair of a key committee of the EFPIA. Prior to his appointment with Interpharma, Thomas Cueni had a career as a journalist, inter alia as a London correspondent for the "Basler Zeitung" and "Der Bund", and he served as a Swiss career diplomat with postings in Paris (OECD) and Vienna (IAEA, UNIDO). He studied at the University of Basel, the London School of Economics, and the Geneva Graduate Institute for International Studies and has Master's degrees in economics (University of Basel) and politics (London School of Economics).</p>
<p><strong>Brook Baker</strong><br>Professor Baker teaches disability discrimination law, negotiations, and a new course on human rights, intellectual property, and access to medicines. He taught and consulted in South African law schools and law school clinics between 1997 and 2012. Professor Baker is an honorary research fellow at the University of KwaZulu Natal in Durban, South Africa.
Professor Baker is also a senior policy analyst for Health GAP (Global Access Project) and is actively engaged in campaigns for universal access to treatment, prevention, and care for people living with HIV/AIDS, especially expanded and improved medical treatment. More recently, he has been working on accelerating research on and equitable global access to vaccines, medicines, and diagnostics to respond to the COVID-19 pandemic. He has written and consulted extensively on intellectual property rights, trade, investor-state dispute settlement, access to medicines, and medicines regulatory policy, including with the African Union, NEPAD, South Africa, Uganda, ASEAN, Thailand, Indonesia, Brazil, Venezuela, CARICOM, UK DfID, the World Health Organization, the Millennium Development Goals Project, the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis, and Malaria, the Open Society Institute, UNAIDS, UNDP, Unitaid, the Medicines Patent Pool, the Global Commission on HIV and the Law, and others. He has served as a key alternative board member and board member of the NGO delegation to Unitaid, which acts to improve market dynamics and early market entry of medicines and diagnostics needed to address HIV/AIDS, TB, Hepatitis C, and malaria.
He is presently a civil society representative to the Therapeutics Pillar of the Access to COVID-19 Tools Accelerator. Professor Baker also works on policy issues concerning the Global Fund and the US PEPFAR Program and how those priority disease initiatives might contribute more broadly to improving health care delivery in developing countries. Finally, he analyzes resource needs for global health, innovative financing mechanisms, and IMF macroeconomic policies that restrict increased government and donor spending on health and education in developing countries.</p>
<p><strong>Lawrence Gostin</strong><br>Lawrence O. Gostin is University Professor, Georgetown University’s highest academic rank conferred by the University President. Prof. Gostin directs the O’Neill Institute for National and Global Health Law and is the Founding O’Neill Chair in Global Health Law. He served as Associate Dean for Research at Georgetown Law from 2004 to 2008. He is Professor of Medicine at Georgetown University and Professor of Public Health at the Johns Hopkins University. Prof. Gostin is the Director of the World Health Organization Collaborating Center on National and Global Health Law. The WHO Director-General has appointed Prof. Gostin to high-level positions, including the International Health Regulations (IHR) Roster of Experts and the Expert Advisory Panel on Mental Health.</p>
<p><strong>Larry Brilliant</strong><br>Dr. Larry Brilliant is a physician and epidemiologist, a proud member of the TED community, CEO of Pandefense Advisory, and Chair of the Advisory Board of the NGO Ending Pandemics. He is a senior advisor to Jeff Skoll and serves on the board of the Skoll Foundation. Previously, he was president and CEO of the Skoll Global Threats Fund, vice president of Google, and the founding executive director of Google.org. He also cofounded the Seva Foundation, an NGO whose programs have given sight back to more than five million blind people in two dozen countries. He also cofounded The Well, a progenitor of today's social media platforms. Earlier in his career, Brilliant was a professor of epidemiology and international health planning at the University of Michigan.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Peter Baldwin</strong><br>Peter Baldwin is especially interested in the historical development of the modern state—a broad field that has led him in many different directions. Two aspects of his work unify it. First, he has attempted to understand contemporary issues from a long historical perspective, whether that be the class coalitions that cemented the modern welfare state, the 19th century public health strategies that provided the template by which the AIDS epidemic was fought a century later, the battles over intellectual property stretching back three centuries that inform, indeed determine, our current battles over copyright, downloading, and internet piracy, or the ever-growing role of law as the socializer of last resort in modern society. Second, he has studied the development of the state transnationally, using detailed and often archival sources in half a dozen languages to marry a broad comparative approach to rigorous empiricism. His books have dealt, above all, with France, Germany, Britain, Sweden, Denmark, and the United States. He has published works on the comparative history of the welfare state, on social policy more broadly, on public health, and on the history of copyright. Other interests have included Nazi Germany and historiography. His latest book is a global history of the development of law and crime over the past 2000 years. He has forthcoming books on open access and on the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p><strong>Michael J. Anderson</strong><br>Michael is an experienced litigator with expertise in numerous practice areas, including real estate, business, employment, construction, environmental, landlord-tenant, municipal, family, criminal, and insurance coverage and defense. Prior to going solo in early 2012, he spent nearly seven years as an integral part of the complex commercial litigation division of a well-respected, mid-sized Milwaukee business law firm. Before that, he specialized in insurance coverage and insurance defense litigation.</p>
<p><strong>Jay Stanley</strong><br>Jay Stanley is a senior policy analyst with the ACLU Speech, Privacy, and Technology Project, where he researches, writes, and speaks about technology-related privacy and civil liberties issues and their future. He is the editor of the ACLU’s Free Future blog and has authored and co-authored a variety of influential ACLU reports on privacy and technology topics. Before joining the ACLU, he was an analyst at the technology research firm Forrester, served as American politics editor of Facts on File’s World News Digest, and was national newswire editor at Medialink. He is a graduate of Williams College and holds an M.A. in American history from the University of Virginia.</p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> December 22, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Health</p>
<p>Two years ago in January, the Covid-19 virus made its way to American shores. (Or at least that is when the CDC confirmed the first U.S. case) In many ways, the world was a different place back then. President Trump was still in office. The word “pandemic” hadn’t quite assumed the gravity it would. And phrases like “flatten the curve,” “doomscrolling,” and “you’re on mute” hadn’t yet become so utterly ubiquitous. But in the midst of the resulting panic, Open to Debate made a commitment to keep debate alive – particularly the kinds of competing ideas that would remain outside the ensuing onslaught of misinformation. We brought in expert interviewees and those who could bring a historical perspective to the unfolding melee. And as the first vaccines surfaced, we debated mandates, pharmaceutical patents, and which groups should receive priority. Through these platforms, and through a closer examination of different perspectives, we hoped to bring some clarity and nuance to what has often been a highly confusing situation.
And so … as we wrap up 2021, we thought we’d bring you an amalgam of our best Covid content. Our host John Donvan will walk you through the ups and downs of this pandemic, guiding you through the depths of what remain highly contentious policies and decisions that continue to affect virtually all of us. And so … from all of us at Open to Debate, we hope you enjoy it. Happy holidays.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/y0EXcU8A-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/y0EXcU8A-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Thomas Cueni</strong><br>Thomas Cueni is Director General of IFPMA, the global association of pharmaceutical research companies, based in Geneva, and Secretary of the Global Biopharmaceutical CEO Roundtable (BCR). In this capacity, Thomas Cueni was instrumental in creating the AMR Action Fund, a collective venture launched in July 2020 to bridge the current gap in funding for the development of new antibiotics. Thomas Cueni represents the innovative biopharmaceutical industry on the ACT Accelerator, the Access to COVID-19 Tools (ACT) Accelerator, a unique global collaboration to accelerate development, production, and equitable access to COVID-19 tests, treatments, and vaccines. Thomas Cueni is Chair of the Business Committee at the OECD Health Committee and also serves on the Board of Directors of the City Cancer Challenge (CCan), an initiative aiming to improve cancer care in major cities in low- and middle-income countries. Cueni also serves as industry co-chair of the APEC Biopharmaceutical WG on Ethics. Furthermore, he is Chair of the Board of the cross-sectoral AMR Industry Alliance, a group committed to tackling the threat of antimicrobial resistance that includes more than 100 companies and associations representing Rx pharma, generics, biotech, and diagnostics. Prior to joining IFPMA, he was Secretary General of Interpharma, the association of pharmaceutical research companies in Switzerland, and for many years was a member of the Board and Chair of a key committee of the EFPIA. Prior to his appointment with Interpharma, Thomas Cueni had a career as a journalist, inter alia as a London correspondent for the "Basler Zeitung" and "Der Bund", and he served as a Swiss career diplomat with postings in Paris (OECD) and Vienna (IAEA, UNIDO). He studied at the University of Basel, the London School of Economics, and the Geneva Graduate Institute for International Studies and has Master's degrees in economics (University of Basel) and politics (London School of Economics).</p>
<p><strong>Brook Baker</strong><br>Professor Baker teaches disability discrimination law, negotiations, and a new course on human rights, intellectual property, and access to medicines. He taught and consulted in South African law schools and law school clinics between 1997 and 2012. Professor Baker is an honorary research fellow at the University of KwaZulu Natal in Durban, South Africa.
Professor Baker is also a senior policy analyst for Health GAP (Global Access Project) and is actively engaged in campaigns for universal access to treatment, prevention, and care for people living with HIV/AIDS, especially expanded and improved medical treatment. More recently, he has been working on accelerating research on and equitable global access to vaccines, medicines, and diagnostics to respond to the COVID-19 pandemic. He has written and consulted extensively on intellectual property rights, trade, investor-state dispute settlement, access to medicines, and medicines regulatory policy, including with the African Union, NEPAD, South Africa, Uganda, ASEAN, Thailand, Indonesia, Brazil, Venezuela, CARICOM, UK DfID, the World Health Organization, the Millennium Development Goals Project, the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis, and Malaria, the Open Society Institute, UNAIDS, UNDP, Unitaid, the Medicines Patent Pool, the Global Commission on HIV and the Law, and others. He has served as a key alternative board member and board member of the NGO delegation to Unitaid, which acts to improve market dynamics and early market entry of medicines and diagnostics needed to address HIV/AIDS, TB, Hepatitis C, and malaria.
He is presently a civil society representative to the Therapeutics Pillar of the Access to COVID-19 Tools Accelerator. Professor Baker also works on policy issues concerning the Global Fund and the US PEPFAR Program and how those priority disease initiatives might contribute more broadly to improving health care delivery in developing countries. Finally, he analyzes resource needs for global health, innovative financing mechanisms, and IMF macroeconomic policies that restrict increased government and donor spending on health and education in developing countries.</p>
<p><strong>Lawrence Gostin</strong><br>Lawrence O. Gostin is University Professor, Georgetown University’s highest academic rank conferred by the University President. Prof. Gostin directs the O’Neill Institute for National and Global Health Law and is the Founding O’Neill Chair in Global Health Law. He served as Associate Dean for Research at Georgetown Law from 2004 to 2008. He is Professor of Medicine at Georgetown University and Professor of Public Health at the Johns Hopkins University. Prof. Gostin is the Director of the World Health Organization Collaborating Center on National and Global Health Law. The WHO Director-General has appointed Prof. Gostin to high-level positions, including the International Health Regulations (IHR) Roster of Experts and the Expert Advisory Panel on Mental Health.</p>
<p><strong>Larry Brilliant</strong><br>Dr. Larry Brilliant is a physician and epidemiologist, a proud member of the TED community, CEO of Pandefense Advisory, and Chair of the Advisory Board of the NGO Ending Pandemics. He is a senior advisor to Jeff Skoll and serves on the board of the Skoll Foundation. Previously, he was president and CEO of the Skoll Global Threats Fund, vice president of Google, and the founding executive director of Google.org. He also cofounded the Seva Foundation, an NGO whose programs have given sight back to more than five million blind people in two dozen countries. He also cofounded The Well, a progenitor of today's social media platforms. Earlier in his career, Brilliant was a professor of epidemiology and international health planning at the University of Michigan.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Peter Baldwin</strong><br>Peter Baldwin is especially interested in the historical development of the modern state—a broad field that has led him in many different directions. Two aspects of his work unify it. First, he has attempted to understand contemporary issues from a long historical perspective, whether that be the class coalitions that cemented the modern welfare state, the 19th century public health strategies that provided the template by which the AIDS epidemic was fought a century later, the battles over intellectual property stretching back three centuries that inform, indeed determine, our current battles over copyright, downloading, and internet piracy, or the ever-growing role of law as the socializer of last resort in modern society. Second, he has studied the development of the state transnationally, using detailed and often archival sources in half a dozen languages to marry a broad comparative approach to rigorous empiricism. His books have dealt, above all, with France, Germany, Britain, Sweden, Denmark, and the United States. He has published works on the comparative history of the welfare state, on social policy more broadly, on public health, and on the history of copyright. Other interests have included Nazi Germany and historiography. His latest book is a global history of the development of law and crime over the past 2000 years. He has forthcoming books on open access and on the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p><strong>Michael J. Anderson</strong><br>Michael is an experienced litigator with expertise in numerous practice areas, including real estate, business, employment, construction, environmental, landlord-tenant, municipal, family, criminal, and insurance coverage and defense. Prior to going solo in early 2012, he spent nearly seven years as an integral part of the complex commercial litigation division of a well-respected, mid-sized Milwaukee business law firm. Before that, he specialized in insurance coverage and insurance defense litigation.</p>
<p><strong>Jay Stanley</strong><br>Jay Stanley is a senior policy analyst with the ACLU Speech, Privacy, and Technology Project, where he researches, writes, and speaks about technology-related privacy and civil liberties issues and their future. He is the editor of the ACLU’s Free Future blog and has authored and co-authored a variety of influential ACLU reports on privacy and technology topics. Before joining the ACLU, he was an analyst at the technology research firm Forrester, served as American politics editor of Facts on File’s World News Digest, and was national newswire editor at Medialink. He is a graduate of Williams College and holds an M.A. in American history from the University of Virginia.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Is Amazon Good for Small Business?</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/amazon-good-small-business</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:9988</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> December 08, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Culture, Economics</p>
<p>Amazon has come a long way since online book sales. In fact, when it comes to revenue, Jeff Bezos’ creation is the world’s biggest internet-based company. But what makes the "everything store" so ubiquitous? In large part, it’s the small and medium-sized businesses that use the platform to sell their goods. This year, more than 1.9 million of these businesses participated in its marketplace, which accounted for some 60 percent of Amazon's retail sales. But was it ultimately good for them? On one hand, Amazon opens up a truly global market to smaller retailers. It also offers massive logistics support — such as processing payments, storing inventory, and shipping. But on the other, the tech giant's immense market power makes it a gatekeeper between retailers and consumers. That often means hefty fees for prime placement or what some sellers complain are the costs of superfluous services. Critics also rail against Amazon’s use of its own private label brands that can be weaponized to undermine competitors. In the midst of this historic transition in shopping, we ask: Is Amazon good for small business?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/nCiqOwkE-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/nCiqOwkE-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Mark Jamison</strong><br>Mark Jamison is a nonresident senior fellow at the American Enterprise Institute, where he works on how technology affects the economy and on telecommunications and Federal Communications Commission issues. He has served on the FCC transition team for President-elect Trump, as a special adviser to the chair of the governor of Florida’s internet task force, and as president of the Transportation and Public Utilities Group. He is the author of several books and publications on technology and policy and is currently a professor at the University of Florida.</p>
<p><strong>Kunal Chopra</strong><br>Kunal Chopra is a technology and business executive who has spent decades working at the forefront of e-commerce. Kunal has held several leadership positions in the tech sector, including as a general manager for Amazon Fashion and Microsoft and director of product for Groupon. He is currently the CEO of Kaspien, a company that provides software and services for e-commerce. Kunal is a frequent media commentator and a member of the Forbes Technology Council.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rana Foroohar</strong><br>Rana Foroohar is a widely celebrated author and commentator on the economy, technology, and business. She is a columnist for the Financial Times and a global economic analyst for CNN. Rana’s first book, "Makers and Takers,” explored why capital markets no longer support business and was shortlisted for the Financial Times McKinsey Book of the Year award. Her latest, "Don't Be Evil: How Big Tech Betrayed Its Founding Principles — And All Of Us," "presents a sweeping indictment of technology companies and their reach into every aspect of our lives," according to The New York Times.</p>
<p><strong>Stacy Mitchell</strong><br>Stacy Mitchell is one of the leading strategists working on issues related to Amazon, e-commerce, and small business in America today. A historian by training, Stacy writes frequently on Amazon for media and academic journals alike. She is co-director of the Institute for Local Self-Reliance, a national research and advocacy organization. In 2020, Stacy was profiled in the New York Times for her analysis of Amazon’s power and her leadership in building a broad coalition to challenge it.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Amazon Is Good for Small Business</em></p>
<p><u>Background and History</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Amazon During the Pandemic</u></p>
<p><u>Government Action</u></p>
<p><u>How Third-Party Selling Works</u></p>
<p><u>Fighting Against Amazon's Dominance</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> December 08, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Culture, Economics</p>
<p>Amazon has come a long way since online book sales. In fact, when it comes to revenue, Jeff Bezos’ creation is the world’s biggest internet-based company. But what makes the "everything store" so ubiquitous? In large part, it’s the small and medium-sized businesses that use the platform to sell their goods. This year, more than 1.9 million of these businesses participated in its marketplace, which accounted for some 60 percent of Amazon's retail sales. But was it ultimately good for them? On one hand, Amazon opens up a truly global market to smaller retailers. It also offers massive logistics support — such as processing payments, storing inventory, and shipping. But on the other, the tech giant's immense market power makes it a gatekeeper between retailers and consumers. That often means hefty fees for prime placement or what some sellers complain are the costs of superfluous services. Critics also rail against Amazon’s use of its own private label brands that can be weaponized to undermine competitors. In the midst of this historic transition in shopping, we ask: Is Amazon good for small business?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/nCiqOwkE-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/nCiqOwkE-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Mark Jamison</strong><br>Mark Jamison is a nonresident senior fellow at the American Enterprise Institute, where he works on how technology affects the economy and on telecommunications and Federal Communications Commission issues. He has served on the FCC transition team for President-elect Trump, as a special adviser to the chair of the governor of Florida’s internet task force, and as president of the Transportation and Public Utilities Group. He is the author of several books and publications on technology and policy and is currently a professor at the University of Florida.</p>
<p><strong>Kunal Chopra</strong><br>Kunal Chopra is a technology and business executive who has spent decades working at the forefront of e-commerce. Kunal has held several leadership positions in the tech sector, including as a general manager for Amazon Fashion and Microsoft and director of product for Groupon. He is currently the CEO of Kaspien, a company that provides software and services for e-commerce. Kunal is a frequent media commentator and a member of the Forbes Technology Council.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rana Foroohar</strong><br>Rana Foroohar is a widely celebrated author and commentator on the economy, technology, and business. She is a columnist for the Financial Times and a global economic analyst for CNN. Rana’s first book, "Makers and Takers,” explored why capital markets no longer support business and was shortlisted for the Financial Times McKinsey Book of the Year award. Her latest, "Don't Be Evil: How Big Tech Betrayed Its Founding Principles — And All Of Us," "presents a sweeping indictment of technology companies and their reach into every aspect of our lives," according to The New York Times.</p>
<p><strong>Stacy Mitchell</strong><br>Stacy Mitchell is one of the leading strategists working on issues related to Amazon, e-commerce, and small business in America today. A historian by training, Stacy writes frequently on Amazon for media and academic journals alike. She is co-director of the Institute for Local Self-Reliance, a national research and advocacy organization. In 2020, Stacy was profiled in the New York Times for her analysis of Amazon’s power and her leadership in building a broad coalition to challenge it.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Amazon Is Good for Small Business</em></p>
<p><u>Background and History</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Amazon During the Pandemic</u></p>
<p><u>Government Action</u></p>
<p><u>How Third-Party Selling Works</u></p>
<p><u>Fighting Against Amazon's Dominance</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Agree to Disagree: Is Meritocracy Overrated?</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/agree-disagree-meritocracy-overrated</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:9969</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> November 26, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Culture</p>
<p>The days of kings and queens are largely over. That old hereditary lottery, at least within many democracies, has effectively been replaced by a system in which talent, grit, and ability are meant to set the terms of success. To quote Michael Shaara’s famous Civil War novel, The Killer Angels, “Here we judge you by what you do, not by what your father was.” And yet with income inequality on the rise, and amidst a pernicious and lingering legacy of slavery and racism, new questions are cropping up as to whether meritocracy itself is mere illusion. Those who say “yes” point to examples of wealth transfers within families, and networks that pave the way for lucrative jobs and fancy educations. Those who say “no” argue that not only does talent ultimately win out, but that despite its flaws, meritocratic systems remain the most effective way of lifting disenfranchised groups from obscurity. In this context, we debate the question: “Is Meritocracy Overrated?”</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/lfS7OaL4-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/lfS7OaL4-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Daniel Markovits</strong><br>Daniel Markovits is a Guido Calabresi professor of law at Yale and the founding director of the Center for the Study of Private Law. Markovits works on the philosophical foundations of private law, moral and political philosophy, and behavioral economics. He publishes in a range of disciplines, including Science, The American Economic Review, and The Yale Law Journal. Markovits’s current book, "The Meritocracy Trap," places meritocracy at the center of rising economic inequality and social and political dysfunction. The book takes up the law, economics, and politics of human capital to identify the mechanisms through which meritocracy breeds inequality and expose the burdens that meritocratic inequality imposes on all who fall within meritocracy’s orbit.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Adrian Wooldridge</strong><br>Adrian Wooldridge is The Economist‘s political editor and writes the Bagehot column, an analysis of British life and politics in the tradition of Walter Bagehot, editor of The Economist from 1861–77. Adrian also used to write the Schumpeter column on business, finance, and management. He was previously based in Washington, DC, as the Washington bureau chief, where he also wrote the Lexington column. Prior to his role in Washington, he was The Economist‘s west coast correspondent, management correspondent, and Britain correspondent. He is the co-author of "The Company: A Short History of a Revolutionary Idea", "A Future Perfect: The Challenge and Hidden Promise of Globalization,", "Witch Doctors", a critical examination of management theory, and "The Right Nation", a study of conservatism in America. His most recent books are "The Great Disruption: How Business Is Coping With Turbulent Times" (2015) and "Masters of Management: How the Business Gurus and Their Ideas Have Changed the World—for Better and for Worse" (2011).</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Agree to Disagree: Is Meritocracy Overrated?</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> November 26, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Culture</p>
<p>The days of kings and queens are largely over. That old hereditary lottery, at least within many democracies, has effectively been replaced by a system in which talent, grit, and ability are meant to set the terms of success. To quote Michael Shaara’s famous Civil War novel, The Killer Angels, “Here we judge you by what you do, not by what your father was.” And yet with income inequality on the rise, and amidst a pernicious and lingering legacy of slavery and racism, new questions are cropping up as to whether meritocracy itself is mere illusion. Those who say “yes” point to examples of wealth transfers within families, and networks that pave the way for lucrative jobs and fancy educations. Those who say “no” argue that not only does talent ultimately win out, but that despite its flaws, meritocratic systems remain the most effective way of lifting disenfranchised groups from obscurity. In this context, we debate the question: “Is Meritocracy Overrated?”</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/lfS7OaL4-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/lfS7OaL4-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Daniel Markovits</strong><br>Daniel Markovits is a Guido Calabresi professor of law at Yale and the founding director of the Center for the Study of Private Law. Markovits works on the philosophical foundations of private law, moral and political philosophy, and behavioral economics. He publishes in a range of disciplines, including Science, The American Economic Review, and The Yale Law Journal. Markovits’s current book, "The Meritocracy Trap," places meritocracy at the center of rising economic inequality and social and political dysfunction. The book takes up the law, economics, and politics of human capital to identify the mechanisms through which meritocracy breeds inequality and expose the burdens that meritocratic inequality imposes on all who fall within meritocracy’s orbit.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Adrian Wooldridge</strong><br>Adrian Wooldridge is The Economist‘s political editor and writes the Bagehot column, an analysis of British life and politics in the tradition of Walter Bagehot, editor of The Economist from 1861–77. Adrian also used to write the Schumpeter column on business, finance, and management. He was previously based in Washington, DC, as the Washington bureau chief, where he also wrote the Lexington column. Prior to his role in Washington, he was The Economist‘s west coast correspondent, management correspondent, and Britain correspondent. He is the co-author of "The Company: A Short History of a Revolutionary Idea", "A Future Perfect: The Challenge and Hidden Promise of Globalization,", "Witch Doctors", a critical examination of management theory, and "The Right Nation", a study of conservatism in America. His most recent books are "The Great Disruption: How Business Is Coping With Turbulent Times" (2015) and "Masters of Management: How the Business Gurus and Their Ideas Have Changed the World—for Better and for Worse" (2011).</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Agree to Disagree: Is Meritocracy Overrated?</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Cancel Culture Is Toxic</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/cancel-culture-toxic</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10041</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> November 09, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Culture, U.S.</p>
<p>You know the drill. Someone does, or says, something offensive. A public backlash -- typically on Twitter -- ensues. Then come the calls to "cancel" that person, brand, or institution. That usually means the loss of cultural cache, political clout, and often a job or career. While the term "cancelling" has roots in a misogynistic joke, it has come to be one of the most prominent tools of progressive activists. Many see "cancelling" as a modern-day means of holding people to account, calling out injustice, and breaking down ingrained systems of prejudice and exploitation, particularly for the historically marginalized. But others see it differently. They are sounding alarms about the emergence of a new cancel culture where digital mobs police our speech, invade our rights, and even put our physical safety at risk. They argue that cancel culture has created a society ruled by online censorship and eroded our public discourse. Against this backdrop, we ask: Is cancel culture toxic?
<div class="elfsight-app-1569f9f2-c1a5-421c-a728-830e33f82f6f"></div></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/cfOy0mAg-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/cfOy0mAg-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Kmele Foster</strong><br>Kmele Foster is a media entrepreneur and political commentator. He is the co-host of "The Fifth Column" podcast and the co-founder and executive producer of the media company Freethink. Foster was one of the signatories of the Harper's Letter on justice and open debate, alongside more than 150 people, including Salman Rushdie, J.K. Rowling, and Noam Chomsky. He is an outspoken libertarian critic of cancel culture, the Black Lives Matter movement, and political orthodoxy.</p>
<p><strong>Garry Kasparov</strong><br><span class="TextRun BCX0 SCXO128278720" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun BCX0 SCXO128278720">Garry Kasparov rose to international fame in 1985 as the youngest world chess champion in history. He was 22 at the time and is widely considered among history’s greatest chess players. In 2005, Kasparov retired from the sport to devote his time to writing and human rights activism. He is currently chairman of the Human Rights Foundation, a nonprofit that promotes human rights globally and organizes the Oslo Freedom Forum, and chairman of the Renew Democracy Initiative, dedicated to global democracy. He is a frequent contributor to major international publications, including The Wall Street Journal and The New York Times.</span></span></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Erich Hatala Matthes</strong><br>Erich Hatala Matthes is a scholar and philosophy professor who researches the ethics, politics, and aesthetics of cultural heritage and art. Erich has published on topics related to cultural appropriation, art repatriation, and the ethics of cultural heritage. He is currently an associate professor at Wellesley College, and his first book, "Drawing the Line: What to Do with the Work of Immoral Artists from Museums to the Movies", was released this year.</p>
<p><strong>Karen Attiah</strong><br>Karen Attiah is a Washington Post columnist who writes on issues related to race, international politics, gender, and human rights. As the Post's founding Global Opinions editor, she recruited writers from around the world and won several awards for her work in seeking accountability for the murder of columnist Jamal Khashoggi, including the 2019 George Polk Special Award and the 2019 Journalist of the Year award from the National Association of Black Journalists. She is the author of "Say Your Word, Then Leave" and was a Fulbright Scholar to Ghana.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Workin’ for the Weekend #12: Stelter Fired, Moynihan on FIRE, Kmele Gonna Take You Higher</strong> <small>2023-02-07 22:32:53</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>When it comes to thinking about race and identity, Kmele is something of a radical, though not in the way that many “antiracist” ideologues consider themselves radicals. As you’ll see below in this transcript of my appearance with John on The Fifth Column, Kmele rejects race as a category that need have any bearing on an individual’s self-conception.</p>
<p>I find Kmele’s way of thinking about these matters intriguing, though I have to admit I worry that he’s throwing the baby out with the bathwater. In Tuesday’s post (https://glennloury.substack.com/p/is-the-bipoc-coalition-coming-apart), I argued while we should not allow ourselves to become prisoners to socially legislated identities, neither should we discard communal traditions from which we may draw sustenance and strength. Kmele says he doesn’t think it valid to feel personal pride or shame about even our parents’ and grandparents’ actions, whereas I confess that there are many aspects of my own black heritage of which I am quite proud.</p>
<p>These are deep disagreements but productive ones. We need radical thinkers like Kmele who take up positions that cut against the orthodoxies of both right and left.
* In other Kmele news, Adweek awarded (https://twitter.com/IQ2US/status/1559931446122500098) an Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. debate (https://opentodebate.org/debate/cancel-culture-toxic/#/) on cancel culture that the Freethinker participated in as its “Best Podcast Event of 2022 (https://www.adweek.com/media/see-all-the-2022-adweek-podcast-of-the-year-awards-winners/)”:</p>
<p>To shed light on a topic commanding the zeitgeist, Intelligence Squared US Debates provided a platform for healthy debate on cancel culture and the impact it may have in dividing Americans across the country at its November 2021 event. Reaching more than 200,000 unique listeners, the live event brought together widely respected thinkers who didn’t simply pander to partisan allegiances, but endeavored to share their point of view in hopes of arriving at a clearer understanding of the phenomenon.</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Cancel Culture Is Toxic</em></p>
<p><u>Background and History</u></p>
<p><u>'The Letter' and Responses</u></p>
<p><u>Prominent Examples</u></p>
<p><u>Dealing With Cancelation</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Reality of Cancel Culture</u></p>
<p><u>Cancel Culture and the Internet</u></p>
<p><u>Stars, Studies, and Academic</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> November 09, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Culture, U.S.</p>
<p>You know the drill. Someone does, or says, something offensive. A public backlash -- typically on Twitter -- ensues. Then come the calls to "cancel" that person, brand, or institution. That usually means the loss of cultural cache, political clout, and often a job or career. While the term "cancelling" has roots in a misogynistic joke, it has come to be one of the most prominent tools of progressive activists. Many see "cancelling" as a modern-day means of holding people to account, calling out injustice, and breaking down ingrained systems of prejudice and exploitation, particularly for the historically marginalized. But others see it differently. They are sounding alarms about the emergence of a new cancel culture where digital mobs police our speech, invade our rights, and even put our physical safety at risk. They argue that cancel culture has created a society ruled by online censorship and eroded our public discourse. Against this backdrop, we ask: Is cancel culture toxic?
<div class="elfsight-app-1569f9f2-c1a5-421c-a728-830e33f82f6f"></div></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/cfOy0mAg-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/cfOy0mAg-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Kmele Foster</strong><br>Kmele Foster is a media entrepreneur and political commentator. He is the co-host of "The Fifth Column" podcast and the co-founder and executive producer of the media company Freethink. Foster was one of the signatories of the Harper's Letter on justice and open debate, alongside more than 150 people, including Salman Rushdie, J.K. Rowling, and Noam Chomsky. He is an outspoken libertarian critic of cancel culture, the Black Lives Matter movement, and political orthodoxy.</p>
<p><strong>Garry Kasparov</strong><br><span class="TextRun BCX0 SCXO128278720" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun BCX0 SCXO128278720">Garry Kasparov rose to international fame in 1985 as the youngest world chess champion in history. He was 22 at the time and is widely considered among history’s greatest chess players. In 2005, Kasparov retired from the sport to devote his time to writing and human rights activism. He is currently chairman of the Human Rights Foundation, a nonprofit that promotes human rights globally and organizes the Oslo Freedom Forum, and chairman of the Renew Democracy Initiative, dedicated to global democracy. He is a frequent contributor to major international publications, including The Wall Street Journal and The New York Times.</span></span></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Erich Hatala Matthes</strong><br>Erich Hatala Matthes is a scholar and philosophy professor who researches the ethics, politics, and aesthetics of cultural heritage and art. Erich has published on topics related to cultural appropriation, art repatriation, and the ethics of cultural heritage. He is currently an associate professor at Wellesley College, and his first book, "Drawing the Line: What to Do with the Work of Immoral Artists from Museums to the Movies", was released this year.</p>
<p><strong>Karen Attiah</strong><br>Karen Attiah is a Washington Post columnist who writes on issues related to race, international politics, gender, and human rights. As the Post's founding Global Opinions editor, she recruited writers from around the world and won several awards for her work in seeking accountability for the murder of columnist Jamal Khashoggi, including the 2019 George Polk Special Award and the 2019 Journalist of the Year award from the National Association of Black Journalists. She is the author of "Say Your Word, Then Leave" and was a Fulbright Scholar to Ghana.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Workin’ for the Weekend #12: Stelter Fired, Moynihan on FIRE, Kmele Gonna Take You Higher</strong> <small>2023-02-07 22:32:53</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>When it comes to thinking about race and identity, Kmele is something of a radical, though not in the way that many “antiracist” ideologues consider themselves radicals. As you’ll see below in this transcript of my appearance with John on The Fifth Column, Kmele rejects race as a category that need have any bearing on an individual’s self-conception.</p>
<p>I find Kmele’s way of thinking about these matters intriguing, though I have to admit I worry that he’s throwing the baby out with the bathwater. In Tuesday’s post (https://glennloury.substack.com/p/is-the-bipoc-coalition-coming-apart), I argued while we should not allow ourselves to become prisoners to socially legislated identities, neither should we discard communal traditions from which we may draw sustenance and strength. Kmele says he doesn’t think it valid to feel personal pride or shame about even our parents’ and grandparents’ actions, whereas I confess that there are many aspects of my own black heritage of which I am quite proud.</p>
<p>These are deep disagreements but productive ones. We need radical thinkers like Kmele who take up positions that cut against the orthodoxies of both right and left.
* In other Kmele news, Adweek awarded (https://twitter.com/IQ2US/status/1559931446122500098) an Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. debate (https://opentodebate.org/debate/cancel-culture-toxic/#/) on cancel culture that the Freethinker participated in as its “Best Podcast Event of 2022 (https://www.adweek.com/media/see-all-the-2022-adweek-podcast-of-the-year-awards-winners/)”:</p>
<p>To shed light on a topic commanding the zeitgeist, Intelligence Squared US Debates provided a platform for healthy debate on cancel culture and the impact it may have in dividing Americans across the country at its November 2021 event. Reaching more than 200,000 unique listeners, the live event brought together widely respected thinkers who didn’t simply pander to partisan allegiances, but endeavored to share their point of view in hopes of arriving at a clearer understanding of the phenomenon.</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Cancel Culture Is Toxic</em></p>
<p><u>Background and History</u></p>
<p><u>'The Letter' and Responses</u></p>
<p><u>Prominent Examples</u></p>
<p><u>Dealing With Cancelation</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Reality of Cancel Culture</u></p>
<p><u>Cancel Culture and the Internet</u></p>
<p><u>Stars, Studies, and Academic</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Agree to Disagree COVID Series: Are Booster Shots Unethical?</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/agree-disagree-covid-series-are-booster-shots-unethical</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:9952</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> October 29, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Health, Law, Science, World</p>
<p>The boosters are rolling out. In places likes the U.S., Britain, Israel, Germany and France, authorities are providing additional Covid-19 vaccines with the goal of bolstering immune systems and shoring up their economies. Though vaccines such as Moderna and Pfizer-BioNTech have proven highly effective against the virus, efficacy wanes after six months, rendering older adults and those with weakened immune systems more vulnerable. Yet a debate about fairness is growing. Billions of people haven gotten at least one dose of the Covid-19 vaccine, though much of the planet remains unvaccinated, beleaguered by lingering scarcities and difficultly of transport. Offering booster shots to those who have already gotten their jabs is akin to “hand[ing] out extra life jackets to people who already have life jackets” while “leaving other people to drown," said World Health Organization Emergency Director Mike Ryan. Not so, say others. Places like the U.S. were not only global hotspots for the viral transmission, but they also remain as core threats to the global economy with the increased threat and spread of Covid variants. Though getting the rest of the globe vaccinated is critically important, it is unrealistic, they argue, for political leaders to ignore these threats to their own populations. In the context of this emerging divide, we ask the question: Are booster shots unethical?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/8nMdRiHp-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/8nMdRiHp-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Vin Gupta</strong><br>Gupta is a Harvard-trained lung specialist with more than 15 years of experience working worldwide to improve public health for organizations including the US Centers for Disease Control, the Institute for Health Metrics and Evaluation, the Harvard Global Health Institute, the World Health Organization, and the Pentagon's Center for Global Health Engagement. Given his diversity of experiences, he is now a trusted advisor and contributor to national and international media outlets on several of the most important health issues today, including serving as a regular health policy analyst for NBC News and a contributor to the New York Times and CNN New Day.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Leana Wen</strong><br>Dr. Leana Wen is an emergency physician and public health professor at George Washington University. Previously, she served as Baltimore's Health Commissioner. She’s a contributing columnist for the Washington Post and the author of the new book, "Lifelines: A Doctor’s Journey in the Fight for Public Health."</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Agree to Disagree COVID Series: Are Booster Shots Unethical?</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> October 29, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Health, Law, Science, World</p>
<p>The boosters are rolling out. In places likes the U.S., Britain, Israel, Germany and France, authorities are providing additional Covid-19 vaccines with the goal of bolstering immune systems and shoring up their economies. Though vaccines such as Moderna and Pfizer-BioNTech have proven highly effective against the virus, efficacy wanes after six months, rendering older adults and those with weakened immune systems more vulnerable. Yet a debate about fairness is growing. Billions of people haven gotten at least one dose of the Covid-19 vaccine, though much of the planet remains unvaccinated, beleaguered by lingering scarcities and difficultly of transport. Offering booster shots to those who have already gotten their jabs is akin to “hand[ing] out extra life jackets to people who already have life jackets” while “leaving other people to drown," said World Health Organization Emergency Director Mike Ryan. Not so, say others. Places like the U.S. were not only global hotspots for the viral transmission, but they also remain as core threats to the global economy with the increased threat and spread of Covid variants. Though getting the rest of the globe vaccinated is critically important, it is unrealistic, they argue, for political leaders to ignore these threats to their own populations. In the context of this emerging divide, we ask the question: Are booster shots unethical?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/8nMdRiHp-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/8nMdRiHp-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Vin Gupta</strong><br>Gupta is a Harvard-trained lung specialist with more than 15 years of experience working worldwide to improve public health for organizations including the US Centers for Disease Control, the Institute for Health Metrics and Evaluation, the Harvard Global Health Institute, the World Health Organization, and the Pentagon's Center for Global Health Engagement. Given his diversity of experiences, he is now a trusted advisor and contributor to national and international media outlets on several of the most important health issues today, including serving as a regular health policy analyst for NBC News and a contributor to the New York Times and CNN New Day.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Leana Wen</strong><br>Dr. Leana Wen is an emergency physician and public health professor at George Washington University. Previously, she served as Baltimore's Health Commissioner. She’s a contributing columnist for the Washington Post and the author of the new book, "Lifelines: A Doctor’s Journey in the Fight for Public Health."</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Agree to Disagree COVID Series: Are Booster Shots Unethical?</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Should Paying Hacker Ransoms Be Illegal?</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/should-paying-hacker-ransoms-be-illegal</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:9962</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> October 15, 2021</p>
<p>With cyber threats and ransomware on the rise globally, the Biden administration has enlisted America’s tech titans to help blunt their effects. Amazon, Microsoft, and Google, are all in discussions with Washington over how to strengthen the nation’s critical infrastructure defenses against a growing array of both private and state-sponsored attacks. Skeptics question just how much can be achieved, given how connected U.S. society has become. But solutions are emerging, from lifting the veil of cryptocurrencies, a favored transaction among hackers, to making the paying of ransoms illegal. In this special edition of Open to Debate's Agree-to-Disagree series, John Donvan sits down with David Sanger of The New York Times for a closer examination of these attacks before launching into a much more specific debate with two cyber security experts. The debate: Should paying hacker ransoms be made illegal? Cyber Threat Alliance president and chief executive Michael Daniel and Rapid7 vice-president Jen Ellis square off in light of recent high-profile hackings.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/jKn7Mpgm-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/jKn7Mpgm-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Michael Daniel</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO212281303 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto">Michael leads the Cyber Threat Alliance team, a group of cybersecurity practitioners from organizations that have chosen to work together, and oversees the organization’s operations. Prior to joining the CTA in February 2017, Michael served from June 2012 to January 2017 as Special Assistant to President Obama and Cybersecurity Coordinator on the National Security Council Staff. In this role, Michael led the development of national cybersecurity strategy and policy and ensured that the US government partnered with the private sector, non-governmental organizations, and other nations.</span></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Jen Ellis</strong><br>Jen Ellis is the vice president of community and public affairs at Rapid7, a leading cyber security company, and a nonresident senior fellow with the Atlantic Council’s Cyber Statecraft Initiative. She works extensively with security researchers, technology providers and operators, and various government entities to help them understand and address cybersecurity challenges. She has testified before the US Congress and spoken at various security or business events, including SXSW, RSA, DEF CON, and the National Association of Corporate Directors (NACD) Global Cyber Summit.</p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> October 15, 2021</p>
<p>With cyber threats and ransomware on the rise globally, the Biden administration has enlisted America’s tech titans to help blunt their effects. Amazon, Microsoft, and Google, are all in discussions with Washington over how to strengthen the nation’s critical infrastructure defenses against a growing array of both private and state-sponsored attacks. Skeptics question just how much can be achieved, given how connected U.S. society has become. But solutions are emerging, from lifting the veil of cryptocurrencies, a favored transaction among hackers, to making the paying of ransoms illegal. In this special edition of Open to Debate's Agree-to-Disagree series, John Donvan sits down with David Sanger of The New York Times for a closer examination of these attacks before launching into a much more specific debate with two cyber security experts. The debate: Should paying hacker ransoms be made illegal? Cyber Threat Alliance president and chief executive Michael Daniel and Rapid7 vice-president Jen Ellis square off in light of recent high-profile hackings.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/jKn7Mpgm-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/jKn7Mpgm-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Michael Daniel</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO212281303 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto">Michael leads the Cyber Threat Alliance team, a group of cybersecurity practitioners from organizations that have chosen to work together, and oversees the organization’s operations. Prior to joining the CTA in February 2017, Michael served from June 2012 to January 2017 as Special Assistant to President Obama and Cybersecurity Coordinator on the National Security Council Staff. In this role, Michael led the development of national cybersecurity strategy and policy and ensured that the US government partnered with the private sector, non-governmental organizations, and other nations.</span></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Jen Ellis</strong><br>Jen Ellis is the vice president of community and public affairs at Rapid7, a leading cyber security company, and a nonresident senior fellow with the Atlantic Council’s Cyber Statecraft Initiative. She works extensively with security researchers, technology providers and operators, and various government entities to help them understand and address cybersecurity challenges. She has testified before the US Congress and spoken at various security or business events, including SXSW, RSA, DEF CON, and the National Association of Corporate Directors (NACD) Global Cyber Summit.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>We Should Expand the Supreme Court</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/we-should-expand-supreme-court</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10284</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> September 30, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Law, Politics, U.S.</p>
<p>Right now, nine justices hold tremendous power in American law. It's been that way since Ulysses S. Grant first inhabited the White House. The Constitution is silent on just how many justices should sit on the nation's top bench, and in 1937 President Roosevelt tried to add a slew of new appointments that would be sympathetic to his New Deal programs. Congress didn't bite. Now, advocates on the left are eyeing the bench once again. They see a Supreme Court out of touch with the American electorate, obstructed by partisan interests, and rendered illegitimate by years of controversial appointments. But those opposed are sounding the alarms. A move to dramatically change one of the three core pillars of American government would ultimately undermine the court’s legitimacy. It’s not perfect, they argue. But the court has consistently shown its independence and should not be compromised as a result of partisan ambitions. So, in light of this emerging divide, Open to Debate, formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. in partnership with The Newt and Jo Minow Debate Series at Northwestern Pritzker School of Law asks this question: Is it okay to expand the court?
<div class="elfsight-app-3d359447-b932-4cca-80e9-ade6527e66f7"></div></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/U793ZoXz-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/U793ZoXz-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Dahlia Lithwick</strong><br>Dahlia Lithwick is one of the nation’s most prominent progressive legal commentators and Supreme Court analysts. She is a senior editor at Slate, where she has written her "Supreme Court Dispatches" and "Jurisprudence" columns since 1999 and is the host of the award-winning law podcast "Amicus." She holds a J.D. from Stanford University and is currently teaching a short course on the Supreme Court and Ruth Bader Ginsburg at the University of Virginia Law.</p>
<p><strong>Tamara Brummer</strong><br>Tamara Brummer serves as Senior Advisor and Director of National Outreach and Engagement for Demand Justice, one of the leading organizations advocating for court expansion and reform. Prior to this post, Tamara spent years as a political organizer and strategist, building meaningful and impactful relationships rooted in a shared vision of economic justice. This includes tenures across the labor movement, notably with the AFL-CIO and the International Union of Painters and Allied Trades.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Akhil Reed Amar</strong><br>Akhil Reed Amar is a Sterling Professor of Law and Political Science at Yale University, where he teaches constitutional law at both Yale College and Yale Law School. He received his B.A., summa cum laude, in 1980 from Yale College and his J.D. in 1984 from Yale Law School, where he served as an editor of The Yale Law Journal. After clerking for Judge Stephen Breyer, U.S. Court of Appeals, 1st Circuit, Amar joined the Yale faculty in 1985. Along with Dean Paul Brest and Professors Sanford Levinson, Jack Balkin, and Reva Siegel, Amar is the co-editor of a leading constitutional law casebook, "Processes of Constitutional Decisionmaking." He is also the author of several books, including "The Constitution and Criminal Procedure: First Principles" (1997), "The Bill of Rights: Creation and Reconstruction" (1998), "America's Constitution: A Biography" (2005), and most recently, "America's Unwritten Constitution: The Precedents and Principles We Live By" (2012). Akhil recently launched the weekly podcast "America’s Constitution."</p>
<p><strong>Carter Phillips</strong><br>Carter Phillips is one of the most experienced and celebrated Supreme Court and appellate lawyers in the country. He has argued more than 85 cases before the Supreme Court, both in private practice and on behalf of the United States government. He served as assistant to the solicitor general and clerked for Chief Justice Warren E. Burger. He is a partner at the law firm Sidley Austin in Washington, D.C. Carter is an alum of the Northwestern School of Law, where he is a professor in the Supreme Court clinic.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>We Should Expand the Supreme Court</em></p>
<p><u>Background and History</u></p>
<p><u>Mechanics of Reform</u></p>
<p><u>Recent Calls for Reform</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Biden and the Presidential Commission</u></p>
<p><u>Stats, Studies, and Academic</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> September 30, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Law, Politics, U.S.</p>
<p>Right now, nine justices hold tremendous power in American law. It's been that way since Ulysses S. Grant first inhabited the White House. The Constitution is silent on just how many justices should sit on the nation's top bench, and in 1937 President Roosevelt tried to add a slew of new appointments that would be sympathetic to his New Deal programs. Congress didn't bite. Now, advocates on the left are eyeing the bench once again. They see a Supreme Court out of touch with the American electorate, obstructed by partisan interests, and rendered illegitimate by years of controversial appointments. But those opposed are sounding the alarms. A move to dramatically change one of the three core pillars of American government would ultimately undermine the court’s legitimacy. It’s not perfect, they argue. But the court has consistently shown its independence and should not be compromised as a result of partisan ambitions. So, in light of this emerging divide, Open to Debate, formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. in partnership with The Newt and Jo Minow Debate Series at Northwestern Pritzker School of Law asks this question: Is it okay to expand the court?
<div class="elfsight-app-3d359447-b932-4cca-80e9-ade6527e66f7"></div></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/U793ZoXz-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/U793ZoXz-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Dahlia Lithwick</strong><br>Dahlia Lithwick is one of the nation’s most prominent progressive legal commentators and Supreme Court analysts. She is a senior editor at Slate, where she has written her "Supreme Court Dispatches" and "Jurisprudence" columns since 1999 and is the host of the award-winning law podcast "Amicus." She holds a J.D. from Stanford University and is currently teaching a short course on the Supreme Court and Ruth Bader Ginsburg at the University of Virginia Law.</p>
<p><strong>Tamara Brummer</strong><br>Tamara Brummer serves as Senior Advisor and Director of National Outreach and Engagement for Demand Justice, one of the leading organizations advocating for court expansion and reform. Prior to this post, Tamara spent years as a political organizer and strategist, building meaningful and impactful relationships rooted in a shared vision of economic justice. This includes tenures across the labor movement, notably with the AFL-CIO and the International Union of Painters and Allied Trades.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Akhil Reed Amar</strong><br>Akhil Reed Amar is a Sterling Professor of Law and Political Science at Yale University, where he teaches constitutional law at both Yale College and Yale Law School. He received his B.A., summa cum laude, in 1980 from Yale College and his J.D. in 1984 from Yale Law School, where he served as an editor of The Yale Law Journal. After clerking for Judge Stephen Breyer, U.S. Court of Appeals, 1st Circuit, Amar joined the Yale faculty in 1985. Along with Dean Paul Brest and Professors Sanford Levinson, Jack Balkin, and Reva Siegel, Amar is the co-editor of a leading constitutional law casebook, "Processes of Constitutional Decisionmaking." He is also the author of several books, including "The Constitution and Criminal Procedure: First Principles" (1997), "The Bill of Rights: Creation and Reconstruction" (1998), "America's Constitution: A Biography" (2005), and most recently, "America's Unwritten Constitution: The Precedents and Principles We Live By" (2012). Akhil recently launched the weekly podcast "America’s Constitution."</p>
<p><strong>Carter Phillips</strong><br>Carter Phillips is one of the most experienced and celebrated Supreme Court and appellate lawyers in the country. He has argued more than 85 cases before the Supreme Court, both in private practice and on behalf of the United States government. He served as assistant to the solicitor general and clerked for Chief Justice Warren E. Burger. He is a partner at the law firm Sidley Austin in Washington, D.C. Carter is an alum of the Northwestern School of Law, where he is a professor in the Supreme Court clinic.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>We Should Expand the Supreme Court</em></p>
<p><u>Background and History</u></p>
<p><u>Mechanics of Reform</u></p>
<p><u>Recent Calls for Reform</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Biden and the Presidential Commission</u></p>
<p><u>Stats, Studies, and Academic</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The United Nations Is Obsolete</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/united-nations-obsolete</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10329</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> September 17, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> World</p>
<p>As world attention descends on the United Nations General Assembly, Intelligence Squared U.S. casts a critical lens on this nearly 76-year-old global organization. In light of recent controversies in places like Haiti, and its limited presence in places such as Afghanistan -- where the Taliban has regained control -- questions are mounting as to whether the United Nations itself is both ineffective and outdated. Those who say “no” point to its promotion of peace and stability in an increasingly fractured political landscape, its devotion to human rights, its addressing of climate change, its commitment to multilateralism, and its widespread delivery of humanitarian aid as evidence of its value. The system is not perfect, they say, but its achievements are many, and are often unsung. Yet those who say “yes” question its usefulness in addressing a radically different global environment than the one in which it was formed, critique its promotion of globalism. They also cite corruption and a lack of accountability with regard to the very populations the body is charged with helping. So, in light of these emerging questions, we ask an especially timely question: Is the United Nations is Obsolete?
<div class="elfsight-app-6f02753d-fb60-4cef-80a5-54581af044d0"></div></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/nwirSPvq-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/nwirSPvq-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rajan Menon</strong><br>Rajan Menon is an author and scholar who has held several esteemed teaching positions at Columbia University, the City College of New York, Vanderbilt University, and others. He is the author of several books, including "The Conceit of Humanitarian Intervention," which offers a wide-ranging critique of the ideology underlying military intervention. Rajan has been a fellow at the New American Foundation, a senior adviser for the Carnegia Corporation, and a senior fellow at the Council on Foreign Relations. His current work concerns American foreign and national security policy, international security, and globalization.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.ccny.cuny.edu/profiles/rajan-menon">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Nile Gardiner</strong><br>Nile Gardiner is a British scholar and commentator currently serving as director of the Heritage Foundation’s Margaret Thatcher Center for Freedom. He is a specialist on transatlantic relationships and has advised the U.S. government on a range of international security issues. He was also a researcher for former British Prime Minister Margaret Thatcher, assisting with her book “Statecraft: Strategies for a Changing World.” He was named one of the 50 most influential Britons in the U.S. by the London Daily Telegraph.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Angela Kane</strong><br>Angela Kane is a German diplomat and served as the United Nations High Representative for Disarmament Affairs, where she provided strategy and leadership on the U.N.’s multilateral disarmament and non-proliferation agendas. Prior to that post, she served as Under-Secretary-General for Management. She is now a distinguished fellow at the Nuclear Threat Initiative, working to reduce global catastrophic biological risk by strengthening international coordination in preventing and responding to nuclear events.</p>
<p><strong>Mohammad-Mahmoud Ould Mohamedou</strong><br>Mohamed Mahmoud Ould Mohamedou is a scholar, author, and diplomat. He is currently the deputy director, a professor of international history and politics, and director of executive education at the Geneva Graduate Institute and has held academic posts at Harvard and the Ralph Bunche Institute on the United Nations (now Ralph Bunche Institute for International Studies at the City University of New York’s Graduate Center), among others. He is the author of severali books and previously served as Minister of Foreign Affairs of Mauritania.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>The United Nations Is Obsolete</em></p>
<p><u>Background and History</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Proposed Reforms</u></p>
<p><u>Successes and Failures</u></p>
<p><u>Stats, Studies, and Academic</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> September 17, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> World</p>
<p>As world attention descends on the United Nations General Assembly, Intelligence Squared U.S. casts a critical lens on this nearly 76-year-old global organization. In light of recent controversies in places like Haiti, and its limited presence in places such as Afghanistan -- where the Taliban has regained control -- questions are mounting as to whether the United Nations itself is both ineffective and outdated. Those who say “no” point to its promotion of peace and stability in an increasingly fractured political landscape, its devotion to human rights, its addressing of climate change, its commitment to multilateralism, and its widespread delivery of humanitarian aid as evidence of its value. The system is not perfect, they say, but its achievements are many, and are often unsung. Yet those who say “yes” question its usefulness in addressing a radically different global environment than the one in which it was formed, critique its promotion of globalism. They also cite corruption and a lack of accountability with regard to the very populations the body is charged with helping. So, in light of these emerging questions, we ask an especially timely question: Is the United Nations is Obsolete?
<div class="elfsight-app-6f02753d-fb60-4cef-80a5-54581af044d0"></div></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/nwirSPvq-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/nwirSPvq-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rajan Menon</strong><br>Rajan Menon is an author and scholar who has held several esteemed teaching positions at Columbia University, the City College of New York, Vanderbilt University, and others. He is the author of several books, including "The Conceit of Humanitarian Intervention," which offers a wide-ranging critique of the ideology underlying military intervention. Rajan has been a fellow at the New American Foundation, a senior adviser for the Carnegia Corporation, and a senior fellow at the Council on Foreign Relations. His current work concerns American foreign and national security policy, international security, and globalization.
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.ccny.cuny.edu/profiles/rajan-menon">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Nile Gardiner</strong><br>Nile Gardiner is a British scholar and commentator currently serving as director of the Heritage Foundation’s Margaret Thatcher Center for Freedom. He is a specialist on transatlantic relationships and has advised the U.S. government on a range of international security issues. He was also a researcher for former British Prime Minister Margaret Thatcher, assisting with her book “Statecraft: Strategies for a Changing World.” He was named one of the 50 most influential Britons in the U.S. by the London Daily Telegraph.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Angela Kane</strong><br>Angela Kane is a German diplomat and served as the United Nations High Representative for Disarmament Affairs, where she provided strategy and leadership on the U.N.’s multilateral disarmament and non-proliferation agendas. Prior to that post, she served as Under-Secretary-General for Management. She is now a distinguished fellow at the Nuclear Threat Initiative, working to reduce global catastrophic biological risk by strengthening international coordination in preventing and responding to nuclear events.</p>
<p><strong>Mohammad-Mahmoud Ould Mohamedou</strong><br>Mohamed Mahmoud Ould Mohamedou is a scholar, author, and diplomat. He is currently the deputy director, a professor of international history and politics, and director of executive education at the Geneva Graduate Institute and has held academic posts at Harvard and the Ralph Bunche Institute on the United Nations (now Ralph Bunche Institute for International Studies at the City University of New York’s Graduate Center), among others. He is the author of severali books and previously served as Minister of Foreign Affairs of Mauritania.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>The United Nations Is Obsolete</em></p>
<p><u>Background and History</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Proposed Reforms</u></p>
<p><u>Successes and Failures</u></p>
<p><u>Stats, Studies, and Academic</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Agree to Disagree: Should Congress Spend Trillions to &quot;Build Back Better&quot;?</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/agree-to-disagree-should-congress-spend-trillions-to-build-back-better</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:9976</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> September 03, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Economics</p>
<p>Biden wants to spend big. The administration is calling for some $4.5 trillion in increased government spending and tax credits over the next decade. The “Build Back Better" agenda includes hefty investments in infrastructure and unprecedented spending on the labor force, not to mention funding a host of Democratic policy priorities from child and elder care to paid family and medical leave. Its champions see an unjust and unstable economy in need of major government intervention. They argue that bold investments are necessary to combat economic inequality, build the next generation of American business, and help the nation regain its economic footing in the post-pandemic world. But opponents are sounding the alarm: Trillions in new spending could balloon the national deficit and drive inflation. Further, they say, Biden’s swath of new big government social programs would only create more bureaucracy, drive up prices on everything from education to childcare, undermine business, and ultimately harm American consumers and workers. As Washington takes up this historic plan, we ask: Should Congress spend trillions to “Build Back Better”?
Arguing “YES” is Mark Zandi, chief economist of Moody’s Analytics and a frequent public commentator and policy advisor on the global economy and public policy.
Arguing “NO” is Michael Strain, director of economic policy studies at the American Enterprise Institute where his research focuses on economic policy, financial markets, and tax and budget policy.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/EUfqRYEe-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/EUfqRYEe-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Mark Zandi</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO11142785 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO11142785 BCX0">Mark Zandi is the chief economist of Moody’s Analytics, where he directs economic research and oversees the global economic forecast. He is also a co-founder of Economy.com, an economics research and analytics firm, which was bought by Moody’s in 2005. Notably, he was one of the first economists to warn about the 2008 financial crisis a few years before it occurred. Zandi is on the board of directors of MGIC, the nation’s largest private mortgage insurance company, and is the lead director of Reinvestment Fund, one of the nation’s largest community development financial institutions that makes investments in underserved communities. Zandi frequently testifies before Congress and conducts regular briefings on the economy for corporate boards, trade associations, and policymakers. He is often quoted in national and global publications and interviewed by major news media outlets, and is a frequent guest on CNBC, NPR, Meet the Press, CNN, and various other networks and news programs. Zandi is the author of “Paying the Price: Ending the Great Recession and Beginning a New American Century” and “Financial Shock: A 360° Look at the Subprime Mortgage Implosion, and How to Avoid the Next Financial Crisis.” He has a B.S. and Ph.D. in economics from the University of Pennsylvania.</span></span><span class="EOP SCXO11142785 BCX0"> </span></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Michael Strain</strong><br><span class="TextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093">Michael Strain is the Director of Economic Policy Studies and the Arthur F. Burns Scholar in Political Economy at the American Enterprise Institute. At AEI, Strain oversees the Institute’s work in economic policy, financial markets, welfare economics, and other related areas. He has published several dozen articles in academic and policy journals and is the author of “The American Dream Is Not Dead: (But Populism Could Kill It).” Before joining AEI, Strain worked in the Center for Economic Studies at the U.S. Census Bureau and the Federal Reserve Bank of New York. Strain is a professor at Georgetown University and is associated with the IZA Institute of Labor Economics, the Institute for Research on Poverty, and the Aspen Economic Strategy Group. He has served on committees, including the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, the National Academy of Social Insurance, and the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine. His essays and op-eds have been published by </span></span><span class="TextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093">The New York Times</span></span><span class="TextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093">, </span></span><span class="TextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093">The Wall Street Journal</span></span><span class="TextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093">, the </span></span><span class="TextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093">Financial Times</span></span><span class="TextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093">, and </span></span><span class="TextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093">Project Syndicate</span></span><span class="TextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093">, among other outlets. Strain has testified before Congress and is frequently interviewed on radio and television, including CNBC, MSNBC, and NPR.</span></span></p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Agree to Disagree: Should Congress Spend Trillions to "Build Back Better"?</em></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> September 03, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Economics</p>
<p>Biden wants to spend big. The administration is calling for some $4.5 trillion in increased government spending and tax credits over the next decade. The “Build Back Better" agenda includes hefty investments in infrastructure and unprecedented spending on the labor force, not to mention funding a host of Democratic policy priorities from child and elder care to paid family and medical leave. Its champions see an unjust and unstable economy in need of major government intervention. They argue that bold investments are necessary to combat economic inequality, build the next generation of American business, and help the nation regain its economic footing in the post-pandemic world. But opponents are sounding the alarm: Trillions in new spending could balloon the national deficit and drive inflation. Further, they say, Biden’s swath of new big government social programs would only create more bureaucracy, drive up prices on everything from education to childcare, undermine business, and ultimately harm American consumers and workers. As Washington takes up this historic plan, we ask: Should Congress spend trillions to “Build Back Better”?
Arguing “YES” is Mark Zandi, chief economist of Moody’s Analytics and a frequent public commentator and policy advisor on the global economy and public policy.
Arguing “NO” is Michael Strain, director of economic policy studies at the American Enterprise Institute where his research focuses on economic policy, financial markets, and tax and budget policy.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/EUfqRYEe-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/EUfqRYEe-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Mark Zandi</strong><br><span class="TextRun SCXO11142785 BCX0" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="auto"><span class="NormalTextRun SCXO11142785 BCX0">Mark Zandi is the chief economist of Moody’s Analytics, where he directs economic research and oversees the global economic forecast. He is also a co-founder of Economy.com, an economics research and analytics firm, which was bought by Moody’s in 2005. Notably, he was one of the first economists to warn about the 2008 financial crisis a few years before it occurred. Zandi is on the board of directors of MGIC, the nation’s largest private mortgage insurance company, and is the lead director of Reinvestment Fund, one of the nation’s largest community development financial institutions that makes investments in underserved communities. Zandi frequently testifies before Congress and conducts regular briefings on the economy for corporate boards, trade associations, and policymakers. He is often quoted in national and global publications and interviewed by major news media outlets, and is a frequent guest on CNBC, NPR, Meet the Press, CNN, and various other networks and news programs. Zandi is the author of “Paying the Price: Ending the Great Recession and Beginning a New American Century” and “Financial Shock: A 360° Look at the Subprime Mortgage Implosion, and How to Avoid the Next Financial Crisis.” He has a B.S. and Ph.D. in economics from the University of Pennsylvania.</span></span><span class="EOP SCXO11142785 BCX0"> </span></p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Michael Strain</strong><br><span class="TextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093">Michael Strain is the Director of Economic Policy Studies and the Arthur F. Burns Scholar in Political Economy at the American Enterprise Institute. At AEI, Strain oversees the Institute’s work in economic policy, financial markets, welfare economics, and other related areas. He has published several dozen articles in academic and policy journals and is the author of “The American Dream Is Not Dead: (But Populism Could Kill It).” Before joining AEI, Strain worked in the Center for Economic Studies at the U.S. Census Bureau and the Federal Reserve Bank of New York. Strain is a professor at Georgetown University and is associated with the IZA Institute of Labor Economics, the Institute for Research on Poverty, and the Aspen Economic Strategy Group. He has served on committees, including the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, the National Academy of Social Insurance, and the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine. His essays and op-eds have been published by </span></span><span class="TextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093">The New York Times</span></span><span class="TextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093">, </span></span><span class="TextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093">The Wall Street Journal</span></span><span class="TextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093">, the </span></span><span class="TextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093">Financial Times</span></span><span class="TextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093">, and </span></span><span class="TextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093">Project Syndicate</span></span><span class="TextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun  BCX0 SCXO80527093">, among other outlets. Strain has testified before Congress and is frequently interviewed on radio and television, including CNBC, MSNBC, and NPR.</span></span></p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Agree to Disagree: Should Congress Spend Trillions to "Build Back Better"?</em></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Agree to Disagree: Leaving Afghanistan</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/agree-to-disagree-leaving-afghanistan</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:9971</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> August 21, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Politics, U.S., World</p>
<p>The Taliban have won. Twenty years after the 2001 invasion, the U.S.-backed government in Kabul has fallen. The Afghan president has fled. Taliban leadership, which ran the country in the late 1990s, is now firmly in place within the presidential palace. Thousands are desperate to leave, literally clinging to departing aircraft as they rumble down runways, fearful of what reprisals may come. But after two decades of war, tens of billions spent, hundreds of thousands of lives lost – including more than 2,300 U.S. military personnel – bigger questions have emerged: Is the cost of leaving greater than the cost of staying? And was pulling out the right decision? Those who say “yes” argue that the world is a decidedly different place than it was in 2001, that the mission was never to nation-build, and that continued presence prolonged the violence and distracted energies and resources away from more pressing global challenges, particularly on those centered on China. But those who argue “no” point to the potential for a humanitarian and human rights catastrophe, the ceding of U.S. influence in Central Asia, and the likelihood for another terrorist safe haven. As such, Intelligence Squared and its host John Donvan examine these competing perspectives in this special timely edition of Agree-to-Disagree: Leaving Afghanistan.
First, a conversation with Ahmed Rashid, a Pakistani journalist and best-selling author, who is one of the world’s leading experts on the social and political situations in Pakistan and Afghanistan. His first book, Taliban: Militant Islam, Oil and Fundamentalism in Central Asia, explores the shadowy world of the Taliban and quickly became a #1 New York Times bestseller. Rashid has been called “Pakistan’s best and bravest reporter” (Christopher Hitchens).
Then, a competition of ideas: Arguing in favor of leaving is Daniel Markey, Senior Research Professor at Johns Hopkins University School of Advanced International Studies. Arguing against leaving is Kori Schake is a senior fellow and the director of foreign and defense policy studies at the American Enterprise Institute (AEI). Emmy award-winning journalist John Donvan is the moderator.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/x0IKmVwX-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/x0IKmVwX-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Daniel Markey</strong><br>Daniel Markey is a senior research professor at Johns Hopkins University’s School of Advanced International Studies (SAIS). He also serves as the academic director of the Johns Hopkins SAIS Global Policy Program. Dr. Markey is the author of China’s Western Horizon: Beijing and the New Geopolitics of Eurasia. From 2007 to 2015, Daniel Markey was a senior fellow for India, Pakistan, and South Asia at the Council on Foreign Relations. While there, he wrote "No Exit from Pakistan: America’s Tortured Relationship with Islamabad." From 2003 to 2007, Dr. Markey held the South Asia portfolio on the Secretary’s Policy Planning Staff at the US Department of State. Prior to government service, he taught in the Department of Politics at Princeton University and was a postdoctoral fellow at Harvard’s Olin Institute for Strategic Studies. Dr. Markey is the author of numerous reports, articles, book chapters, and opinion pieces. His commentary has been featured widely in US and international media.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Kori Schake</strong><br>Kori Schake is a senior fellow and the director of foreign and defense policy studies at the American Enterprise Institute (AEI). Dr. Schake is the former deputy director-general of the International Institute for Strategic Studies in London. She has worked at the U.S. State Department, the U.S. Department of Defense, and the National Security Council at the White House. Author of five books, most recently "America vs. the West: Can the Liberal World Order Be Preserved?" Dr. Schake is widely published in policy journals and the popular press. She has a doctorate in government and politics from the University of Maryland.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Agree to Disagree: Leaving Afghanistan</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Live Updates</u></p>
<p><u>From The White House Briefing Room</u></p>
<p><u>Bipartisan Criticism</u></p>
<p><u>In Support of Biden</u></p>
<p><u>America Shifting Focus</u></p>
<p><u>Miscalculations</u></p>
<p><u>Terrorism Safe Haven</u></p>
<p><u>China, Russia, and the International Community</u></p>
<p><u>Good Resource for a Number of Topics</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> August 21, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Politics, U.S., World</p>
<p>The Taliban have won. Twenty years after the 2001 invasion, the U.S.-backed government in Kabul has fallen. The Afghan president has fled. Taliban leadership, which ran the country in the late 1990s, is now firmly in place within the presidential palace. Thousands are desperate to leave, literally clinging to departing aircraft as they rumble down runways, fearful of what reprisals may come. But after two decades of war, tens of billions spent, hundreds of thousands of lives lost – including more than 2,300 U.S. military personnel – bigger questions have emerged: Is the cost of leaving greater than the cost of staying? And was pulling out the right decision? Those who say “yes” argue that the world is a decidedly different place than it was in 2001, that the mission was never to nation-build, and that continued presence prolonged the violence and distracted energies and resources away from more pressing global challenges, particularly on those centered on China. But those who argue “no” point to the potential for a humanitarian and human rights catastrophe, the ceding of U.S. influence in Central Asia, and the likelihood for another terrorist safe haven. As such, Intelligence Squared and its host John Donvan examine these competing perspectives in this special timely edition of Agree-to-Disagree: Leaving Afghanistan.
First, a conversation with Ahmed Rashid, a Pakistani journalist and best-selling author, who is one of the world’s leading experts on the social and political situations in Pakistan and Afghanistan. His first book, Taliban: Militant Islam, Oil and Fundamentalism in Central Asia, explores the shadowy world of the Taliban and quickly became a #1 New York Times bestseller. Rashid has been called “Pakistan’s best and bravest reporter” (Christopher Hitchens).
Then, a competition of ideas: Arguing in favor of leaving is Daniel Markey, Senior Research Professor at Johns Hopkins University School of Advanced International Studies. Arguing against leaving is Kori Schake is a senior fellow and the director of foreign and defense policy studies at the American Enterprise Institute (AEI). Emmy award-winning journalist John Donvan is the moderator.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/x0IKmVwX-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/x0IKmVwX-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Daniel Markey</strong><br>Daniel Markey is a senior research professor at Johns Hopkins University’s School of Advanced International Studies (SAIS). He also serves as the academic director of the Johns Hopkins SAIS Global Policy Program. Dr. Markey is the author of China’s Western Horizon: Beijing and the New Geopolitics of Eurasia. From 2007 to 2015, Daniel Markey was a senior fellow for India, Pakistan, and South Asia at the Council on Foreign Relations. While there, he wrote "No Exit from Pakistan: America’s Tortured Relationship with Islamabad." From 2003 to 2007, Dr. Markey held the South Asia portfolio on the Secretary’s Policy Planning Staff at the US Department of State. Prior to government service, he taught in the Department of Politics at Princeton University and was a postdoctoral fellow at Harvard’s Olin Institute for Strategic Studies. Dr. Markey is the author of numerous reports, articles, book chapters, and opinion pieces. His commentary has been featured widely in US and international media.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Kori Schake</strong><br>Kori Schake is a senior fellow and the director of foreign and defense policy studies at the American Enterprise Institute (AEI). Dr. Schake is the former deputy director-general of the International Institute for Strategic Studies in London. She has worked at the U.S. State Department, the U.S. Department of Defense, and the National Security Council at the White House. Author of five books, most recently "America vs. the West: Can the Liberal World Order Be Preserved?" Dr. Schake is widely published in policy journals and the popular press. She has a doctorate in government and politics from the University of Maryland.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Agree to Disagree: Leaving Afghanistan</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Live Updates</u></p>
<p><u>From The White House Briefing Room</u></p>
<p><u>Bipartisan Criticism</u></p>
<p><u>In Support of Biden</u></p>
<p><u>America Shifting Focus</u></p>
<p><u>Miscalculations</u></p>
<p><u>Terrorism Safe Haven</u></p>
<p><u>China, Russia, and the International Community</u></p>
<p><u>Good Resource for a Number of Topics</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The New York Times Has Lost Its Way</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/new-york-times-has-lost-its-way</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10256</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> July 29, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Culture</p>
<p>What's happening at The New York Times? The paper of record is under fire. Critics argue it has sacrificed journalistic and intellectual balance in favor of correcting historic inequalities. In the process, they say, that effort has stifled dissent and promoted social justice above all else. Not so, say its defenders. The paper has indeed evolved, they argue. Yet that evolution has been proven a particular strength in such tumultuous times. Subscriptions are up, while both casting a critically important lens on historically disenfranchised groups and maintaining its core commitment to high editorial standards and a wide breadth of reporting. So here's the debate: "Has the New York Times Lost Its Way?"
<div class="elfsight-app-bc50dc7e-885e-4084-826e-4b4986430dca"></div></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/dZCO1dIB-AjT519rD.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/dZCO1dIB-AjT519rD.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Yascha Mounk</strong><br>Yascha Mounk is an associate professor of practice in international affairs at Johns Hopkins University and a postdoctoral fellow at the German Marshall Fund. A columnist at Slate and the host of "The Good Fight" podcast, he is an expert on the rise of populism and the crisis of liberal democracy. He is also the author of "The People vs. Democracy: Why Our Freedom Is in Danger and How to Save It."
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.yaschamounk.com/about">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Batya Ungar-Sargon</strong><br>Batya Ungar-Sargon is Newsweek's deputy opinion editor and author of the forthcoming book “Bad News: How Woke Media Is Undermining Democracy." The book focuses on the recent shift in media and its effects across the broader democratic landscape.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Frank Sesno</strong><br>Frank Sesno is the former director of the School of Media and Public Affairs at George Washington University. He is the creator of Planet Forward and has served in several roles at CNN, including as a White House correspondent, anchor, and Washington Bureau Chief.</p>
<p><strong>Virginia Heffernan</strong><br>Virginia Heffernan is an American journalist and cultural critic. Since 2015, she has been a political columnist at the Los Angeles Times and a cultural columnist at Wired Magazine.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>De Blasio’s Victory in New York vs. Florida Debate Is a Wake-Up Call for Conservatives</strong> <small>2023-04-19 21:24:53</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>‘Florida is choosing the path of burning books,’ the ex-mayor says in painting the Sunshine State as a MAGA-fueled dystopia.</p>
<p>On April 28, a debate (https://opentodebate.org/debate/is-florida-eating-new-yorks-lunch/) between the Democratic former mayor of New York City, Bill de Blasio, and the Manhattan Institute’s president, Reihan Salam, will be released. Having watched the taping, I can say it’s a much-watch for liberals and conservatives alike for very different reasons.</p>
<p>I expected Mr. DeBlasio, with a governing record to defend, to be the underdog on the question, “Is Florida Eating New York’s Lunch?” The more than 1.6 million former New Yorkers who now call the Sunshine State home would seem to disprove his side of the argument.</p>
<p>The Census shows more New Yorkers relocated to Florida in 2022 than in any year since it joined the union in 1845. New York also has, at almost 10 percent, the highest income tax in the nation, while Florida has none.</p>
<p>The facts, figures, and comparisons of legal and regulatory climates all favored Mr. Salam, so liberals will enjoy seeing Mr. De Blasio prevail. Still, conservatives would do well to watch, not to suffer, but to see just what they’re up against in the arena of ideas.</p>
<p>The debate to be shared on public radio, video, and the Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. podcast was hosted by the non-partisan Open to Debate group, whose mission is to address “the extreme polarization of our nation and our politics.”</p>
<p>Mr. Salam, like many on the right, seemed to interpret avoiding “extreme polarization” as refusing to punch or even block. This posture was striking since he used to be the executive editor of William F. Buckley’s National Review.</p>
<p>Mr. Buckley earned universal praise for his geniality yet never let anyone run roughshod over him. Even when confronting radicals and racists as the host of “Firing Line,” he never showed his belly, marshaling intelligence and humor to lay out the strongest possible case.</p>
<p>Mr. De Blasio, too, has core beliefs. He was unafraid to launch haymakers and score some hits below the belt. Even when the moderator, John Donvan, stepped in to defend Mr. Salam, the mayor would go right on flogging straw dogs.</p>
<p>Like “Bad, Bad Leroy Brown” from the Jim Croce song, Mr. De Blasio concealed a razor in his shoe and used it to carve up Mr. Salam with such skill, that the man seemed not to notice until he grew woozy.</p>
<p>It was like watching a pitcher on a team I don’t root for throw a perfect game. “Why can’t our guy whip a fastball like that?” Mr. De Blasio pulled off the upset because while Mr. Salam aimed for viewers’ brains, Mr. De Blasio zeroed in on their hearts, painting Florida as an intolerant, dystopian hellscape dominated by “MAGA extremism.”</p>
<p>Florida is choosing a path of banning books, Mr. De Blasio said, and disallowing a woman’s right to choose. Florida’s turning against trans youth. Despite the state having larger black and Hispanic populations, he said it was hostile to diversity.</p>
<p>Mr. De Blasio also warned as the Democratic senator from New York, Daniel Patrick Moynihan did in 1969 that Florida would soon be underwater due to greenhouse gas, and heralded the Empire State’s social spending while sidestepping that its unsustainable deficit is the nation’s largest.</p>
<p>When I factor in pre-K for my child, Mr. De Blasio said, quoting a new arrival from Seattle, my cost of living is actually cheaper. I could almost hear the picture of Thomas Sowell in the book behind Mr. Salam screaming that this is tempting people to New York on the promise the state will give them cash stolen from their neighbors.</p>
<p>Mr. De Blasio also touted his city’s rent control and $15 minimum wage. Conservatives used to have answers for these subjects: If rent control works, why does Gotham have the highest rent in the country? What about the minimum wage pricing out entry-level jobs, etc.?</p>
<p>The left ought to watch this debate to exalt victory and the right to relearn the lesson of the 2022 midterms that statistics won’t win elections for them, and until they learn to wield the rhetorical razor once more, the left is going to go right on charging lunch to their tabs.</p></div>
<div><strong>De Blasio slams Florida in online debate</strong> <small>2023-04-19 21:35:32</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>'The future unfortunately is not bright for Florida' the former mayor said, regarding climate change.
Former New York City Mayor Bill de Blasio disavowed Marxism Friday afternoon, declaring that New York City’s inclusive politics far outweighed whatever advantages of climate or affordability the state of Florida may have. Unless you happen to take a Marxian perspective here, you can’t just talk about economics. You have to talk about cultural and political factors as well,” he said. “Florida has some strengths. But Florida is rapidly and aggressively undermining those strengths.”</p>
<p>De Blasio put himself in the debate chair to defend his city on a livestream (https://opentodebate.org/debate/is-florida-eating-new-yorks-lunch/) hosted by Open to Debate, a nonpartisan nonprofit devoted to civil discourse. He took on Reihan Salam, the president of the conservative think tank the Manhattan Institute on the question: “Is Florida eating New York’s lunch?”</p>
<p>Now a visiting professor (https://nyunews.com/news/2023/04/11/bill-de-blasio-speaks-at-wagner/) at NYU’s Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service, de Blasio sat there while Salam slammed him, indirectly, on the city’s cost of living, ability to educate its students, retain public employees including police and teachers, and argued that working class people were leaving in search of affordability.</p>
<p>De Blasio, in turn, criticized Florida’s politics, including Gov. Ron DeSantis’ law banning abortion (https://www.politico.com/news/2023/04/13/florida-6-week-abortion-ban-bill-00091965) after six weeks and the “Don’t Say Gay” law. (https://apnews.com/article/florida-dont-say-gay-law-signed-56aee61f075a12663f25990c7b31624d) The current mayor, Eric Adams, has found DeSantis’ conservative politics to be an easy target too, and backed an ad campaign (https://www.cityandstateny.com/politics/2022/04/nyc-fires-back-floridas-dont-say-gay-bill-billboard-counter-attack/363992/) telling LGTBQ Floridians and their allies to come to New York.</p>
<p>In a somewhat morbid closing argument, de Blasio invoked the threat of climate change to argue that New York will ultimately prevail in the rivalry. “The future, unfortunately, is not bright for Florida,” he said. “The human made threats coming out of their state government are bad enough, and will hinder Florida’s economic and social future. But the threat from mother nature is so much greater.”</p></div>
<div><strong>Bill de Blasio Argues Against ‘Marxian Analysis’ of NYC’s Affordability Crisis</strong> <small>2023-04-19 21:41:23</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>The former "communist mayor" brags about millionaires, and more links to start your day.</p>
<p>On Friday afternoon, while everyone else was out basking in the freakish warmth of a summer day in spring, the 109th mayor of New York City put on a suit, sat in front of a microphone, and attempted to defend our honor.</p>
<p>Bill de Blasio had agreed to tape an episode of the Open to Debate podcast (https://opentodebate.org/). The question at hand: Is Florida eating New York's lunch? Reihan Salam, the president of the Manhattan Institute, entered the Zoom room to argue in the affirmative, but both men soon discovered that this vague prompt was kind of stupid.</p>
<p>No one was here to argue that Florida living was better than New York's, not even the guy who was supposed to make that point. They're too different (https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2023-04-14/three-years-into-the-pandemic-the-urban-exodus-was-overblown?utm_source=website&utm_medium=share&utm_campaign=copy). "Floridians can just hop in their SUVs. I personally prefer the New York way of life," Salam admitted. And essentially, everyone agreed that Florida was rapidly becoming a place that excludes women (https://apnews.com/article/florida-abortion-ban-approved-c9c53311a0b2426adc4b8d0b463edad1), the LGBTQ community (https://www.npr.org/2022/03/28/1089221657/dont-say-gay-florida-desantis), immigrants (https://www.nytimes.com/2022/10/02/us/migrants-marthas-vineyard-desantis-texas.html), and people who are squeamish about banning books (https://pen.org/banned-books-florida/). "Florida is a place that a lot of smart, creative, entrepreneurial people are going to say, 'This isn't for me anymore,'" de Blasio declared.</p>
<p>The debate got interesting when Salam raised a point that de Blasio seemingly had no answer to: New York is becoming impossibly unaffordable to everyone but the rich and extremely rich.</p>
<p>We're really losing strivers. We're really losing working- and middle-class people. What's happening is the gentrification of New York, Salam said.</p>
<p>"Now, you can't just, you know, unless you happen to take a Marxian analysis here, you can't just talk about economics," de Blasio said. "You have to talk about cultural and political factors as well."</p>
<p>If you had experienced the eight years of Bill and were still watching the debate, you were screaming at your screen. What's that, Mr. Tale of Two Cities (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NH_zMTrhgAw)? Mr. Free Pre-K for All (https://www.theatlantic.com/education/archive/2016/09/bill-de-blasios-prek-crusade/498830/)? You can't just look at the economics?</p>
<p>De Blasio could have admitted that yes, NYC was too expensive, and yes, he had done his best but failed to fully turn things around, but that New York still has the legislative ability to make deep and enduring changes on the economic front while maintaining its cultural capital, and he could have pointed to legislation in Albany that would protect tenants and make things more affordable for lower-income New Yorkers, and on and on.</p>
<p>But that would have required a self-awareness that still somehow eludes de Blasio in his public appearances. So instead, he made noises about "opportunity" and pointed to the existence of rent-stabilized apartments and NYCHA buildings as proof that New York was going to be just fine.</p>
<p>In the end, you had the Manhattan Institute guy complaining about the length of the NYCHA waitlist, and Bill fucking de Blasio, the guy the right-wing media spent years painting as a straight-up communist, bragging about how New York increased its number of millionaires (https://www.nytimes.com/2023/02/23/nyregion/millionaires-new-york-taxes.html).</p>
<p>Nearly one hour into the debate, some journalists were allowed to come on to ask a question both the Times and Politico asked de Blasio what they thought of Mayor Eric Adams's stated intention to stop the expansion (https://www.nytimes.com/2022/09/22/nyregion/prekindergarten-adams-nyc-3k.html) of 3-K for all, and both times, de Blasio failed to stand up for his program Classic.</p>
<p>I've heard many times, including direct conversations with Mayor Adams, that he said how much he is committed to early childhood education. And until the budget is resolved between him and the Council, it's impossible to say what the final investments will be made, de Blasio said.</p>
<p>Will the former mayor find his footing or will he remain a hot take (https://hellgatenyc.com/nyc-hot-take-bracket-goes-from-elite-eight-to-final-four)? Watch this space.</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>The New York Times Has Lost Its Way</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Echo Chambers</u></p>
<p><u>Recent Incidents</u></p>
<p><u>State of Journalism</u></p>
<p><u>Stats, Studies, and Academic</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> July 29, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Culture</p>
<p>What's happening at The New York Times? The paper of record is under fire. Critics argue it has sacrificed journalistic and intellectual balance in favor of correcting historic inequalities. In the process, they say, that effort has stifled dissent and promoted social justice above all else. Not so, say its defenders. The paper has indeed evolved, they argue. Yet that evolution has been proven a particular strength in such tumultuous times. Subscriptions are up, while both casting a critically important lens on historically disenfranchised groups and maintaining its core commitment to high editorial standards and a wide breadth of reporting. So here's the debate: "Has the New York Times Lost Its Way?"
<div class="elfsight-app-bc50dc7e-885e-4084-826e-4b4986430dca"></div></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/dZCO1dIB-AjT519rD.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/dZCO1dIB-AjT519rD.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Yascha Mounk</strong><br>Yascha Mounk is an associate professor of practice in international affairs at Johns Hopkins University and a postdoctoral fellow at the German Marshall Fund. A columnist at Slate and the host of "The Good Fight" podcast, he is an expert on the rise of populism and the crisis of liberal democracy. He is also the author of "The People vs. Democracy: Why Our Freedom Is in Danger and How to Save It."
<br>Full bio is available <a href="https://www.yaschamounk.com/about">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Batya Ungar-Sargon</strong><br>Batya Ungar-Sargon is Newsweek's deputy opinion editor and author of the forthcoming book “Bad News: How Woke Media Is Undermining Democracy." The book focuses on the recent shift in media and its effects across the broader democratic landscape.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Frank Sesno</strong><br>Frank Sesno is the former director of the School of Media and Public Affairs at George Washington University. He is the creator of Planet Forward and has served in several roles at CNN, including as a White House correspondent, anchor, and Washington Bureau Chief.</p>
<p><strong>Virginia Heffernan</strong><br>Virginia Heffernan is an American journalist and cultural critic. Since 2015, she has been a political columnist at the Los Angeles Times and a cultural columnist at Wired Magazine.</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>De Blasio’s Victory in New York vs. Florida Debate Is a Wake-Up Call for Conservatives</strong> <small>2023-04-19 21:24:53</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>‘Florida is choosing the path of burning books,’ the ex-mayor says in painting the Sunshine State as a MAGA-fueled dystopia.</p>
<p>On April 28, a debate (https://opentodebate.org/debate/is-florida-eating-new-yorks-lunch/) between the Democratic former mayor of New York City, Bill de Blasio, and the Manhattan Institute’s president, Reihan Salam, will be released. Having watched the taping, I can say it’s a much-watch for liberals and conservatives alike for very different reasons.</p>
<p>I expected Mr. DeBlasio, with a governing record to defend, to be the underdog on the question, “Is Florida Eating New York’s Lunch?” The more than 1.6 million former New Yorkers who now call the Sunshine State home would seem to disprove his side of the argument.</p>
<p>The Census shows more New Yorkers relocated to Florida in 2022 than in any year since it joined the union in 1845. New York also has, at almost 10 percent, the highest income tax in the nation, while Florida has none.</p>
<p>The facts, figures, and comparisons of legal and regulatory climates all favored Mr. Salam, so liberals will enjoy seeing Mr. De Blasio prevail. Still, conservatives would do well to watch, not to suffer, but to see just what they’re up against in the arena of ideas.</p>
<p>The debate to be shared on public radio, video, and the Open to Debate formerly known as Intelligence Squared U.S. podcast was hosted by the non-partisan Open to Debate group, whose mission is to address “the extreme polarization of our nation and our politics.”</p>
<p>Mr. Salam, like many on the right, seemed to interpret avoiding “extreme polarization” as refusing to punch or even block. This posture was striking since he used to be the executive editor of William F. Buckley’s National Review.</p>
<p>Mr. Buckley earned universal praise for his geniality yet never let anyone run roughshod over him. Even when confronting radicals and racists as the host of “Firing Line,” he never showed his belly, marshaling intelligence and humor to lay out the strongest possible case.</p>
<p>Mr. De Blasio, too, has core beliefs. He was unafraid to launch haymakers and score some hits below the belt. Even when the moderator, John Donvan, stepped in to defend Mr. Salam, the mayor would go right on flogging straw dogs.</p>
<p>Like “Bad, Bad Leroy Brown” from the Jim Croce song, Mr. De Blasio concealed a razor in his shoe and used it to carve up Mr. Salam with such skill, that the man seemed not to notice until he grew woozy.</p>
<p>It was like watching a pitcher on a team I don’t root for throw a perfect game. “Why can’t our guy whip a fastball like that?” Mr. De Blasio pulled off the upset because while Mr. Salam aimed for viewers’ brains, Mr. De Blasio zeroed in on their hearts, painting Florida as an intolerant, dystopian hellscape dominated by “MAGA extremism.”</p>
<p>Florida is choosing a path of banning books, Mr. De Blasio said, and disallowing a woman’s right to choose. Florida’s turning against trans youth. Despite the state having larger black and Hispanic populations, he said it was hostile to diversity.</p>
<p>Mr. De Blasio also warned as the Democratic senator from New York, Daniel Patrick Moynihan did in 1969 that Florida would soon be underwater due to greenhouse gas, and heralded the Empire State’s social spending while sidestepping that its unsustainable deficit is the nation’s largest.</p>
<p>When I factor in pre-K for my child, Mr. De Blasio said, quoting a new arrival from Seattle, my cost of living is actually cheaper. I could almost hear the picture of Thomas Sowell in the book behind Mr. Salam screaming that this is tempting people to New York on the promise the state will give them cash stolen from their neighbors.</p>
<p>Mr. De Blasio also touted his city’s rent control and $15 minimum wage. Conservatives used to have answers for these subjects: If rent control works, why does Gotham have the highest rent in the country? What about the minimum wage pricing out entry-level jobs, etc.?</p>
<p>The left ought to watch this debate to exalt victory and the right to relearn the lesson of the 2022 midterms that statistics won’t win elections for them, and until they learn to wield the rhetorical razor once more, the left is going to go right on charging lunch to their tabs.</p></div>
<div><strong>De Blasio slams Florida in online debate</strong> <small>2023-04-19 21:35:32</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>'The future unfortunately is not bright for Florida' the former mayor said, regarding climate change.
Former New York City Mayor Bill de Blasio disavowed Marxism Friday afternoon, declaring that New York City’s inclusive politics far outweighed whatever advantages of climate or affordability the state of Florida may have. Unless you happen to take a Marxian perspective here, you can’t just talk about economics. You have to talk about cultural and political factors as well,” he said. “Florida has some strengths. But Florida is rapidly and aggressively undermining those strengths.”</p>
<p>De Blasio put himself in the debate chair to defend his city on a livestream (https://opentodebate.org/debate/is-florida-eating-new-yorks-lunch/) hosted by Open to Debate, a nonpartisan nonprofit devoted to civil discourse. He took on Reihan Salam, the president of the conservative think tank the Manhattan Institute on the question: “Is Florida eating New York’s lunch?”</p>
<p>Now a visiting professor (https://nyunews.com/news/2023/04/11/bill-de-blasio-speaks-at-wagner/) at NYU’s Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service, de Blasio sat there while Salam slammed him, indirectly, on the city’s cost of living, ability to educate its students, retain public employees including police and teachers, and argued that working class people were leaving in search of affordability.</p>
<p>De Blasio, in turn, criticized Florida’s politics, including Gov. Ron DeSantis’ law banning abortion (https://www.politico.com/news/2023/04/13/florida-6-week-abortion-ban-bill-00091965) after six weeks and the “Don’t Say Gay” law. (https://apnews.com/article/florida-dont-say-gay-law-signed-56aee61f075a12663f25990c7b31624d) The current mayor, Eric Adams, has found DeSantis’ conservative politics to be an easy target too, and backed an ad campaign (https://www.cityandstateny.com/politics/2022/04/nyc-fires-back-floridas-dont-say-gay-bill-billboard-counter-attack/363992/) telling LGTBQ Floridians and their allies to come to New York.</p>
<p>In a somewhat morbid closing argument, de Blasio invoked the threat of climate change to argue that New York will ultimately prevail in the rivalry. “The future, unfortunately, is not bright for Florida,” he said. “The human made threats coming out of their state government are bad enough, and will hinder Florida’s economic and social future. But the threat from mother nature is so much greater.”</p></div>
<div><strong>Bill de Blasio Argues Against ‘Marxian Analysis’ of NYC’s Affordability Crisis</strong> <small>2023-04-19 21:41:23</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>The former "communist mayor" brags about millionaires, and more links to start your day.</p>
<p>On Friday afternoon, while everyone else was out basking in the freakish warmth of a summer day in spring, the 109th mayor of New York City put on a suit, sat in front of a microphone, and attempted to defend our honor.</p>
<p>Bill de Blasio had agreed to tape an episode of the Open to Debate podcast (https://opentodebate.org/). The question at hand: Is Florida eating New York's lunch? Reihan Salam, the president of the Manhattan Institute, entered the Zoom room to argue in the affirmative, but both men soon discovered that this vague prompt was kind of stupid.</p>
<p>No one was here to argue that Florida living was better than New York's, not even the guy who was supposed to make that point. They're too different (https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2023-04-14/three-years-into-the-pandemic-the-urban-exodus-was-overblown?utm_source=website&utm_medium=share&utm_campaign=copy). "Floridians can just hop in their SUVs. I personally prefer the New York way of life," Salam admitted. And essentially, everyone agreed that Florida was rapidly becoming a place that excludes women (https://apnews.com/article/florida-abortion-ban-approved-c9c53311a0b2426adc4b8d0b463edad1), the LGBTQ community (https://www.npr.org/2022/03/28/1089221657/dont-say-gay-florida-desantis), immigrants (https://www.nytimes.com/2022/10/02/us/migrants-marthas-vineyard-desantis-texas.html), and people who are squeamish about banning books (https://pen.org/banned-books-florida/). "Florida is a place that a lot of smart, creative, entrepreneurial people are going to say, 'This isn't for me anymore,'" de Blasio declared.</p>
<p>The debate got interesting when Salam raised a point that de Blasio seemingly had no answer to: New York is becoming impossibly unaffordable to everyone but the rich and extremely rich.</p>
<p>We're really losing strivers. We're really losing working- and middle-class people. What's happening is the gentrification of New York, Salam said.</p>
<p>"Now, you can't just, you know, unless you happen to take a Marxian analysis here, you can't just talk about economics," de Blasio said. "You have to talk about cultural and political factors as well."</p>
<p>If you had experienced the eight years of Bill and were still watching the debate, you were screaming at your screen. What's that, Mr. Tale of Two Cities (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NH_zMTrhgAw)? Mr. Free Pre-K for All (https://www.theatlantic.com/education/archive/2016/09/bill-de-blasios-prek-crusade/498830/)? You can't just look at the economics?</p>
<p>De Blasio could have admitted that yes, NYC was too expensive, and yes, he had done his best but failed to fully turn things around, but that New York still has the legislative ability to make deep and enduring changes on the economic front while maintaining its cultural capital, and he could have pointed to legislation in Albany that would protect tenants and make things more affordable for lower-income New Yorkers, and on and on.</p>
<p>But that would have required a self-awareness that still somehow eludes de Blasio in his public appearances. So instead, he made noises about "opportunity" and pointed to the existence of rent-stabilized apartments and NYCHA buildings as proof that New York was going to be just fine.</p>
<p>In the end, you had the Manhattan Institute guy complaining about the length of the NYCHA waitlist, and Bill fucking de Blasio, the guy the right-wing media spent years painting as a straight-up communist, bragging about how New York increased its number of millionaires (https://www.nytimes.com/2023/02/23/nyregion/millionaires-new-york-taxes.html).</p>
<p>Nearly one hour into the debate, some journalists were allowed to come on to ask a question both the Times and Politico asked de Blasio what they thought of Mayor Eric Adams's stated intention to stop the expansion (https://www.nytimes.com/2022/09/22/nyregion/prekindergarten-adams-nyc-3k.html) of 3-K for all, and both times, de Blasio failed to stand up for his program Classic.</p>
<p>I've heard many times, including direct conversations with Mayor Adams, that he said how much he is committed to early childhood education. And until the budget is resolved between him and the Council, it's impossible to say what the final investments will be made, de Blasio said.</p>
<p>Will the former mayor find his footing or will he remain a hot take (https://hellgatenyc.com/nyc-hot-take-bracket-goes-from-elite-eight-to-final-four)? Watch this space.</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>The New York Times Has Lost Its Way</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p><u>Echo Chambers</u></p>
<p><u>Recent Incidents</u></p>
<p><u>State of Journalism</u></p>
<p><u>Stats, Studies, and Academic</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Agree to Disagree COVID Series: Vaccine Mandates</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/agree-disagree-covid-series-vaccine-mandates</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:9954</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> July 02, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Health, Law</p>
<p>As more and more Americans become vaccinated, schools, employers, and healthcare facilities are facing a tough decision: Will they require students, employees, and caregivers to get the jab? Those who say “yes” cite safety concerns, particularly when dealing with vulnerable populations and call it a necessary step to return to normal. Those who say “no” argue these sorts of mandates violate individual rights, could expose recipients to potential dangers from the vaccines themselves, and set dangerous broader precedents when it comes to government overreach in public health. It is an especially timely question that pits health concerns against ideals of personal liberty. And it has practical implications as societies emerge from lockdown.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/L2CKDiWd-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/L2CKDiWd-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Lawrence Gostin</strong><br>Lawrence O. Gostin is University Professor, Georgetown University’s highest academic rank conferred by the University President. Prof. Gostin directs the O’Neill Institute for National and Global Health Law and is the Founding O’Neill Chair in Global Health Law. He served as Associate Dean for Research at Georgetown Law from 2004 to 2008. He is Professor of Medicine at Georgetown University and Professor of Public Health at the Johns Hopkins University. Prof. Gostin is the Director of the World Health Organization Collaborating Center on National and Global Health Law. The WHO Director-General has appointed Prof. Gostin to high-level positions, including the International Health Regulations (IHR) Roster of Experts and the Expert Advisory Panel on Mental Health.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Michael J. Anderson</strong><br>Michael is an experienced litigator with expertise in numerous practice areas, including real estate, business, employment, construction, environmental, landlord-tenant, municipal, family, criminal, and insurance coverage and defense. Prior to going solo in early 2012, he spent nearly seven years as an integral part of the complex commercial litigation division of a well-respected, mid-sized Milwaukee business law firm. Before that, he specialized in insurance coverage and insurance defense litigation.</p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> July 02, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Health, Law</p>
<p>As more and more Americans become vaccinated, schools, employers, and healthcare facilities are facing a tough decision: Will they require students, employees, and caregivers to get the jab? Those who say “yes” cite safety concerns, particularly when dealing with vulnerable populations and call it a necessary step to return to normal. Those who say “no” argue these sorts of mandates violate individual rights, could expose recipients to potential dangers from the vaccines themselves, and set dangerous broader precedents when it comes to government overreach in public health. It is an especially timely question that pits health concerns against ideals of personal liberty. And it has practical implications as societies emerge from lockdown.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/L2CKDiWd-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/L2CKDiWd-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Lawrence Gostin</strong><br>Lawrence O. Gostin is University Professor, Georgetown University’s highest academic rank conferred by the University President. Prof. Gostin directs the O’Neill Institute for National and Global Health Law and is the Founding O’Neill Chair in Global Health Law. He served as Associate Dean for Research at Georgetown Law from 2004 to 2008. He is Professor of Medicine at Georgetown University and Professor of Public Health at the Johns Hopkins University. Prof. Gostin is the Director of the World Health Organization Collaborating Center on National and Global Health Law. The WHO Director-General has appointed Prof. Gostin to high-level positions, including the International Health Regulations (IHR) Roster of Experts and the Expert Advisory Panel on Mental Health.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Michael J. Anderson</strong><br>Michael is an experienced litigator with expertise in numerous practice areas, including real estate, business, employment, construction, environmental, landlord-tenant, municipal, family, criminal, and insurance coverage and defense. Prior to going solo in early 2012, he spent nearly seven years as an integral part of the complex commercial litigation division of a well-respected, mid-sized Milwaukee business law firm. Before that, he specialized in insurance coverage and insurance defense litigation.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Is Taiwan Indefensible?</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/taiwan-indefensible-0</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10174</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> May 20, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Politics, U.S., World</p>
<p>The fate of Taiwan is uncertain. As a revanchist China builds up forces near the island, the Biden administration is warning Beijing against an invasion, bolstering its defense with the sale of military hardware. While the United States does not officially recognize Taiwan’s government, it remains its strongest international backer. Beijing, meanwhile, sees Taiwan as lost territory, which needs to be “reunified” with the mainland. Recently, Beijing sent 25 warplanes into Taiwan's air defense identification zone, the largest ever incursion into the region by the People’s Liberation Army. And some argue that the scale of China’s military presence has already surpassed anything the U.S. or Taiwan militaries could stop. It is indefensible, both militarily and from a political capital perspective; the notion of risking American soldiers in this geostrategic flashpoint unthinkable. Others say American credibility is actually on the line, that the U.S. could indeed win if it had to, and that its political posturing should reflect that. So, here’s our question: Is Taiwan indefensible?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://www.youtube.com/embed/RRZd_Kxvhvo' target='_blank'>https://www.youtube.com/embed/RRZd_Kxvhvo</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Lyle J. Goldstein</strong><br>Lyle J. Goldstein is a research professor in the China Maritime Studies Institute at the United States Naval War College in Newport, RI. In addition to Chinese, he also speaks Russian, and he is also an affiliate of the new Russia Maritime Studies Institute (RMSI) at Naval War College. He is the author of "Meeting China Halfway: How to Defuse the Emerging US-China Rivalry," among others.</p>
<p><strong>Charlie Glaser</strong><br>Charlie Glaser is a professor of political science and international affairs and director of the Elliott School's Institute for Security and Conflict Studies at George Washington University. His research focuses on international relations theory and international security policy. He is the author of “Rational Theory of International Politics: The Logic of Competition and Cooperation,” among others.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Elbridge Colby</strong><br>Elbridge Colby served as the deputy assistant secretary of defense for strategy and force development from 2017–2018 and is the former director of the defense program at the Center for a New American Security. He currently serves as co-founder and principal of The Marathon Initiative, a non-profit research organization focused on diplomatic, military, and economic strategies within great power rivalries. He is also the author of "The Strategy of Denial: American Defense in an Age of Great Power Conflict."</p>
<p><strong>Elizabeth Larus</strong><br>Elizabeth Larus is professor and department chair of Political Science and International Affairs at the University of Mary Washington. She has 30 years of research and practical experience in the domestic politics and foreign relations of China, Taiwan and Hong Kong and has authored three books on China and more than twenty academic articles and book chapters on international relations in the Asia-Pacific. She is currently conducting research on U.S. naval diplomacy in the Asia-Pacific.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Is Taiwan Indefensible?</em></p>
<p><u>Strategic Clarity vs. Ambiguity</u></p>
<p><u>Global State of Affairs</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>War Games</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> May 20, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Politics, U.S., World</p>
<p>The fate of Taiwan is uncertain. As a revanchist China builds up forces near the island, the Biden administration is warning Beijing against an invasion, bolstering its defense with the sale of military hardware. While the United States does not officially recognize Taiwan’s government, it remains its strongest international backer. Beijing, meanwhile, sees Taiwan as lost territory, which needs to be “reunified” with the mainland. Recently, Beijing sent 25 warplanes into Taiwan's air defense identification zone, the largest ever incursion into the region by the People’s Liberation Army. And some argue that the scale of China’s military presence has already surpassed anything the U.S. or Taiwan militaries could stop. It is indefensible, both militarily and from a political capital perspective; the notion of risking American soldiers in this geostrategic flashpoint unthinkable. Others say American credibility is actually on the line, that the U.S. could indeed win if it had to, and that its political posturing should reflect that. So, here’s our question: Is Taiwan indefensible?</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://www.youtube.com/embed/RRZd_Kxvhvo' target='_blank'>https://www.youtube.com/embed/RRZd_Kxvhvo</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Lyle J. Goldstein</strong><br>Lyle J. Goldstein is a research professor in the China Maritime Studies Institute at the United States Naval War College in Newport, RI. In addition to Chinese, he also speaks Russian, and he is also an affiliate of the new Russia Maritime Studies Institute (RMSI) at Naval War College. He is the author of "Meeting China Halfway: How to Defuse the Emerging US-China Rivalry," among others.</p>
<p><strong>Charlie Glaser</strong><br>Charlie Glaser is a professor of political science and international affairs and director of the Elliott School's Institute for Security and Conflict Studies at George Washington University. His research focuses on international relations theory and international security policy. He is the author of “Rational Theory of International Politics: The Logic of Competition and Cooperation,” among others.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Elbridge Colby</strong><br>Elbridge Colby served as the deputy assistant secretary of defense for strategy and force development from 2017–2018 and is the former director of the defense program at the Center for a New American Security. He currently serves as co-founder and principal of The Marathon Initiative, a non-profit research organization focused on diplomatic, military, and economic strategies within great power rivalries. He is also the author of "The Strategy of Denial: American Defense in an Age of Great Power Conflict."</p>
<p><strong>Elizabeth Larus</strong><br>Elizabeth Larus is professor and department chair of Political Science and International Affairs at the University of Mary Washington. She has 30 years of research and practical experience in the domestic politics and foreign relations of China, Taiwan and Hong Kong and has authored three books on China and more than twenty academic articles and book chapters on international relations in the Asia-Pacific. She is currently conducting research on U.S. naval diplomacy in the Asia-Pacific.</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Is Taiwan Indefensible?</em></p>
<p><u>Strategic Clarity vs. Ambiguity</u></p>
<p><u>Global State of Affairs</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>War Games</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Agree to Disagree: Covid Series Do We Need Vaccine Passports?</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/agree-disagree-covid-series-vaccine-passports</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:9956</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> May 12, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Health, Law, World</p>
<p>Will you need a digital passport to prove you’ve been vaccinated the next time you try to board a flight or get into a concert? The idea is already being tested in Israel and governments around the world including the Biden administration are exploring what vaccine credentials might look like. For some, these digital tools are a golden ticket back to “normal” life. But for others, these tools raise dire concerns about privacy, civil rights, and equitable access.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/aL7L8uxA-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/aL7L8uxA-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Peter Baldwin</strong><br>Peter Baldwin is especially interested in the historical development of the modern state—a broad field that has led him in many different directions. Two aspects of his work unify it. First, he has attempted to understand contemporary issues from a long historical perspective, whether that be the class coalitions that cemented the modern welfare state, the 19th century public health strategies that provided the template by which the AIDS epidemic was fought a century later, the battles over intellectual property stretching back three centuries that inform, indeed determine, our current battles over copyright, downloading, and internet piracy, or the ever-growing role of law as the socializer of last resort in modern society. Second, he has studied the development of the state transnationally, using detailed and often archival sources in half a dozen languages to marry a broad comparative approach to rigorous empiricism. His books have dealt, above all, with France, Germany, Britain, Sweden, Denmark, and the United States. He has published works on the comparative history of the welfare state, on social policy more broadly, on public health, and on the history of copyright. Other interests have included Nazi Germany and historiography. His latest book is a global history of the development of law and crime over the past 2000 years. He has forthcoming books on open access and on the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Jay Stanley</strong><br>Jay Stanley is a senior policy analyst with the ACLU Speech, Privacy, and Technology Project, where he researches, writes, and speaks about technology-related privacy and civil liberties issues and their future. He is the editor of the ACLU’s Free Future blog and has authored and co-authored a variety of influential ACLU reports on privacy and technology topics. Before joining the ACLU, he was an analyst at the technology research firm Forrester, served as American politics editor of Facts on File’s World News Digest, and was national newswire editor at Medialink. He is a graduate of Williams College and holds an M.A. in American history from the University of Virginia.</p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> May 12, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Health, Law, World</p>
<p>Will you need a digital passport to prove you’ve been vaccinated the next time you try to board a flight or get into a concert? The idea is already being tested in Israel and governments around the world including the Biden administration are exploring what vaccine credentials might look like. For some, these digital tools are a golden ticket back to “normal” life. But for others, these tools raise dire concerns about privacy, civil rights, and equitable access.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/aL7L8uxA-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/aL7L8uxA-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Peter Baldwin</strong><br>Peter Baldwin is especially interested in the historical development of the modern state—a broad field that has led him in many different directions. Two aspects of his work unify it. First, he has attempted to understand contemporary issues from a long historical perspective, whether that be the class coalitions that cemented the modern welfare state, the 19th century public health strategies that provided the template by which the AIDS epidemic was fought a century later, the battles over intellectual property stretching back three centuries that inform, indeed determine, our current battles over copyright, downloading, and internet piracy, or the ever-growing role of law as the socializer of last resort in modern society. Second, he has studied the development of the state transnationally, using detailed and often archival sources in half a dozen languages to marry a broad comparative approach to rigorous empiricism. His books have dealt, above all, with France, Germany, Britain, Sweden, Denmark, and the United States. He has published works on the comparative history of the welfare state, on social policy more broadly, on public health, and on the history of copyright. Other interests have included Nazi Germany and historiography. His latest book is a global history of the development of law and crime over the past 2000 years. He has forthcoming books on open access and on the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Jay Stanley</strong><br>Jay Stanley is a senior policy analyst with the ACLU Speech, Privacy, and Technology Project, where he researches, writes, and speaks about technology-related privacy and civil liberties issues and their future. He is the editor of the ACLU’s Free Future blog and has authored and co-authored a variety of influential ACLU reports on privacy and technology topics. Before joining the ACLU, he was an analyst at the technology research firm Forrester, served as American politics editor of Facts on File’s World News Digest, and was national newswire editor at Medialink. He is a graduate of Williams College and holds an M.A. in American history from the University of Virginia.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Legalize Psychedelics</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/legalize-psychedelics</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10234</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> April 22, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Culture, Health, Law, Science</p>
<p><div>Psychedelics, in medical terms, is an inexact category of drugs that affect perceptions and cognition. Their proponents say 1960s-era associations have undermined exciting research in the field of neuroscience. Psychedelics should be made much more widely available, they contend, to treat a range of mental and emotional issues, as well as to ascertain a more profound sense of ourselves. People should also be empowered to make their own decisions in its use. Not so fast, say opponents. These are powerful substances. And society does not know enough about the broader consequences of greatly increasing access. Cautionary tales should be heeded. Either way, like cannabis, the movement for wider use is growing. So... here’s our debate: Should society legalize psychedelics?</div>
<div>To kick things off, psychedelics comedian Sarah Rose Siskind offers up her two cents.</div></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/RQY1U4Vn-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/RQY1U4Vn-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rick Doblin</strong><br>Rick Doblin is the founder and executive director of the Multidisciplinary Association for Psychedelic Studies. He received his doctorate in Public Policy from Harvard's Kennedy School of Government, and his professional goal is to help develop legal contexts for the beneficial uses of psychedelics and marijuana, primarily as prescription medicines but also for personal growth for otherwise healthy people, and eventually to become a legally licensed psychedelic therapist.</p>
<p><strong>Bia Labate</strong><br>Dr. Beatriz Caiuby Labate (Bia Labate) is a queer Brazilian anthropologist based in San Francisco. Her main areas of interest are the study of plant medicines, drug policy, shamanism, ritual, religion, and social justice. She is executive director of the Chacruna Institute for Psychedelic Plant Medicines, a public education and culture specialist at the Multidisciplinary Association for Psychedelic Studies, and adjunct faculty at the East-West Psychology Program at the California Institute of Integral Studies. She is also co-founder of the Interdisciplinary Group for Psychoactive Studies in Brazil. She is the author, co-author, and co-editor of twenty-two books, two special-edition journals, and several peer-reviewed articles.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Jeffrey Lieberman</strong><br>Jeffrey A. Lieberman, M.D., is Professor and Chairman of Psychiatry at the Columbia University College of Physicians and Surgeons and served as President of the American Psychiatric Association in 2013 and 2014. He has authored or co-authored over 700 articles published in scientific literature and wrote or edited 17 books on mental illness and psychiatry, including "Shrinks: the Untold Story of Psychiatry" (Little Brown 2015) for general audiences.</p>
<p><strong>Kevin Sabet</strong><br><span class="TextRun  BCX0 SCXO104402131" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun  BCX0 SCXO104402131">Described by NBC as the “prodigy” of drug politics and policy, Kevin A. Sabet, PhD, is an author, consultant, former advisor to the presidential administrations of Bill Clinton, Barack Obama, and George W. Bush, an affiliate of Yale University’s Institution for Social and Policy Studies and the Medical School, and serves as the President and CEO of both Smart Approaches to Marijuana, which he founded with former Congressman Patrick Kennedy in 2013 and the Foundation for Drug Policy Solutions. He has studied, researched, written about, and implemented drug policy for more than 25 years. His work has been featured on the front page of the </span></span><span class="TextRun  BCX0 SCXO104402131" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun  BCX0 SCXO104402131">New York Times</span></span><span class="TextRun  BCX0 SCXO104402131" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun  BCX0 SCXO104402131"> and in virtually every major media publication and news channel on the subject of drug policy. Dr. Sabet’s first book, “Reefer Sanity: Seven Great Myths About Marijuana,” was published in 2013, and its second edition was released in 2018. His bestselling book, “Smokescreen: What the Marijuana Industry Doesn’t Want You to Know,” released in 2021 to critical acclaim.</span></span></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> April 22, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Culture, Health, Law, Science</p>
<p><div>Psychedelics, in medical terms, is an inexact category of drugs that affect perceptions and cognition. Their proponents say 1960s-era associations have undermined exciting research in the field of neuroscience. Psychedelics should be made much more widely available, they contend, to treat a range of mental and emotional issues, as well as to ascertain a more profound sense of ourselves. People should also be empowered to make their own decisions in its use. Not so fast, say opponents. These are powerful substances. And society does not know enough about the broader consequences of greatly increasing access. Cautionary tales should be heeded. Either way, like cannabis, the movement for wider use is growing. So... here’s our debate: Should society legalize psychedelics?</div>
<div>To kick things off, psychedelics comedian Sarah Rose Siskind offers up her two cents.</div></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/RQY1U4Vn-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/RQY1U4Vn-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rick Doblin</strong><br>Rick Doblin is the founder and executive director of the Multidisciplinary Association for Psychedelic Studies. He received his doctorate in Public Policy from Harvard's Kennedy School of Government, and his professional goal is to help develop legal contexts for the beneficial uses of psychedelics and marijuana, primarily as prescription medicines but also for personal growth for otherwise healthy people, and eventually to become a legally licensed psychedelic therapist.</p>
<p><strong>Bia Labate</strong><br>Dr. Beatriz Caiuby Labate (Bia Labate) is a queer Brazilian anthropologist based in San Francisco. Her main areas of interest are the study of plant medicines, drug policy, shamanism, ritual, religion, and social justice. She is executive director of the Chacruna Institute for Psychedelic Plant Medicines, a public education and culture specialist at the Multidisciplinary Association for Psychedelic Studies, and adjunct faculty at the East-West Psychology Program at the California Institute of Integral Studies. She is also co-founder of the Interdisciplinary Group for Psychoactive Studies in Brazil. She is the author, co-author, and co-editor of twenty-two books, two special-edition journals, and several peer-reviewed articles.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Jeffrey Lieberman</strong><br>Jeffrey A. Lieberman, M.D., is Professor and Chairman of Psychiatry at the Columbia University College of Physicians and Surgeons and served as President of the American Psychiatric Association in 2013 and 2014. He has authored or co-authored over 700 articles published in scientific literature and wrote or edited 17 books on mental illness and psychiatry, including "Shrinks: the Untold Story of Psychiatry" (Little Brown 2015) for general audiences.</p>
<p><strong>Kevin Sabet</strong><br><span class="TextRun  BCX0 SCXO104402131" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun  BCX0 SCXO104402131">Described by NBC as the “prodigy” of drug politics and policy, Kevin A. Sabet, PhD, is an author, consultant, former advisor to the presidential administrations of Bill Clinton, Barack Obama, and George W. Bush, an affiliate of Yale University’s Institution for Social and Policy Studies and the Medical School, and serves as the President and CEO of both Smart Approaches to Marijuana, which he founded with former Congressman Patrick Kennedy in 2013 and the Foundation for Drug Policy Solutions. He has studied, researched, written about, and implemented drug policy for more than 25 years. His work has been featured on the front page of the </span></span><span class="TextRun  BCX0 SCXO104402131" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun  BCX0 SCXO104402131">New York Times</span></span><span class="TextRun  BCX0 SCXO104402131" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US" data-contrast="none"><span class="NormalTextRun  BCX0 SCXO104402131"> and in virtually every major media publication and news channel on the subject of drug policy. Dr. Sabet’s first book, “Reefer Sanity: Seven Great Myths About Marijuana,” was published in 2013, and its second edition was released in 2018. His bestselling book, “Smokescreen: What the Marijuana Industry Doesn’t Want You to Know,” released in 2021 to critical acclaim.</span></span></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Agree to Disagree COVID Series: Vaccine Patents</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/agree-disagree-covid-series-vaccine-patents</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:9958</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> April 09, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Health, Law</p>
<p><p class="rtecenter">India and South Africa have petitioned the World Trade Organization to suspend intellectual property protections for Covid-19 vaccines. These nations – along with a coalition of scholars, activists, and nonprofit organizations – argue that developing nations are at risk of waiting years to get full access to the vaccines unless these protections are lifted. But their opponents say suspending patent protections will do little to speed up the manufacturing process. Instead, undermining these protections will ensure that the next time the world needs an emergency vaccine, governments and pharmaceuticals will be unable to act as swiftly. It’s a debate emblematic of the uneven vaccine rollout, and strikes at the core of society’s ability to act quickly.</p></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/L5Xj3Na1-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/L5Xj3Na1-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Thomas Cueni</strong><br>Thomas Cueni is Director General of IFPMA, the global association of pharmaceutical research companies, based in Geneva, and Secretary of the Global Biopharmaceutical CEO Roundtable (BCR). In this capacity, Thomas Cueni was instrumental in creating the AMR Action Fund, a collective venture launched in July 2020 to bridge the current gap in funding for the development of new antibiotics. Thomas Cueni represents the innovative biopharmaceutical industry on the ACT Accelerator, the Access to COVID-19 Tools (ACT) Accelerator, a unique global collaboration to accelerate development, production, and equitable access to COVID-19 tests, treatments, and vaccines. Thomas Cueni is Chair of the Business Committee at the OECD Health Committee and also serves on the Board of Directors of the City Cancer Challenge (CCan), an initiative aiming to improve cancer care in major cities in low- and middle-income countries. Cueni also serves as industry co-chair of the APEC Biopharmaceutical WG on Ethics. Furthermore, he is Chair of the Board of the cross-sectoral AMR Industry Alliance, a group committed to tackling the threat of antimicrobial resistance that includes more than 100 companies and associations representing Rx pharma, generics, biotech, and diagnostics. Prior to joining IFPMA, he was Secretary General of Interpharma, the association of pharmaceutical research companies in Switzerland, and for many years was a member of the Board and Chair of a key committee of the EFPIA. Prior to his appointment with Interpharma, Thomas Cueni had a career as a journalist, inter alia as a London correspondent for the "Basler Zeitung" and "Der Bund", and he served as a Swiss career diplomat with postings in Paris (OECD) and Vienna (IAEA, UNIDO). He studied at the University of Basel, the London School of Economics, and the Geneva Graduate Institute for International Studies and has Master's degrees in economics (University of Basel) and politics (London School of Economics).</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Brook Baker</strong><br>Professor Baker teaches disability discrimination law, negotiations, and a new course on human rights, intellectual property, and access to medicines. He taught and consulted in South African law schools and law school clinics between 1997 and 2012. Professor Baker is an honorary research fellow at the University of KwaZulu Natal in Durban, South Africa.
Professor Baker is also a senior policy analyst for Health GAP (Global Access Project) and is actively engaged in campaigns for universal access to treatment, prevention, and care for people living with HIV/AIDS, especially expanded and improved medical treatment. More recently, he has been working on accelerating research on and equitable global access to vaccines, medicines, and diagnostics to respond to the COVID-19 pandemic. He has written and consulted extensively on intellectual property rights, trade, investor-state dispute settlement, access to medicines, and medicines regulatory policy, including with the African Union, NEPAD, South Africa, Uganda, ASEAN, Thailand, Indonesia, Brazil, Venezuela, CARICOM, UK DfID, the World Health Organization, the Millennium Development Goals Project, the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis, and Malaria, the Open Society Institute, UNAIDS, UNDP, Unitaid, the Medicines Patent Pool, the Global Commission on HIV and the Law, and others. He has served as a key alternative board member and board member of the NGO delegation to Unitaid, which acts to improve market dynamics and early market entry of medicines and diagnostics needed to address HIV/AIDS, TB, Hepatitis C, and malaria.
He is presently a civil society representative to the Therapeutics Pillar of the Access to COVID-19 Tools Accelerator. Professor Baker also works on policy issues concerning the Global Fund and the US PEPFAR Program and how those priority disease initiatives might contribute more broadly to improving health care delivery in developing countries. Finally, he analyzes resource needs for global health, innovative financing mechanisms, and IMF macroeconomic policies that restrict increased government and donor spending on health and education in developing countries.</p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> April 09, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Health, Law</p>
<p><p class="rtecenter">India and South Africa have petitioned the World Trade Organization to suspend intellectual property protections for Covid-19 vaccines. These nations – along with a coalition of scholars, activists, and nonprofit organizations – argue that developing nations are at risk of waiting years to get full access to the vaccines unless these protections are lifted. But their opponents say suspending patent protections will do little to speed up the manufacturing process. Instead, undermining these protections will ensure that the next time the world needs an emergency vaccine, governments and pharmaceuticals will be unable to act as swiftly. It’s a debate emblematic of the uneven vaccine rollout, and strikes at the core of society’s ability to act quickly.</p></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/L5Xj3Na1-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/L5Xj3Na1-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Thomas Cueni</strong><br>Thomas Cueni is Director General of IFPMA, the global association of pharmaceutical research companies, based in Geneva, and Secretary of the Global Biopharmaceutical CEO Roundtable (BCR). In this capacity, Thomas Cueni was instrumental in creating the AMR Action Fund, a collective venture launched in July 2020 to bridge the current gap in funding for the development of new antibiotics. Thomas Cueni represents the innovative biopharmaceutical industry on the ACT Accelerator, the Access to COVID-19 Tools (ACT) Accelerator, a unique global collaboration to accelerate development, production, and equitable access to COVID-19 tests, treatments, and vaccines. Thomas Cueni is Chair of the Business Committee at the OECD Health Committee and also serves on the Board of Directors of the City Cancer Challenge (CCan), an initiative aiming to improve cancer care in major cities in low- and middle-income countries. Cueni also serves as industry co-chair of the APEC Biopharmaceutical WG on Ethics. Furthermore, he is Chair of the Board of the cross-sectoral AMR Industry Alliance, a group committed to tackling the threat of antimicrobial resistance that includes more than 100 companies and associations representing Rx pharma, generics, biotech, and diagnostics. Prior to joining IFPMA, he was Secretary General of Interpharma, the association of pharmaceutical research companies in Switzerland, and for many years was a member of the Board and Chair of a key committee of the EFPIA. Prior to his appointment with Interpharma, Thomas Cueni had a career as a journalist, inter alia as a London correspondent for the "Basler Zeitung" and "Der Bund", and he served as a Swiss career diplomat with postings in Paris (OECD) and Vienna (IAEA, UNIDO). He studied at the University of Basel, the London School of Economics, and the Geneva Graduate Institute for International Studies and has Master's degrees in economics (University of Basel) and politics (London School of Economics).</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Brook Baker</strong><br>Professor Baker teaches disability discrimination law, negotiations, and a new course on human rights, intellectual property, and access to medicines. He taught and consulted in South African law schools and law school clinics between 1997 and 2012. Professor Baker is an honorary research fellow at the University of KwaZulu Natal in Durban, South Africa.
Professor Baker is also a senior policy analyst for Health GAP (Global Access Project) and is actively engaged in campaigns for universal access to treatment, prevention, and care for people living with HIV/AIDS, especially expanded and improved medical treatment. More recently, he has been working on accelerating research on and equitable global access to vaccines, medicines, and diagnostics to respond to the COVID-19 pandemic. He has written and consulted extensively on intellectual property rights, trade, investor-state dispute settlement, access to medicines, and medicines regulatory policy, including with the African Union, NEPAD, South Africa, Uganda, ASEAN, Thailand, Indonesia, Brazil, Venezuela, CARICOM, UK DfID, the World Health Organization, the Millennium Development Goals Project, the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis, and Malaria, the Open Society Institute, UNAIDS, UNDP, Unitaid, the Medicines Patent Pool, the Global Commission on HIV and the Law, and others. He has served as a key alternative board member and board member of the NGO delegation to Unitaid, which acts to improve market dynamics and early market entry of medicines and diagnostics needed to address HIV/AIDS, TB, Hepatitis C, and malaria.
He is presently a civil society representative to the Therapeutics Pillar of the Access to COVID-19 Tools Accelerator. Professor Baker also works on policy issues concerning the Global Fund and the US PEPFAR Program and how those priority disease initiatives might contribute more broadly to improving health care delivery in developing countries. Finally, he analyzes resource needs for global health, innovative financing mechanisms, and IMF macroeconomic policies that restrict increased government and donor spending on health and education in developing countries.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Should America Forgive Student Debt?</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/forgive-student-debt-0</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10107</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> March 25, 2021</p>
<p>Facing growing discontent over the rising student loan repayments in the middle of a Pandemic, many prominent Democrats – and some Republicans – are calling on Washington to cancel much of the $1.7 trillion that Americans owe. They say it would help level the playing field, stimulate the economy, unbridle graduates to pursue what they want, and offer a life-line amidst the largest health crisis the world has seen in decades. But others argue that it would balloon the federal deficit, waste taxpayer money, and benefit wealthy borrowers who don’t need their student loans cancelled. In this especially timely debate, we ask: Should America forgive student debt?
<strong>A private donor and VIP premiere will be taking place on Thursday, March 25th. The debate will be made publicly available on Friday March 26th on podcast, radio and video. </strong><script src="https://apps.elfsight.com/p/platform.js" defer></script>
<div class="elfsight-app-442ad472-224a-43c8-9bbb-c090f5ee569e"></div></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/sBYcREah-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/sBYcREah-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Ashley Harrington</strong><br>Ashley Harrington is the Federal Advocacy Director and Senior Counsel at the Center for Responsible Lending. She also served as the director of the National Social Justice Program and was a member of the Public Policy and Government Affairs team. Originally from Greensboro, North Carolina, Ashley earned her J.D. from New York University School of Law and was later awarded the Vanderbilt Medal for outstanding service to the law school community.</p>
<p><strong>Dalié Jiménez</strong><br>Dalié Jiménez is the Student Loan Law Initiative Director and Professor at the University of California, Irvine School of Law. She previously worked at the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, working on debt collection, debt relief, credit reporting, and student loan issues. Jiménez chairs the Association of American Law Schools' (AALS) Section on Consumer and Commercial Law as well as the Law & Society Association’s Household Finance collaborative research network. She earned her juris doctorate at Harvard Law School.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Nick Gillespie</strong><br>Nick Gillespie is the editor-at-large of Reason, the libertarian magazine of "free minds and free markets," and the host of The Reason Interview podcast with Nick Gillespie. A two-time finalist for the digital National Magazine Awards, he is co-author of "The Declaration of Independents: How Libertarian Politics Can Fix What's Wrong with America" and holds a Ph.D. in American literature.
Full bio is available <a href="https://reason.com/people/nick-gillespie/">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Beth Akers</strong><br>Akers is a resident scholar at the American Enterprise Institute, where her work focuses on the economics of higher education. Previously, she was a senior fellow at the Manhattan Institute, a fellow at the Brookings Institution, and a staff economist with the Council of Economic Advisors under President George W. Bush. Akers is the co-author of "Game of Loans" and the author of the forthcoming book "Making College Pay: An Economist Explains How to Make a Smart Bet on Higher Education."</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Student Debt Forgiveness Folly</strong> <small>2023-02-07 22:41:30</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>In this week's The Reason Roundtable, editors Matt Welch, (https://reason.com/people/matt-welch/) Peter Suderman (https://reason.com/people/peter-suderman/), and Nick Gillespie (https://reason.com/people/nick-gillespie/) are joined by Associate Editor Liz Wolfe (https://reason.com/people/liz-wolfe/) as they criticize President Joe Biden's recently announced student loan forgiveness program.</p>
<p>2:07: Biden's executive order to cancel student debt.</p>
<p>29:33: Weekly Listener Question:</p>
<p>Why is the abortion debate within libertarianism treated so dismissively by everyone on The Reason Roundtable? Most other topics are approached with an evenhandedness that attempts to at least acknowledge that those who disagree with the panelists are doing so in good faith and are at least attempting to be reasonable. It's not surprising that everyone on The Roundtable is pro-choice. But why can't you all acknowledge your disagreement with pro-life libertarians is over fundamental values that libertarianism can't resolve? The way you approach the subject makes your own colleagues like Liz Wolfe into pariah libertarians who have no place in the movement. Pro-life libertarians begin with the premise that life starts at conception and that all humans have human rights. Further, in this line of thinking, the most foundational right (if any rights exist at all) is the right to not be killed without just cause. And so we conclude that the right of a baby to not be killed outweighs a woman's right to not be pregnant or not to provide the sustenance a growing baby needs to live in her womb. It is perfectly rational for someone else to say that he values a woman's autonomy more than the rights of a potential human life (or even an actual human life), but these two positions are irreconcilable. Why does everyone on The Roundtable go around masquerading as if their position on abortion is based on pure reason and science and the only acceptable libertarian position instead of acknowledging that it really boils down to values and you don't value a baby's life before she is born more than the mother's autonomy?</p>
<p>49:58: This week's cultural recommendations.</p>
<p>Mentioned in this podcast:</p>
<p>"TGIF: Debts Forgiven and Debts Forgotten (https://www.commonsense.news/p/tgif-debts-forgiven-and-debts-forgotten)," by Nick Gillespie</p>
<p>"Emma Camp: Student Loan Forgiveness Is Bad News and Bad Policy (https://reason.com/podcast/2022/08/26/emma-camp-student-loan-forgiveness-is-bad-news-and-bad-policy/)," by Peter Suderman</p>
<p>"The Student Loan Debate Isn't Just About Money. It's About the Experiences Students Like Me Sacrificed. (https://reason.com/2022/08/25/the-student-loan-debate-isnt-just-about-money-its-about-the-experiences-students-like-me-sacrificed/)" by Fiona Harrigan</p>
<p>"Forgiving Student Debt Without Abolishing the Federal Loan Program Is Morally Wrong (https://reason.com/2022/08/24/biden-student-loan-debt-forgiveness-cancel/)," by Robby Soave
"Debate: Forgive Student Debt? (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wuJB9ZohQNI)" by Intelligence Squared Debates</p>
<p>"Get Ready for the Post-Roe Sex Police! (https://reason.com/2022/06/24/get-ready-for-the-post-roe-sex-police/)" by Nick Gillespie</p>
<p>Send your questions to roundtable@reason.com (mailto:roundtable@reason.com). Be sure to include your social media handle and the correct pronunciation of your name.</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Forgive Student Debt</em></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Economic and Social Implications of Higher Education</u></p>
<p><u>Student Debt Relif Plans</u></p>
<p><u>(Pre-Biden Administration)</u></p>
<p><u>Covid Relief</u></p>
<p><u>Stats, Polling & Public Opinion</u></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> March 25, 2021</p>
<p>Facing growing discontent over the rising student loan repayments in the middle of a Pandemic, many prominent Democrats – and some Republicans – are calling on Washington to cancel much of the $1.7 trillion that Americans owe. They say it would help level the playing field, stimulate the economy, unbridle graduates to pursue what they want, and offer a life-line amidst the largest health crisis the world has seen in decades. But others argue that it would balloon the federal deficit, waste taxpayer money, and benefit wealthy borrowers who don’t need their student loans cancelled. In this especially timely debate, we ask: Should America forgive student debt?
<strong>A private donor and VIP premiere will be taking place on Thursday, March 25th. The debate will be made publicly available on Friday March 26th on podcast, radio and video. </strong><script src="https://apps.elfsight.com/p/platform.js" defer></script>
<div class="elfsight-app-442ad472-224a-43c8-9bbb-c090f5ee569e"></div></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/sBYcREah-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/sBYcREah-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Ashley Harrington</strong><br>Ashley Harrington is the Federal Advocacy Director and Senior Counsel at the Center for Responsible Lending. She also served as the director of the National Social Justice Program and was a member of the Public Policy and Government Affairs team. Originally from Greensboro, North Carolina, Ashley earned her J.D. from New York University School of Law and was later awarded the Vanderbilt Medal for outstanding service to the law school community.</p>
<p><strong>Dalié Jiménez</strong><br>Dalié Jiménez is the Student Loan Law Initiative Director and Professor at the University of California, Irvine School of Law. She previously worked at the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, working on debt collection, debt relief, credit reporting, and student loan issues. Jiménez chairs the Association of American Law Schools' (AALS) Section on Consumer and Commercial Law as well as the Law & Society Association’s Household Finance collaborative research network. She earned her juris doctorate at Harvard Law School.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Nick Gillespie</strong><br>Nick Gillespie is the editor-at-large of Reason, the libertarian magazine of "free minds and free markets," and the host of The Reason Interview podcast with Nick Gillespie. A two-time finalist for the digital National Magazine Awards, he is co-author of "The Declaration of Independents: How Libertarian Politics Can Fix What's Wrong with America" and holds a Ph.D. in American literature.
Full bio is available <a href="https://reason.com/people/nick-gillespie/">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Beth Akers</strong><br>Akers is a resident scholar at the American Enterprise Institute, where her work focuses on the economics of higher education. Previously, she was a senior fellow at the Manhattan Institute, a fellow at the Brookings Institution, and a staff economist with the Council of Economic Advisors under President George W. Bush. Akers is the co-author of "Game of Loans" and the author of the forthcoming book "Making College Pay: An Economist Explains How to Make a Smart Bet on Higher Education."</p>
<p><strong>Related News:</strong></p>
<div><strong>Student Debt Forgiveness Folly</strong> <small>2023-02-07 22:41:30</small></div>
<div class='news-content'><p>In this week's The Reason Roundtable, editors Matt Welch, (https://reason.com/people/matt-welch/) Peter Suderman (https://reason.com/people/peter-suderman/), and Nick Gillespie (https://reason.com/people/nick-gillespie/) are joined by Associate Editor Liz Wolfe (https://reason.com/people/liz-wolfe/) as they criticize President Joe Biden's recently announced student loan forgiveness program.</p>
<p>2:07: Biden's executive order to cancel student debt.</p>
<p>29:33: Weekly Listener Question:</p>
<p>Why is the abortion debate within libertarianism treated so dismissively by everyone on The Reason Roundtable? Most other topics are approached with an evenhandedness that attempts to at least acknowledge that those who disagree with the panelists are doing so in good faith and are at least attempting to be reasonable. It's not surprising that everyone on The Roundtable is pro-choice. But why can't you all acknowledge your disagreement with pro-life libertarians is over fundamental values that libertarianism can't resolve? The way you approach the subject makes your own colleagues like Liz Wolfe into pariah libertarians who have no place in the movement. Pro-life libertarians begin with the premise that life starts at conception and that all humans have human rights. Further, in this line of thinking, the most foundational right (if any rights exist at all) is the right to not be killed without just cause. And so we conclude that the right of a baby to not be killed outweighs a woman's right to not be pregnant or not to provide the sustenance a growing baby needs to live in her womb. It is perfectly rational for someone else to say that he values a woman's autonomy more than the rights of a potential human life (or even an actual human life), but these two positions are irreconcilable. Why does everyone on The Roundtable go around masquerading as if their position on abortion is based on pure reason and science and the only acceptable libertarian position instead of acknowledging that it really boils down to values and you don't value a baby's life before she is born more than the mother's autonomy?</p>
<p>49:58: This week's cultural recommendations.</p>
<p>Mentioned in this podcast:</p>
<p>"TGIF: Debts Forgiven and Debts Forgotten (https://www.commonsense.news/p/tgif-debts-forgiven-and-debts-forgotten)," by Nick Gillespie</p>
<p>"Emma Camp: Student Loan Forgiveness Is Bad News and Bad Policy (https://reason.com/podcast/2022/08/26/emma-camp-student-loan-forgiveness-is-bad-news-and-bad-policy/)," by Peter Suderman</p>
<p>"The Student Loan Debate Isn't Just About Money. It's About the Experiences Students Like Me Sacrificed. (https://reason.com/2022/08/25/the-student-loan-debate-isnt-just-about-money-its-about-the-experiences-students-like-me-sacrificed/)" by Fiona Harrigan</p>
<p>"Forgiving Student Debt Without Abolishing the Federal Loan Program Is Morally Wrong (https://reason.com/2022/08/24/biden-student-loan-debt-forgiveness-cancel/)," by Robby Soave
"Debate: Forgive Student Debt? (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wuJB9ZohQNI)" by Intelligence Squared Debates</p>
<p>"Get Ready for the Post-Roe Sex Police! (https://reason.com/2022/06/24/get-ready-for-the-post-roe-sex-police/)" by Nick Gillespie</p>
<p>Send your questions to roundtable@reason.com (mailto:roundtable@reason.com). Be sure to include your social media handle and the correct pronunciation of your name.</p></div>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Forgive Student Debt</em></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p><u>Economic and Social Implications of Higher Education</u></p>
<p><u>Student Debt Relif Plans</u></p>
<p><u>(Pre-Biden Administration)</u></p>
<p><u>Covid Relief</u></p>
<p><u>Stats, Polling & Public Opinion</u></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Agree to Disagree: The Filibuster</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/agree-disagree-filibuster</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:9982</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> March 19, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Law, Politics</p>
<p>How do you keep a bill from becoming law if you don’t have a majority in Congress? The answer comes from an 18th-century Dutch word with pirate roots: The filibuster. Though its derivation speaks of Caribbean marauders, its modern application is a political strategy that allows a 41-vote minority in the Senate to block legislation. Created after the U.S constitution was written, it effectively requires a supermajority to get most legislation done – something that’s left the current Democrat-controlled Congress grumbling, but cuts across both parties. So here’s the question: Should minorities have that power? Or is it time to kill the filibuster? Those in favor of killing it say the rule is arcane, anti-democratic, and often used to prevent the passage of matters like gun control and civil rights legislation. Those against its death say this little understood Senate rule serves as an important bulwark against the tyrannies of the majority, something with which America’s founding fathers were especially concerned. Either way, we figured the issue was ripe for debate.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/UFM2eSaV-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/UFM2eSaV-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Caroline Fredrickson</strong><br>Caroline Fredrickson joined the American Constitution Society for Law and Policy (ACS) in 2009 and serves as president. She is the author of "Under the Bus: How Working Women Are Being Run Over" (2015). Before joining ACS, Fredrickson served as the director of the ACLU’s Washington legislative office and as general counsel and legal director of NARAL Pro-Choice America. In addition, Fredrickson was chief of staff to Sen. Maria Cantwell and deputy chief of staff to then-Senate Democratic Leader Tom Daschle. During the Clinton administration, she served as special assistant to the president for legislative affairs. Fredrickson is a member of Law Students for Reproductive Justice's Advisory Board. In 2013, she was named a public member of the Administrative Conference of the United States. Fredrickson is co-chair of the National Constitution Center's Coalition for Freedom Advisory Board. In 2015, she was named a Demos senior fellow.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Thomas Jipping</strong><br>Thomas L. Jipping is a senior legal fellow for the Edwin Meese III Center for Legal and Judicial Studies, which is part of the Institute for Constitutional Government at Heritage. Tom joined Heritage in May 2018 after 15 years on the staff of U.S. Senator Orrin Hatch (R-Utah), including several as his chief counsel on the Senate Judiciary Committee. He spent the previous 13 years at two public policy organizations: Concerned Women for America, where he was a senior fellow in legal studies, and the Free Congress Foundation, where Tom served as Vice President for Policy and Director of the Center for Law and Democracy. Tom has developed a national reputation, among both liberals and conservatives, as an expert in the federal judiciary and, in particular, the appointment of federal judges. The Nation magazine, for example, has dubbed him "the right’s ablest analyst of confirmation fights." Tom’s scholarship includes articles in law and public policy journals as well as hundreds of op-eds and articles in both print and online publications. He has presented papers at conferences, including the American Political Science Association, and testified before legislative committees in the U.S. Senate and House and in several states. Tom received a B.A. with honors from Calvin College and both an M.A. in political science and a J.D., cum laude, from the State University of New York at Buffalo.</p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> March 19, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Law, Politics</p>
<p>How do you keep a bill from becoming law if you don’t have a majority in Congress? The answer comes from an 18th-century Dutch word with pirate roots: The filibuster. Though its derivation speaks of Caribbean marauders, its modern application is a political strategy that allows a 41-vote minority in the Senate to block legislation. Created after the U.S constitution was written, it effectively requires a supermajority to get most legislation done – something that’s left the current Democrat-controlled Congress grumbling, but cuts across both parties. So here’s the question: Should minorities have that power? Or is it time to kill the filibuster? Those in favor of killing it say the rule is arcane, anti-democratic, and often used to prevent the passage of matters like gun control and civil rights legislation. Those against its death say this little understood Senate rule serves as an important bulwark against the tyrannies of the majority, something with which America’s founding fathers were especially concerned. Either way, we figured the issue was ripe for debate.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/UFM2eSaV-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/UFM2eSaV-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Caroline Fredrickson</strong><br>Caroline Fredrickson joined the American Constitution Society for Law and Policy (ACS) in 2009 and serves as president. She is the author of "Under the Bus: How Working Women Are Being Run Over" (2015). Before joining ACS, Fredrickson served as the director of the ACLU’s Washington legislative office and as general counsel and legal director of NARAL Pro-Choice America. In addition, Fredrickson was chief of staff to Sen. Maria Cantwell and deputy chief of staff to then-Senate Democratic Leader Tom Daschle. During the Clinton administration, she served as special assistant to the president for legislative affairs. Fredrickson is a member of Law Students for Reproductive Justice's Advisory Board. In 2013, she was named a public member of the Administrative Conference of the United States. Fredrickson is co-chair of the National Constitution Center's Coalition for Freedom Advisory Board. In 2015, she was named a Demos senior fellow.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Thomas Jipping</strong><br>Thomas L. Jipping is a senior legal fellow for the Edwin Meese III Center for Legal and Judicial Studies, which is part of the Institute for Constitutional Government at Heritage. Tom joined Heritage in May 2018 after 15 years on the staff of U.S. Senator Orrin Hatch (R-Utah), including several as his chief counsel on the Senate Judiciary Committee. He spent the previous 13 years at two public policy organizations: Concerned Women for America, where he was a senior fellow in legal studies, and the Free Congress Foundation, where Tom served as Vice President for Policy and Director of the Center for Law and Democracy. Tom has developed a national reputation, among both liberals and conservatives, as an expert in the federal judiciary and, in particular, the appointment of federal judges. The Nation magazine, for example, has dubbed him "the right’s ablest analyst of confirmation fights." Tom’s scholarship includes articles in law and public policy journals as well as hundreds of op-eds and articles in both print and online publications. He has presented papers at conferences, including the American Political Science Association, and testified before legislative committees in the U.S. Senate and House and in several states. Tom received a B.A. with honors from Calvin College and both an M.A. in political science and a J.D., cum laude, from the State University of New York at Buffalo.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Agree to Disagree: Slavery Reparations</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/agree-disagree-slavery-reparations-0</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:9980</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> March 12, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Economics, Law, U.S.</p>
<p>Between 1525 and 1866, more than 12 million Africans were shipped to the New World as slaves. After some 200 years, slavery was abolished, and yet another century of Jim Crow, coupled with discriminatory housing and lending policies, contributed to its legacy. Dealing with the relics of that stain on American history is part of the national dilemma. But exactly how to do it is our question; something lawmakers in Washington are also now debating. A top aide to President Joe Biden recently said that the White House will ‘start acting now’ on reparations for African Americans. Some say it’s long over-due. Reparations, they say, are important to start to address the moral injury slavery inflicted. Others say direct payments to African Americans will divide the black community, exaggerate racial tensions and prove impossible to administer.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/B9icMYvC-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/B9icMYvC-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Cornell William Brooks</strong><br>Cornell William Brooks is a Hauser Professor of the Practice of Nonprofit Organizations and Professor of the Practice of Public Leadership and Social Justice at the Harvard Kennedy School. He is also the director of the William Monroe Trotter Collaborative for Social Justice at the School’s Center for Public Leadership, and Visiting Professor of the Practice of Prophetic Religion and Public Leadership at Harvard Divinity School. Brooks is the former president and CEO of the NAACP, a civil rights attorney, and an ordained minister.</p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> March 12, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Economics, Law, U.S.</p>
<p>Between 1525 and 1866, more than 12 million Africans were shipped to the New World as slaves. After some 200 years, slavery was abolished, and yet another century of Jim Crow, coupled with discriminatory housing and lending policies, contributed to its legacy. Dealing with the relics of that stain on American history is part of the national dilemma. But exactly how to do it is our question; something lawmakers in Washington are also now debating. A top aide to President Joe Biden recently said that the White House will ‘start acting now’ on reparations for African Americans. Some say it’s long over-due. Reparations, they say, are important to start to address the moral injury slavery inflicted. Others say direct payments to African Americans will divide the black community, exaggerate racial tensions and prove impossible to administer.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/B9icMYvC-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/B9icMYvC-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Cornell William Brooks</strong><br>Cornell William Brooks is a Hauser Professor of the Practice of Nonprofit Organizations and Professor of the Practice of Public Leadership and Social Justice at the Harvard Kennedy School. He is also the director of the William Monroe Trotter Collaborative for Social Justice at the School’s Center for Public Leadership, and Visiting Professor of the Practice of Prophetic Religion and Public Leadership at Harvard Divinity School. Brooks is the former president and CEO of the NAACP, a civil rights attorney, and an ordained minister.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Agree to Disagree: Sex with Robots</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/agree-disagree-sex-robots</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:9973</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> February 12, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Culture, Tech</p>
<p>As robots and artificial intelligence reached new heights, the relationship between humans and machines is getting closer. The sex tech industry is worth $30 billion annually and growing, as sex with synthetic companions is becoming far more widespread. But should it be? What are the social consequences? Some argue that sex robots will encourage bad behavior, perpetuate misogyny, and reinforce pornographic depictions of the opposite sex. Others say it can serve as a societal good for those who struggle with traditional relationships, and be employed as a safe outlet for otherwise toxic behavior. So in this episode of Agree to Disagree, we debate sex robots and their place in society.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/8K75NQm1-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/8K75NQm1-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Kate Devlin</strong><br>Kate is a senior lecturer in social and cultural artificial intelligence at King’s College London. Coming from an arts and humanities background (as an archaeologist) with a subsequent PhD in computer science, Kate has a demonstrable track record of combining diverse fields and methods of research. Her work investigates how people interact with and react to technology to understand how emerging and future technologies will affect us and the society in which we live. Her recent research has focused on cognition, sexuality, and intimacy and how these might be incorporated into cognitive systems. This formed the topic of her new book, "Turned On: Science, Sex, and Robots" (Bloomsbury, 2018). Kate is a member of Ada-AI, an international non-profit organization working to ensure that AI is developed and adopted in ways that are inclusive and equitable. Kate is a campaigner for gender equality and is involved in initiatives to improve opportunities for women in tech. She is also a mental health advocate and fundraiser.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Joanna Bryson</strong><br>Joanna J. Bryson is an academic recognized for her broad expertise on intelligence, its nature, and its consequences. Holding two degrees each in psychology and AI (BA Chicago, MSc & MPhil Edinburgh, PhD MIT), she has been the Professor of Ethics and Technology at the Hertie School of Governance in Berlin since 2020. Bryson advises governments, corporations, and other agencies globally, particularly on AI policy. Her work has appeared in venues ranging from Reddit to the journal Science. From 2002–2019, she was Computer Science faculty at the University of Bath; she has also been affiliated with Harvard Psychology, Oxford Anthropology, the Mannheim Centre for Social Science Research, the Konrad Lorenz Institute for Evolution and Cognition Research, and the Princeton Center for Information Technology Policy. Bryson first observed the confusion generated by anthropomorphized AI during her PhD, leading to her first AI ethics publication, "Just Another Artifact," in 1998. She is now a leader in AI ethics, having since coauthored the first national-level AI ethics policy, the UK’s (2011) Principles of Robotics, and contributed to efforts by the OECD, EU, UN, OSCE, Red Cross, and Google, among others. She also continues to research the systems engineering of AI and the cognitive science of intelligence. Her present research focuses on the impacts of technology on human societies and new models of governance for AI and digital technology. She is a founding member of the Hertie School’s Center for Digital Governance and one of Germany’s nine nominated experts for the Global Partnership for AI.</p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> February 12, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Culture, Tech</p>
<p>As robots and artificial intelligence reached new heights, the relationship between humans and machines is getting closer. The sex tech industry is worth $30 billion annually and growing, as sex with synthetic companions is becoming far more widespread. But should it be? What are the social consequences? Some argue that sex robots will encourage bad behavior, perpetuate misogyny, and reinforce pornographic depictions of the opposite sex. Others say it can serve as a societal good for those who struggle with traditional relationships, and be employed as a safe outlet for otherwise toxic behavior. So in this episode of Agree to Disagree, we debate sex robots and their place in society.</p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/8K75NQm1-8hAezjjd.js' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/8K75NQm1-8hAezjjd.js</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Kate Devlin</strong><br>Kate is a senior lecturer in social and cultural artificial intelligence at King’s College London. Coming from an arts and humanities background (as an archaeologist) with a subsequent PhD in computer science, Kate has a demonstrable track record of combining diverse fields and methods of research. Her work investigates how people interact with and react to technology to understand how emerging and future technologies will affect us and the society in which we live. Her recent research has focused on cognition, sexuality, and intimacy and how these might be incorporated into cognitive systems. This formed the topic of her new book, "Turned On: Science, Sex, and Robots" (Bloomsbury, 2018). Kate is a member of Ada-AI, an international non-profit organization working to ensure that AI is developed and adopted in ways that are inclusive and equitable. Kate is a campaigner for gender equality and is involved in initiatives to improve opportunities for women in tech. She is also a mental health advocate and fundraiser.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Joanna Bryson</strong><br>Joanna J. Bryson is an academic recognized for her broad expertise on intelligence, its nature, and its consequences. Holding two degrees each in psychology and AI (BA Chicago, MSc & MPhil Edinburgh, PhD MIT), she has been the Professor of Ethics and Technology at the Hertie School of Governance in Berlin since 2020. Bryson advises governments, corporations, and other agencies globally, particularly on AI policy. Her work has appeared in venues ranging from Reddit to the journal Science. From 2002–2019, she was Computer Science faculty at the University of Bath; she has also been affiliated with Harvard Psychology, Oxford Anthropology, the Mannheim Centre for Social Science Research, the Konrad Lorenz Institute for Evolution and Cognition Research, and the Princeton Center for Information Technology Policy. Bryson first observed the confusion generated by anthropomorphized AI during her PhD, leading to her first AI ethics publication, "Just Another Artifact," in 1998. She is now a leader in AI ethics, having since coauthored the first national-level AI ethics policy, the UK’s (2011) Principles of Robotics, and contributed to efforts by the OECD, EU, UN, OSCE, Red Cross, and Google, among others. She also continues to research the systems engineering of AI and the cognitive science of intelligence. Her present research focuses on the impacts of technology on human societies and new models of governance for AI and digital technology. She is a founding member of the Hertie School’s Center for Digital Governance and one of Germany’s nine nominated experts for the Global Partnership for AI.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The GOP Has Lost Its Way</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/gop-has-lost-its-way</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10205</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> February 11, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Politics</p>
<p>What should the Republican party look like after Donald Trump? For many prominent establishment figures, including those behind The Lincoln Project, the GOP has lost its way. The only way back, they say, is to purge the forces that brought Trump to power. But others warn that rejecting the millions of voters who supported the former president is the wrong call for the American right. Rather, the GOP should instead double down, focus on bridging the establishment and grassroots factions of their party, and find a way to move forward together. In light of shifting political sands, we ask: Has the GOP lost its way?
<div class="elfsight-app-da6764a0-8ad3-4564-acf4-fa380841a508"></div></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/beGkWT0B-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/beGkWT0B-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Jeff Flake</strong><br>The Honorable Jeff Flake is the former U.S. Senator from Arizona, where he served from 2013 to 2019. Before that, he served six terms in the House of Representatives representing Arizona’s 6th Congressional District. Senator Flake is the author of the 2017 New York Times best-seller “Conscience of a Conservative: A Rejection of Destructive Politics and a Return to Principle,” where he takes a stand for civility in an era of hyper-partisanship. He is currently a contributor to CBS News, a guest lecturer at Princeton, and a guest speaker at Yale.</p>
<p><strong>Carlos Curbelo</strong><br>Former U.S. Congressman Carlos Luis Curbelo served Florida’s 26th congressional district from 2015 to 2019. While there, he served on the Transportation and Infrastructure Committee, the Education and Workforce Committee, the Small Business Committee, and the Committee on Ways and Means, and co-founded the bipartisan House Climate Solutions Caucus. Prior to serving in Congress, Curbelo worked at the Miami-Dade Metropolitan Planning Organization and the Miami Dade County School Board. He further founded a media and public relations firm, which he managed for more than 10 years. Born in Miami, Florida, his parents were political refugees who fled Cuba.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Ben Domenech</strong><br>Benjamin Domenech is the publisher of The Federalist, host of The Federalist Radio Hour, and writer of "The Transom", a daily subscription newsletter for political insiders. Domenech also serves as a fellow at the Manhattan Institute. He was previously a senior fellow at the Heartland Institute, editor-in-chief of The City, an academic journal on faith and culture, and a speechwriter for HHS Secretary Tommy Thompson and U.S. Senator John Cornyn of Texas. He co-founded Redstate and co-hosted "Coffee & Markets", an award-winning economic podcast. His writing has been published in the Daily Beast, Politico, Commentary, Reason, and GQ, and he appears regularly on Fox News, MSNBC, CNN, HBO, and CBS's Face the Nation.</p>
<p><strong>Kimberley A. Strassel</strong><br>Kimberley A. Strassel is an author and member of the editorial board for The Wall Street Journal. She also writes a weekly Potomac Watch political column and is a regular contributor to Sunday political shows, including CBS's "Face the Nation," Fox News Sunday, and NBC's "Meet the Press." She is the author of "The Intimidation Game: How the Left Is Silencing Free Speech," "Leaving Women Behind: Modern Families, Outdated Laws," and "Resistance (At All Costs): How Trump Haters are Breaking America."</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>The GOP Has Lost Its Way</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://open.spotify.com/episode/6EUDZLFAXRviyLn3a2k41V?si=Drrhf2mrQwqA5WJRoXXIsA&nd=1' target='_blank'>Liz Cheney vs. Marjorie Taylor Greene</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2021/02/05/three-factions-house-republicans/' target='_blank'>The three factions of House Republicans</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nationalaffairs.com/publications/detail/the-future-is-faction' target='_blank'>The Future is Faction</a></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.thebulwark.com/a-republican-journey/' target='_blank'>A Republican Journey</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2021/01/republicans-lost-everything/617564/' target='_blank'>Trump Lost Everything for the Republicans</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/11/us/politics/republican-party-trump.html' target='_blank'>Fractured by Trump, the G.O.P. Can't Argree on a Way Back to Power</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nationalreview.com/news/rand-paul-warns-one-third-of-republicans-will-leave-party-if-gop-senators-back-impeachment/?utm_source=recirc-desktop&utm_medium=homepage&utm_campaign=river&utm_content=featured-content-trending&utm_term=first' target='_blank'>Rand Paul Warns One-Third of Republicans Will Leave Party if GOP Senators Back Impeachment</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.wsj.com/livecoverage/trump-impeachment-biden-inauguration/card/90pPMzFPqr5fMzg1Bkbs' target='_blank'>Trump Has Discussed Starting a New Political Party</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/12/us/politics/trump-lawsuits-electoral-college.html' target='_blank'>'An indelible Stain': How the G.O.P. Tried to Topple a Pillar of Democracy</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.usatoday.com/story/opinion/2020/06/26/republican-party-has-lost-its-way-republicans-should-vote-for-joe-biden-2020-column/3254053001/' target='_blank'>2020 Election: If Republicans care about America, they should vote for Joe Biden</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/12/opinion/trump-republicans.html' target='_blank'>If it's Still Trump's Party, Many Republicans Like Me Will Leave</a></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://thefederalist.com/2021/02/03/why-democrats-will-never-stop-talking-about-insurrection/' target='_blank'>Why Democrats Will Never Stop Talking About 'Insurrection'</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2021/01/22/will-hurd-if-gop-wants-future-it-must-make-major-changes/' target='_blank'>Opinion: Will Hurd: If the GOP wants a future, it must look in the mirror</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://thefederalist.com/2021/02/02/adam-kinzinger-shouldnt-be-proud-his-family-disowned-him-he-should-be-ashamed/' target='_blank'>Adam Kinzinger Shouldn't Be Proud His Family Disowned Him. He Should Be Ashamed</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.newsweek.com/trumpism-gop-long-term-1566555' target='_blank'>Trumpism Need Not Define the GOP | Opinion</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://thefederalist.com/2021/02/04/the-qanon-takeover-of-the-gop-is-a-fantasy-of-corporate-media-and-democrats/' target='_blank'>The QAnon Takeover Of The GOP Is A Fantasy Of Corporate Media And Democrats</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/15/opinion/politics/never-trump-republican-party.html' target='_blank'>If the Republican Part Doesn't Shape Up, We Will Challenge It</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nationalreview.com/2021/01/a-final-assessment-of-the-trump-presidency-and-the-path-forward/?utm_source=recirc-desktop&utm_medium=homepage&utm_campaign=river&utm_content=featured-content-trending&utm_term=third' target='_blank'>A Final Assessment of the Trump Presidency, and the Path Forward</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.portclintonnewsherald.com/story/opinion/2020/02/07/america-and-republican-party-just-fine-thank-you-dwight-weidman/4693165002/' target='_blank'>America and the Republican Party are just fine, thank you</a></p>
<p><u>Polls & Public Opinion</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/trump-poll-post-abc/2021/01/14/aeac7b96-5690-11eb-a817-e5e7f8a406d6_story.html' target='_blank'>Post-ABC poll: Overwhelming opposition to Capitol attacks, majority support for preventing Trump from serving again</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/meet-the-press/gop-registration-drop-after-capitol-attack-part-larger-trend-n1256966' target='_blank'>GOP registration drop after Capitol attack is part of larger trend</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.pewresearch.org/politics/2021/01/15/biden-begins-presidency-with-positive-ratings-trump-departs-with-lowest-ever-job-mark/' target='_blank'>Biden Begins Presidency With Positive Ratings: Trump Departs With Lowest-Ever Job Mark</a></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> February 11, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Politics</p>
<p>What should the Republican party look like after Donald Trump? For many prominent establishment figures, including those behind The Lincoln Project, the GOP has lost its way. The only way back, they say, is to purge the forces that brought Trump to power. But others warn that rejecting the millions of voters who supported the former president is the wrong call for the American right. Rather, the GOP should instead double down, focus on bridging the establishment and grassroots factions of their party, and find a way to move forward together. In light of shifting political sands, we ask: Has the GOP lost its way?
<div class="elfsight-app-da6764a0-8ad3-4564-acf4-fa380841a508"></div></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/beGkWT0B-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/beGkWT0B-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Jeff Flake</strong><br>The Honorable Jeff Flake is the former U.S. Senator from Arizona, where he served from 2013 to 2019. Before that, he served six terms in the House of Representatives representing Arizona’s 6th Congressional District. Senator Flake is the author of the 2017 New York Times best-seller “Conscience of a Conservative: A Rejection of Destructive Politics and a Return to Principle,” where he takes a stand for civility in an era of hyper-partisanship. He is currently a contributor to CBS News, a guest lecturer at Princeton, and a guest speaker at Yale.</p>
<p><strong>Carlos Curbelo</strong><br>Former U.S. Congressman Carlos Luis Curbelo served Florida’s 26th congressional district from 2015 to 2019. While there, he served on the Transportation and Infrastructure Committee, the Education and Workforce Committee, the Small Business Committee, and the Committee on Ways and Means, and co-founded the bipartisan House Climate Solutions Caucus. Prior to serving in Congress, Curbelo worked at the Miami-Dade Metropolitan Planning Organization and the Miami Dade County School Board. He further founded a media and public relations firm, which he managed for more than 10 years. Born in Miami, Florida, his parents were political refugees who fled Cuba.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Ben Domenech</strong><br>Benjamin Domenech is the publisher of The Federalist, host of The Federalist Radio Hour, and writer of "The Transom", a daily subscription newsletter for political insiders. Domenech also serves as a fellow at the Manhattan Institute. He was previously a senior fellow at the Heartland Institute, editor-in-chief of The City, an academic journal on faith and culture, and a speechwriter for HHS Secretary Tommy Thompson and U.S. Senator John Cornyn of Texas. He co-founded Redstate and co-hosted "Coffee & Markets", an award-winning economic podcast. His writing has been published in the Daily Beast, Politico, Commentary, Reason, and GQ, and he appears regularly on Fox News, MSNBC, CNN, HBO, and CBS's Face the Nation.</p>
<p><strong>Kimberley A. Strassel</strong><br>Kimberley A. Strassel is an author and member of the editorial board for The Wall Street Journal. She also writes a weekly Potomac Watch political column and is a regular contributor to Sunday political shows, including CBS's "Face the Nation," Fox News Sunday, and NBC's "Meet the Press." She is the author of "The Intimidation Game: How the Left Is Silencing Free Speech," "Leaving Women Behind: Modern Families, Outdated Laws," and "Resistance (At All Costs): How Trump Haters are Breaking America."</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>The GOP Has Lost Its Way</em></p>
<p><u>Background</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://open.spotify.com/episode/6EUDZLFAXRviyLn3a2k41V?si=Drrhf2mrQwqA5WJRoXXIsA&nd=1' target='_blank'>Liz Cheney vs. Marjorie Taylor Greene</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2021/02/05/three-factions-house-republicans/' target='_blank'>The three factions of House Republicans</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nationalaffairs.com/publications/detail/the-future-is-faction' target='_blank'>The Future is Faction</a></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.thebulwark.com/a-republican-journey/' target='_blank'>A Republican Journey</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2021/01/republicans-lost-everything/617564/' target='_blank'>Trump Lost Everything for the Republicans</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/11/us/politics/republican-party-trump.html' target='_blank'>Fractured by Trump, the G.O.P. Can't Argree on a Way Back to Power</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nationalreview.com/news/rand-paul-warns-one-third-of-republicans-will-leave-party-if-gop-senators-back-impeachment/?utm_source=recirc-desktop&utm_medium=homepage&utm_campaign=river&utm_content=featured-content-trending&utm_term=first' target='_blank'>Rand Paul Warns One-Third of Republicans Will Leave Party if GOP Senators Back Impeachment</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.wsj.com/livecoverage/trump-impeachment-biden-inauguration/card/90pPMzFPqr5fMzg1Bkbs' target='_blank'>Trump Has Discussed Starting a New Political Party</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/12/us/politics/trump-lawsuits-electoral-college.html' target='_blank'>'An indelible Stain': How the G.O.P. Tried to Topple a Pillar of Democracy</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.usatoday.com/story/opinion/2020/06/26/republican-party-has-lost-its-way-republicans-should-vote-for-joe-biden-2020-column/3254053001/' target='_blank'>2020 Election: If Republicans care about America, they should vote for Joe Biden</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/12/opinion/trump-republicans.html' target='_blank'>If it's Still Trump's Party, Many Republicans Like Me Will Leave</a></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://thefederalist.com/2021/02/03/why-democrats-will-never-stop-talking-about-insurrection/' target='_blank'>Why Democrats Will Never Stop Talking About 'Insurrection'</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2021/01/22/will-hurd-if-gop-wants-future-it-must-make-major-changes/' target='_blank'>Opinion: Will Hurd: If the GOP wants a future, it must look in the mirror</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://thefederalist.com/2021/02/02/adam-kinzinger-shouldnt-be-proud-his-family-disowned-him-he-should-be-ashamed/' target='_blank'>Adam Kinzinger Shouldn't Be Proud His Family Disowned Him. He Should Be Ashamed</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.newsweek.com/trumpism-gop-long-term-1566555' target='_blank'>Trumpism Need Not Define the GOP | Opinion</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://thefederalist.com/2021/02/04/the-qanon-takeover-of-the-gop-is-a-fantasy-of-corporate-media-and-democrats/' target='_blank'>The QAnon Takeover Of The GOP Is A Fantasy Of Corporate Media And Democrats</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/15/opinion/politics/never-trump-republican-party.html' target='_blank'>If the Republican Part Doesn't Shape Up, We Will Challenge It</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nationalreview.com/2021/01/a-final-assessment-of-the-trump-presidency-and-the-path-forward/?utm_source=recirc-desktop&utm_medium=homepage&utm_campaign=river&utm_content=featured-content-trending&utm_term=third' target='_blank'>A Final Assessment of the Trump Presidency, and the Path Forward</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.portclintonnewsherald.com/story/opinion/2020/02/07/america-and-republican-party-just-fine-thank-you-dwight-weidman/4693165002/' target='_blank'>America and the Republican Party are just fine, thank you</a></p>
<p><u>Polls & Public Opinion</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/trump-poll-post-abc/2021/01/14/aeac7b96-5690-11eb-a817-e5e7f8a406d6_story.html' target='_blank'>Post-ABC poll: Overwhelming opposition to Capitol attacks, majority support for preventing Trump from serving again</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/meet-the-press/gop-registration-drop-after-capitol-attack-part-larger-trend-n1256966' target='_blank'>GOP registration drop after Capitol attack is part of larger trend</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.pewresearch.org/politics/2021/01/15/biden-begins-presidency-with-positive-ratings-trump-departs-with-lowest-ever-job-mark/' target='_blank'>Biden Begins Presidency With Positive Ratings: Trump Departs With Lowest-Ever Job Mark</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>For the Last Four Years, America Got The Middle East Right</title>
            <link>https://opentodebate.org/debate/last-four-years-america-got-middle-east-right</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">otd:debate:10105</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>\n            
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> January 14, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Politics, World</p>
<p>Joe Biden’s approach to the Middle East will likely be very different than Donald Trump’s. But should it be?  For some, the Trump legacy was the right approach: A transactional style that resulted in a host of political and diplomatic victories, including normalizing relations between Israel and several Arab states. It was also selectively aggressively when it came to the death of the leader of the Islamic State or sanctions against Iran that, some say, blunted Tehran’s ambitions and reduced its power in the region. But others, including many prominent members of Biden's transition team, see the last four years as a failure of strategy and leadership. They argue that Trump's personalized approach to the Middle East eroded America's moral agency and gave cover to authoritarian leaders. To them, Trump’s stance on Iran emboldened hardliners, while its staunch support for Israeli interests isolated American allies and undermined the Palestinians. So, as the Biden team gets going, we debate whether Trump got the Middle East right.
<div class="elfsight-app-435ed765-cf99-444e-9fa1-764101b6fd72"></div></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/QzVPp92j-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/QzVPp92j-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Mary Beth Long</strong><br>Mary Beth Long is an attorney, political advisor, and former government official. She was the first woman to be confirmed by the Senate as Assistant Secretary of Defense for International Security Affairs and spent more than a decade as a CIA officer. She has also served as a senior advisor to the Supreme Allied Commander of NATO and chaired NATO's High-Level Group responsible for nuclear policy. Long is the founder of M. B. Long & Associates.</p>
<p><strong>Danny Danon</strong><br>Danon was Israel’s 17th Permanent Representative to the United Nations and is the nation’s former Deputy Minister of Defense. He is currently Chairman of the World Likud, a global organization dedicated to combating anti-Semitism and conducting pro-Israel advocacy activities.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Justine A. Rosenthal</strong><br>Rosenthal served as Director of the Council on Global Terrorism and is a former Director at the Council on Foreign Relations, a Brookings Research Fellow, and a Special Assistant to former Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin. Her areas of expertise include international terrorism, counter-terrorism strategies, nuclear proliferation, civil warfare, and East Asian security. She recently produced several international current-affairs documentaries for National Geographic and the Emmy-nominated HBO film "Only the Dead See the End of War."</p>
<p><strong>Michael Ware</strong><br>Ware is a journalist and documentary filmmaker. He served as Time's Baghdad bureau chief before moving to CNN. There, Ware was a foreign correspondent, reporting from across the region. He was one of the few Western journalists to live full-time in Iraq during the war, having embedded with U.S. forces, insurgents, and terrorists. He is the writer and director of the Emmy-nominated HBO documentary "Only the Dead See the End of War."</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Trump Got the Middle East Right</em></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://foreignpolicy.com/2020/11/16/trump-biden-iran-israel-uae-middle-east/' target='_blank'>Trump's parting gift to Biden: A More Stable Middle East</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2019/09/how-trump-remaking-republican-foreign-policy/159989/' target='_blank'>How Trump is Remaking Republican Foreign Policy</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nytimes.com/2020/09/16/opinion/trump-israel-bahrain-uae.html' target='_blank'>Trump's Middle East Deal Is Good. But Not That Good</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.jpost.com/opinion/trumps-middle-east-legacy-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly-opinion-650738' target='_blank'>Trump's Middle East policies will be recognized as major positives of his administration</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.cato.org/policy-analysis/step-back-lessons-us-foreign-policy-failed-war-terror' target='_blank'>Step Baack: Lessons for U.S. Foreign Policy from the Failed War on Terror</a></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://foreignpolicy.com/2020/10/28/trumps-middle-east-legacy-is-failure/' target='_blank'>Trump's Middle East Legacy Is Failure</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.cnn.com/2020/10/29/middleeast/trump-middle-east-ben-wedeman-intl/index.html' target='_blank'>Trump tried to reinvent Middle East policy, but the region is still a bottomless pit of woes</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.brookings.edu/blog/order-from-chaos/2020/01/06/trumps-reckless-middle-east-policy-has-brought-the-us-to-the-brink-of-war/' target='_blank'>Trump's reckless Middle East policy has brought the US to the brink of war</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/global-opinions/trump-middle-east-legacy/2020/11/22/4563bec2-2a7d-11eb-8fa2-06e7cbb145c0_story.html' target='_blank'>Trump's overarching Middle East strategy reaches a disastrous dead end</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.ft.com/content/9c4b656d-c1dd-4a42-a03b-87174dfe2792' target='_blank'>Biden is likely to rethink much of Trump's Middle East policy</a></p>
<p><u>Istaeli Peace Deals</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.whitehouse.gov/peacetoprosperity/' target='_blank'>Peace to Prosperity</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://interactive.aljazeera.com/aje/2020/the-failed-deals-of-the-century/index.html' target='_blank'>THE FAILED DEALS OF THE CENTURY</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2020/01/28/trump-administrations-new-mideast-peace-plan-is-absurd/' target='_blank'>The Trump administration's new Mideast 'peace' plan is absurd</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://carnegieendowment.org/2020/02/27/i-m-veteran-middle-east-peace-negotiator.-trump-s-plan-is-most-dangerous-i-ve-ever-seen-pub-81171' target='_blank'>I'm a Veteran Middle East Peace Negotiator, Trump's Plan Is the Most Dangerous I've Ever Seen</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nytimes.com/2020/05/30/opinion/sunday/west-bank-israel-annex.html?action=click&module=RelatedLinks&pgtype=Article' target='_blank'>Annexing the West Bank is a Brazen Violation of International Law</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.brookings.edu/blog/order-from-chaos/2020/02/04/trumps-middle-east-plan-what-does-america-stand-for/' target='_blank'>Trump's Middle East plan: What does America stand for?</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/trump-middle-east-accords/2020/10/31/f0585dec-19fc-11eb-aeec-b93bcc29a01b_story.html' target='_blank'>Trump critics hall accords between Israel and Arab countries even as original goal of Palestinian peace remains unmet</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2020/08/14/trump-mideast-israel-uae-deal-395567' target='_blank'>Trump's Win is a Loss for the Middle East</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.politico.com/news/2020/01/28/trump-israel-palestinian-middle-east-peace-plan-108078' target='_blank'>How Trump's Mideast peace plan could actually matter</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2020/01/28/trump-peace-plan-is-squeeze-play-against-palestinians-it-might-work/' target='_blank'>The Trump peace plan is a squeeze play against the Palestinians. It might work</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-10-15/donald-trump-s-middle-east-friends-brace-for-joe-biden?sref=153yhh1c' target='_blank'>Trump's Middle East Friends Brace for Biden</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/president-donald-j-trump-brokers-historic-peace-agreement-israel-sudan/' target='_blank'>President Donald J. Trump Brokers a Historic Peace Agreement Between Israel and Sudan</a></p>
<p><u>Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://slate.com/news-and-politics/2020/12/biden-iran-nuclear-deal.html' target='_blank'>The Iran Deal Lives</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.bbc.com/news/world-middle-east-55530366' target='_blank'>Iran resumes enriching uranium to 20% purity at Fordo facility</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/biden-faces-a-minefield-in-new-diplomacy-with-iran' target='_blank'>Biden Faces a Minefield in New Diplomacy with Iran</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2020/12/trump-could-still-start-last-ditch-war-iran/617530/' target='_blank'>Trump Could Still Start a Last-Ditch War With Iran</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://foreignpolicy.com/2020/12/18/biden-iran-nuclear-deal-jcpoa-sanctions-weapons-trump/' target='_blank'>Biden Shouldn't Rush to Restore the Iran Nuclear Deal</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.vox.com/world/2018/5/8/17326650/iran-nuclear-deal-withdraw-trump-speech-goldberg-interview' target='_blank'>Why Trump is right to pull out of the Iran nuclear deal</a></p>
<p><u>Qatar</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.reuters.com/world/breakthrough-reached-gulf-dispute-with-qatar-senior-trump-official-2021-01-04/' target='_blank'>Breakthrough reached in Gulf dispute with Qatar - senior Trump official</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/05/world/middleeast/gulf-qatar-blockade.html?action=click&block=more_in_recirc&impression_id=c29ab9a1-4f75-11eb-8f2c-e96a7cedd9c7&index=1&pgtype=Article&region=footer' target='_blank'>Gulf States Agree to Ease Isolation of Qatar</a></p>
<p><u>Saudi Arabia & Yemen</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.heritage.org/middle-east/commentary/trumps-veto-yemen-war-resolution-protects-us-security-interests' target='_blank'>Trump's Veto of Yemen War Resolution Protects U.S. Security Interests</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2020/2/7/yemen-al-qaeda-leader-al-rimi-killed-in-us-operation-says-trump' target='_blank'>Yemen al-Qaeda leader al-Rimi in US operation, says Trump</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.businessinsider.com/trump-have-bombed-yemen-more-than-bush-and-obama-combined-2020-10' target='_blank'>Trump may have bombed Yemen more than all previous US presidents combined, new report finds</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://theintercept.com/2020/10/29/trump-yemen-war-civilian-deaths/' target='_blank'>Trump, The War President, Leaves a Trail of Civilians Dead in Yemen</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://foreignpolicy.com/2020/09/16/congress-pressures-trump-aid-yemen-pompeo/' target='_blank'>Congress Pressures Trump Administration to Restore Aid to Yemen</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nbcnews.com/news/world/less-privileged-personal-how-u-s-saudi-ties-may-soon-n1247439' target='_blank'>U.S. Saudi ties were espcially close under Trump. Under Biden, that looks likely to change</a></p>
<p><u>Syria</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://warontherocks.com/2019/10/u-s-officials-ignored-trump-on-syria-and-we-are-all-paying-the-price/' target='_blank'>U.S. Officials Ignored Trump On Syria And We Are All Paying The Price</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://foreignpolicy.com/2020/07/01/trumps-syria-policy-is-working-assad-stalemate-pompeo/' target='_blank'>Trump's Syria Policy Is Working</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2019/10/18/trump-syria-turkey-kurds-news-analysis-229858/' target='_blank'>What Trump Actually Gets Right About Syria</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2019/10/08/trump-is-wrong-pull-troops-syria-hes-right-that-united-states-is-overextended/' target='_blank'>Trump is wrong to pull troops from Syria. He's right that the United States is overextended</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://warontherocks.com/2021/01/redefining-victory-in-americas-war-against-the-islamic-state-in-syria/' target='_blank'>Redefining Victory in America's War Against The Islamic State in Syria</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.vox.com/2020/9/21/21448845/syria-russia-usa-troops-trump' target='_blank'>Trump says the US is out of Syria, But more US troops are heading there.</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.desmoinesregister.com/story/news/elections/presidential/caucus/2019/10/16/joe-biden-donald-trump-syria-troop-withdrawal-turkey-kurds-foreign-policy-iowa-caucuses-2020/4002281002/' target='_blank'>'Trump sold them out': Joe Biden hits the president over Syria troop withrawl in Iowa speech</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://progressive.org/latest/trump-prolonging-civil-war-syria-hunt-201216/' target='_blank'>Trump Is Prolonging the Civil War in Syria</a></p>]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Debate Date:</strong> January 14, 2021</p>
<p><strong>Topics:</strong> Politics, World</p>
<p>Joe Biden’s approach to the Middle East will likely be very different than Donald Trump’s. But should it be?  For some, the Trump legacy was the right approach: A transactional style that resulted in a host of political and diplomatic victories, including normalizing relations between Israel and several Arab states. It was also selectively aggressively when it came to the death of the leader of the Islamic State or sanctions against Iran that, some say, blunted Tehran’s ambitions and reduced its power in the region. But others, including many prominent members of Biden's transition team, see the last four years as a failure of strategy and leadership. They argue that Trump's personalized approach to the Middle East eroded America's moral agency and gave cover to authoritarian leaders. To them, Trump’s stance on Iran emboldened hardliners, while its staunch support for Israeli interests isolated American allies and undermined the Palestinians. So, as the Biden team gets going, we debate whether Trump got the Middle East right.
<div class="elfsight-app-435ed765-cf99-444e-9fa1-764101b6fd72"></div></p>
<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href='https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/QzVPp92j-8hAezjjd.html' target='_blank'>https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/QzVPp92j-8hAezjjd.html</a></p>
<p><strong>Moderators:</strong></p>
<p><strong>John Donvan</strong><br>John Donvan is the host of Open to Debate and has been moderating our debates since 2008. An author, speaker, and journalist, John has reported for ABC, CNN, and PBS, including multi-year postings in Moscow, London, Jerusalem, and Amman, and a term as chief White House correspondent for ABC News. His 2016 book, "In a Different Key: The Story of Autism", was a New York Times bestseller and a Wall Street Journal Top Ten Nonfiction Book of the Year. John is a four-time Emmy Award winner and was a National Magazine Award finalist in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers For:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Mary Beth Long</strong><br>Mary Beth Long is an attorney, political advisor, and former government official. She was the first woman to be confirmed by the Senate as Assistant Secretary of Defense for International Security Affairs and spent more than a decade as a CIA officer. She has also served as a senior advisor to the Supreme Allied Commander of NATO and chaired NATO's High-Level Group responsible for nuclear policy. Long is the founder of M. B. Long & Associates.</p>
<p><strong>Danny Danon</strong><br>Danon was Israel’s 17th Permanent Representative to the United Nations and is the nation’s former Deputy Minister of Defense. He is currently Chairman of the World Likud, a global organization dedicated to combating anti-Semitism and conducting pro-Israel advocacy activities.</p>
<p><strong>Speakers Against:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Justine A. Rosenthal</strong><br>Rosenthal served as Director of the Council on Global Terrorism and is a former Director at the Council on Foreign Relations, a Brookings Research Fellow, and a Special Assistant to former Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin. Her areas of expertise include international terrorism, counter-terrorism strategies, nuclear proliferation, civil warfare, and East Asian security. She recently produced several international current-affairs documentaries for National Geographic and the Emmy-nominated HBO film "Only the Dead See the End of War."</p>
<p><strong>Michael Ware</strong><br>Ware is a journalist and documentary filmmaker. He served as Time's Baghdad bureau chief before moving to CNN. There, Ware was a foreign correspondent, reporting from across the region. He was one of the few Western journalists to live full-time in Iraq during the war, having embedded with U.S. forces, insurgents, and terrorists. He is the writer and director of the Emmy-nominated HBO documentary "Only the Dead See the End of War."</p>
<p><strong>Research Briefs:</strong></p>
<p><em>Trump Got the Middle East Right</em></p>
<p><u>Arguments For</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://foreignpolicy.com/2020/11/16/trump-biden-iran-israel-uae-middle-east/' target='_blank'>Trump's parting gift to Biden: A More Stable Middle East</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2019/09/how-trump-remaking-republican-foreign-policy/159989/' target='_blank'>How Trump is Remaking Republican Foreign Policy</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nytimes.com/2020/09/16/opinion/trump-israel-bahrain-uae.html' target='_blank'>Trump's Middle East Deal Is Good. But Not That Good</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.jpost.com/opinion/trumps-middle-east-legacy-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly-opinion-650738' target='_blank'>Trump's Middle East policies will be recognized as major positives of his administration</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.cato.org/policy-analysis/step-back-lessons-us-foreign-policy-failed-war-terror' target='_blank'>Step Baack: Lessons for U.S. Foreign Policy from the Failed War on Terror</a></p>
<p><u>Arguments Against</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://foreignpolicy.com/2020/10/28/trumps-middle-east-legacy-is-failure/' target='_blank'>Trump's Middle East Legacy Is Failure</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.cnn.com/2020/10/29/middleeast/trump-middle-east-ben-wedeman-intl/index.html' target='_blank'>Trump tried to reinvent Middle East policy, but the region is still a bottomless pit of woes</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.brookings.edu/blog/order-from-chaos/2020/01/06/trumps-reckless-middle-east-policy-has-brought-the-us-to-the-brink-of-war/' target='_blank'>Trump's reckless Middle East policy has brought the US to the brink of war</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/global-opinions/trump-middle-east-legacy/2020/11/22/4563bec2-2a7d-11eb-8fa2-06e7cbb145c0_story.html' target='_blank'>Trump's overarching Middle East strategy reaches a disastrous dead end</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.ft.com/content/9c4b656d-c1dd-4a42-a03b-87174dfe2792' target='_blank'>Biden is likely to rethink much of Trump's Middle East policy</a></p>
<p><u>Istaeli Peace Deals</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.whitehouse.gov/peacetoprosperity/' target='_blank'>Peace to Prosperity</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://interactive.aljazeera.com/aje/2020/the-failed-deals-of-the-century/index.html' target='_blank'>THE FAILED DEALS OF THE CENTURY</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2020/01/28/trump-administrations-new-mideast-peace-plan-is-absurd/' target='_blank'>The Trump administration's new Mideast 'peace' plan is absurd</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://carnegieendowment.org/2020/02/27/i-m-veteran-middle-east-peace-negotiator.-trump-s-plan-is-most-dangerous-i-ve-ever-seen-pub-81171' target='_blank'>I'm a Veteran Middle East Peace Negotiator, Trump's Plan Is the Most Dangerous I've Ever Seen</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nytimes.com/2020/05/30/opinion/sunday/west-bank-israel-annex.html?action=click&module=RelatedLinks&pgtype=Article' target='_blank'>Annexing the West Bank is a Brazen Violation of International Law</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.brookings.edu/blog/order-from-chaos/2020/02/04/trumps-middle-east-plan-what-does-america-stand-for/' target='_blank'>Trump's Middle East plan: What does America stand for?</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/trump-middle-east-accords/2020/10/31/f0585dec-19fc-11eb-aeec-b93bcc29a01b_story.html' target='_blank'>Trump critics hall accords between Israel and Arab countries even as original goal of Palestinian peace remains unmet</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2020/08/14/trump-mideast-israel-uae-deal-395567' target='_blank'>Trump's Win is a Loss for the Middle East</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.politico.com/news/2020/01/28/trump-israel-palestinian-middle-east-peace-plan-108078' target='_blank'>How Trump's Mideast peace plan could actually matter</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2020/01/28/trump-peace-plan-is-squeeze-play-against-palestinians-it-might-work/' target='_blank'>The Trump peace plan is a squeeze play against the Palestinians. It might work</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-10-15/donald-trump-s-middle-east-friends-brace-for-joe-biden?sref=153yhh1c' target='_blank'>Trump's Middle East Friends Brace for Biden</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/president-donald-j-trump-brokers-historic-peace-agreement-israel-sudan/' target='_blank'>President Donald J. Trump Brokers a Historic Peace Agreement Between Israel and Sudan</a></p>
<p><u>Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://slate.com/news-and-politics/2020/12/biden-iran-nuclear-deal.html' target='_blank'>The Iran Deal Lives</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.bbc.com/news/world-middle-east-55530366' target='_blank'>Iran resumes enriching uranium to 20% purity at Fordo facility</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/biden-faces-a-minefield-in-new-diplomacy-with-iran' target='_blank'>Biden Faces a Minefield in New Diplomacy with Iran</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2020/12/trump-could-still-start-last-ditch-war-iran/617530/' target='_blank'>Trump Could Still Start a Last-Ditch War With Iran</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://foreignpolicy.com/2020/12/18/biden-iran-nuclear-deal-jcpoa-sanctions-weapons-trump/' target='_blank'>Biden Shouldn't Rush to Restore the Iran Nuclear Deal</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.vox.com/world/2018/5/8/17326650/iran-nuclear-deal-withdraw-trump-speech-goldberg-interview' target='_blank'>Why Trump is right to pull out of the Iran nuclear deal</a></p>
<p><u>Qatar</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.reuters.com/world/breakthrough-reached-gulf-dispute-with-qatar-senior-trump-official-2021-01-04/' target='_blank'>Breakthrough reached in Gulf dispute with Qatar - senior Trump official</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/05/world/middleeast/gulf-qatar-blockade.html?action=click&block=more_in_recirc&impression_id=c29ab9a1-4f75-11eb-8f2c-e96a7cedd9c7&index=1&pgtype=Article&region=footer' target='_blank'>Gulf States Agree to Ease Isolation of Qatar</a></p>
<p><u>Saudi Arabia & Yemen</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.heritage.org/middle-east/commentary/trumps-veto-yemen-war-resolution-protects-us-security-interests' target='_blank'>Trump's Veto of Yemen War Resolution Protects U.S. Security Interests</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2020/2/7/yemen-al-qaeda-leader-al-rimi-killed-in-us-operation-says-trump' target='_blank'>Yemen al-Qaeda leader al-Rimi in US operation, says Trump</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.businessinsider.com/trump-have-bombed-yemen-more-than-bush-and-obama-combined-2020-10' target='_blank'>Trump may have bombed Yemen more than all previous US presidents combined, new report finds</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://theintercept.com/2020/10/29/trump-yemen-war-civilian-deaths/' target='_blank'>Trump, The War President, Leaves a Trail of Civilians Dead in Yemen</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://foreignpolicy.com/2020/09/16/congress-pressures-trump-aid-yemen-pompeo/' target='_blank'>Congress Pressures Trump Administration to Restore Aid to Yemen</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.nbcnews.com/news/world/less-privileged-personal-how-u-s-saudi-ties-may-soon-n1247439' target='_blank'>U.S. Saudi ties were espcially close under Trump. Under Biden, that looks likely to change</a></p>
<p><u>Syria</u></p>
<p>• <a href='https://warontherocks.com/2019/10/u-s-officials-ignored-trump-on-syria-and-we-are-all-paying-the-price/' target='_blank'>U.S. Officials Ignored Trump On Syria And We Are All Paying The Price</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://foreignpolicy.com/2020/07/01/trumps-syria-policy-is-working-assad-stalemate-pompeo/' target='_blank'>Trump's Syria Policy Is Working</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2019/10/18/trump-syria-turkey-kurds-news-analysis-229858/' target='_blank'>What Trump Actually Gets Right About Syria</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2019/10/08/trump-is-wrong-pull-troops-syria-hes-right-that-united-states-is-overextended/' target='_blank'>Trump is wrong to pull troops from Syria. He's right that the United States is overextended</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://warontherocks.com/2021/01/redefining-victory-in-americas-war-against-the-islamic-state-in-syria/' target='_blank'>Redefining Victory in America's War Against The Islamic State in Syria</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.vox.com/2020/9/21/21448845/syria-russia-usa-troops-trump' target='_blank'>Trump says the US is out of Syria, But more US troops are heading there.</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://www.desmoinesregister.com/story/news/elections/presidential/caucus/2019/10/16/joe-biden-donald-trump-syria-troop-withdrawal-turkey-kurds-foreign-policy-iowa-caucuses-2020/4002281002/' target='_blank'>'Trump sold them out': Joe Biden hits the president over Syria troop withrawl in Iowa speech</a></p>
<p>• <a href='https://progressive.org/latest/trump-prolonging-civil-war-syria-hunt-201216/' target='_blank'>Trump Is Prolonging the Civil War in Syria</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
    
</rss>
